<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Asic-Design on CHIPS Alliance</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/208/tags/asic-design/</link><description>Recent content in Asic-Design on CHIPS Alliance</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 26 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://chipsalliance.org/preview/208/tags/asic-design/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Recap of the Fall 2021 CHIPS Alliance Workshop</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/208/news/recap-of-the-fall-2021-chips-alliance-workshop-rob-mains-chips-alliance/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/208/news/recap-of-the-fall-2021-chips-alliance-workshop-rob-mains-chips-alliance/</guid><description>&lt;p>We recently held our fall 2021 CHIPS Alliance workshop with nearly 160 attendees present for informative seminars covering a range of topics including porting Android to RISC-V, open source ASIC design and FPGA tooling, and OmniXtend. In case you missed the talks, a replay is available &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=auXZdPwYs10">on the CHIPS Alliance YouTube channel&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>During the seminar, we had eight exciting technical presentations, including:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="porting-android-chips_alliance-slides-v1.2-Han-Mao.pdf">Porting Android to RISC-V&lt;/a> – Guoyin Chen and Han Mao, Alibaba&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="Practical-Adoption-of-Open-Source-System-Verilog-Tools-CHIPS-Fall-Workshop-Michael-Gielda.pdf">Practical Adoption of Open Source SystemVerilog Tools&lt;/a> – Michael Gielda, Antmicro&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="ChiselTalk_ChipsAlliance_2021_October-Jack-Koenig.pdf">Chisel and FIRRTL for Next-Generation SoC Designs&lt;/a> – Jack Koenig, SiFive&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="OpenFASOC_-Open-Source-Fully-Autonomous-SoC-Synthesis-using-Customizable-Cell-Based-Synthesizable-Analog-Circuits-CHIPS-Alliance-Mehdi-Saligane.pdf">OpenFASOC: Automated Open Source Analog and Mixed-Signals IC Generation&lt;/a> – Mehdi Saligane, University of Michigan (UMICH)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="FPGA-Tooling-Interoperability-with-the-FPGA-Interchange-Format-Maciej-Kurc.pdf">FPGA Tooling Interoperability with the FPGA Interchange Format&lt;/a> – Maciej Kurc, Antmicro&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="OXLPC_ChipsAlliance-Jaco-Hofmann.pdf">OmniXtend: Scalability and LPC&lt;/a> – Jaco Hofmann, Western Digital Corporation&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="Open-Source-NVME-IP-with-AI-Acceleration-Karol-Gugala.pdf">Open Source NVME IP with AI Acceleration&lt;/a> – Anand Kulkarni, Western Digital Corporation and Karol Gugala, Antmicro&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="2021-10-CHIPS_Alliance-Sachin-Sapatnekar.pdf">Automating Analog Layout using ALIGN&lt;/a> – Sachin Sapatnekar, University of Minnesota (UMN)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Each of these talks provided informative, technical details of key aspects of the work underway by members of CHIPS Alliance who are working in an open, collaborative fashion. Of particular interest are the following topic areas:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Intel joins CHIPS Alliance to promote Advanced Interface Bus (AIB) as an open standard</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/208/news/intel-joins-chips-alliance-to-promote-advanced-interface-bus-aib-as-an-open-standard/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/208/news/intel-joins-chips-alliance-to-promote-advanced-interface-bus-aib-as-an-open-standard/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>Open development for SOCs gets major boost with new collaboration&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>SAN FRANCISCO, Jan. 22, 2020 /PRNewswire/&lt;/strong> — CHIPS Alliance, the leading consortium advancing common and open hardware for interfaces, processors and systems, today announced industry leading chipmaker Intel as it’s newest member. Intel is contributing the Advanced Interface Bus (AIB) to CHIPS Alliance to foster broad adoption.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>CHIPS Alliance is hosted by the Linux Foundation to foster a collaborative environment to accelerate the creation and deployment of open SoCs, peripherals and software tools for use in mobile, computing, consumer electronics and Internet of Things (IoT) applications. The CHIPS Alliance project develops high-quality open source Register Transfer Level (RTL) code and software development tools relevant to the design of open source CPUs, SoCs, and complex peripherals for Field Programmable Gate Arrays (FPGAs) and custom silicon.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>