<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Veer on CHIPS Alliance</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/tags/veer/</link><description>Recent content in Veer on CHIPS Alliance</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://chipsalliance.org/tags/veer/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>CHIPS Alliance 2025- A Year of Breakthroughs in Open Silicon and the Road Ahead</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/news/2025-recap/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/news/2025-recap/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>Author: Rob Mains, Executive Director of CHIPS Alliance&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>CHIPS Alliance is a six-year-old organization that is part of the Linux Foundation, whose mission is to foster collaborative, open source development in the silicon hardware design ecosystem. CHIPS champions all aspects of hardware development including:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Chip design architecture&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Electronic design automation for design entry, design verification, and physical implementation&lt;/li>
&lt;li>FPGA tools&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Repository of chip designs and verification design benches&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Firmware&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Artificial intelligence and chip design&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Generating interactive coverage dashboards for VeeR and Caliptra with Coverview</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/news/coverage-dashboards-for-veer-and-caliptra/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/news/coverage-dashboards-for-veer-and-caliptra/</guid><description>&lt;p>Code coverage is a useful metric to keep track of while developing test suites, providing engineering teams with an actionable overview of how broad their testing goes. This is true both for executable code and digital design, but the different nature of RTL and software execution requires developers to look at different types of coverage information. On top of tracking executed code lines and visited branches, RTL coverage will also need to include information e.g. about specific bit field toggles of all the signals in the design. The thorough testing of a sufficient number of combinations of those signals can be the “make or break” for an RTL design.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Open source and CI-driven RTL testing and verification for Caliptra’s RISC-V VeeR core</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/news/open-source-rtl-ci-testing-and-verification-for-caliptra-veer/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/news/open-source-rtl-ci-testing-and-verification-for-caliptra-veer/</guid><description>&lt;p>As part of &lt;a href="https://www.chipsalliance.org/">CHIPS Alliance’s&lt;/a> mission to enable a software-driven approach to silicon, working with Google and other CHIPS members, Antmicro has been developing and improving a growing number of open source tools to enable effective, CI-driven silicon development.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Fully reproducible and scalable workflows based on open source tooling are especially beneficial for efforts spanning across multiple industrial and academic actors such as Caliptra, a Root of Trust project driven by Google, AMD, NVIDIA and Microsoft which &lt;a href="https://chipsalliance.org/announcement/2022/12/13/chips-alliance-welcomes-the-caliptra-open-source-root-of-trust-project/">recently joined CHIPS&lt;/a> in order to host the ongoing development and provide the necessary structure, working environment and support for the reference implementation of the standard, originally hosted by &lt;a href="https://www.opencompute.org/documents/caliptra-silicon-rot-services-09012022-pdf">Open Compute Project&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>