<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Event-Recap on CHIPS Alliance</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/200/tags/event-recap/</link><description>Recent content in Event-Recap on CHIPS Alliance</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://chipsalliance.org/preview/200/tags/event-recap/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>CHIPS Alliance Fall 2022 Technology Update December 15</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/200/news/chips-alliance-fall-2022-technology-update-december-15/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/200/news/chips-alliance-fall-2022-technology-update-december-15/</guid><description>&lt;p>Please join us on December 15 at 8:30 am PT either in person at Google or virtually for a CHIPS technology update featuring many exciting speakers. Details and registration are here: &lt;a href="https://events.linuxfoundation.org/chips-biannual-technology-update/">https://events.linuxfoundation.org/chips-biannual-technology-update/&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Catch us at DAC 59 in San Francisco starting July 11</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/200/news/catch-us-at-dac-59-in-san-francisco-starting-july-11/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/200/news/catch-us-at-dac-59-in-san-francisco-starting-july-11/</guid><description>&lt;p>Come learn about open source hardware and CHIPS Alliance at next week’s 59th Design Automation Conference in San Francisco. We will be at kiosk 2344 in the RISC-V pavilion. You can also here out talk at 12:30 Monday in the Open Source Central Theatre (booth 2338). We are also in a DAC Pavilion Panel: Is Democratization of Chip Design Already Happening? at 2:30 on Monday. Look forward to an exciting day in SF!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How Google is Applying Machine Learning to Macro Placement</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/200/news/how-google-is-applying-machine-learning-to-macro-placement/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/200/news/how-google-is-applying-machine-learning-to-macro-placement/</guid><description>&lt;p>CHIPS Alliance’s latest Deep Dive Cafe featured an outstanding talk by a Google physical design engineer, Young-Joon Lee, who has a PhD from Georgia Tech, and has been working on machine learning physical design projects for the past two years.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The chip placement problem is a notoriously challenging design problem, and has been explored in the electronic design automation research and development community for years. For those unfamiliar with the problem, it involves finding the optimal placement of physical cells implementing the logical function on a chip image to minimize performance, power, and area of the silicon, which in the end affects the cost of the product. The effort by Google to apply machine learning to the placement problem started as part of the Google Brain effort, which in part focuses on running algorithms at scale on large amounts of data.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Recap of the Fall 2021 CHIPS Alliance Workshop</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/200/news/recap-of-the-fall-2021-chips-alliance-workshop-rob-mains-chips-alliance/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/200/news/recap-of-the-fall-2021-chips-alliance-workshop-rob-mains-chips-alliance/</guid><description>&lt;p>We recently held our fall 2021 CHIPS Alliance workshop with nearly 160 attendees present for informative seminars covering a range of topics including porting Android to RISC-V, open source ASIC design and FPGA tooling, and OmniXtend. In case you missed the talks, a replay is available &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=auXZdPwYs10">on the CHIPS Alliance YouTube channel&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>During the seminar, we had eight exciting technical presentations, including:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="porting-android-chips_alliance-slides-v1.2-Han-Mao.pdf">Porting Android to RISC-V&lt;/a> – Guoyin Chen and Han Mao, Alibaba&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="Practical-Adoption-of-Open-Source-System-Verilog-Tools-CHIPS-Fall-Workshop-Michael-Gielda.pdf">Practical Adoption of Open Source SystemVerilog Tools&lt;/a> – Michael Gielda, Antmicro&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="ChiselTalk_ChipsAlliance_2021_October-Jack-Koenig.pdf">Chisel and FIRRTL for Next-Generation SoC Designs&lt;/a> – Jack Koenig, SiFive&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="OpenFASOC_-Open-Source-Fully-Autonomous-SoC-Synthesis-using-Customizable-Cell-Based-Synthesizable-Analog-Circuits-CHIPS-Alliance-Mehdi-Saligane.pdf">OpenFASOC: Automated Open Source Analog and Mixed-Signals IC Generation&lt;/a> – Mehdi Saligane, University of Michigan (UMICH)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="FPGA-Tooling-Interoperability-with-the-FPGA-Interchange-Format-Maciej-Kurc.pdf">FPGA Tooling Interoperability with the FPGA Interchange Format&lt;/a> – Maciej Kurc, Antmicro&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="OXLPC_ChipsAlliance-Jaco-Hofmann.pdf">OmniXtend: Scalability and LPC&lt;/a> – Jaco Hofmann, Western Digital Corporation&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="Open-Source-NVME-IP-with-AI-Acceleration-Karol-Gugala.pdf">Open Source NVME IP with AI Acceleration&lt;/a> – Anand Kulkarni, Western Digital Corporation and Karol Gugala, Antmicro&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="2021-10-CHIPS_Alliance-Sachin-Sapatnekar.pdf">Automating Analog Layout using ALIGN&lt;/a> – Sachin Sapatnekar, University of Minnesota (UMN)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Each of these talks provided informative, technical details of key aspects of the work underway by members of CHIPS Alliance who are working in an open, collaborative fashion. Of particular interest are the following topic areas:&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>