<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Verible on CHIPS Alliance</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/202/tags/verible/</link><description>Recent content in Verible on CHIPS Alliance</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://chipsalliance.org/preview/202/tags/verible/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Structuring Open Silicon - A TAC Perspective with Aaron Cunningham</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/202/news/structuring-open-silicon/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/202/news/structuring-open-silicon/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="how-a-globally-distributed-program-manager-is-helping-define-the-next-phase-of-open-source-silicon-collaboration">How a globally distributed program manager is helping define the next phase of open source silicon collaboration.&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Introduction&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Aaron Cunningham serves as Chair of the CHIPS Alliance Technical Advisory Council (TAC) and is a Technical Program Manager at Google focused on tooling, architecture, and hardware optimization. From managing infrastructure in Singapore to advocating for cross-project clarity at the Linux Foundation, Aaron brings a uniquely strategic lens to the complexities of scaling open source silicon.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Integrating the Language Server Protocol in Verible</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/202/news/integrating-language-server-protocol-in-verible/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/202/news/integrating-language-server-protocol-in-verible/</guid><description>&lt;p>A more collaborative, open and software driven ASIC design methodology pioneered by the &lt;a href="https://chipsalliance.org">CHIPS Alliance&lt;/a> requires an open source tooling stack to enable sharing of workflows, artifacts and fostering a free exchange of insights and improvements.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>While internally often using new design methodologies and languages such as Migen, Chisel or XLS, Antmicro is conscious of the fact that a lot of the world’s ASIC development involves SystemVerilog and UVM, and so we are working on bridging traditional and new ASIC development methodologies as described in a &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/blog/2023/01/open-source-systemverilog-uvm-support-in-verilator/">recent blog note&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Automatic SystemVerilog Linting in GitHub Actions with Verible</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/202/news/automatic-systemverilog-linting-in-github-actions-with-verible/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/202/news/automatic-systemverilog-linting-in-github-actions-with-verible/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>This post was originally published at &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/blog/2021/08/verible-integration-with-github-actions/">Antmicro&lt;/a>.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>With the recent advances in open source &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/blog/2021/07/open-source-systemverilog-tools-in-asic-design/">ASIC development tools&lt;/a> such as Verible, it has become easier to automate tasks and boost developer productivity. The Verible linter is a static code analysis tool that has been helping us and our collaborators to spot and fix stylistic errors and bugs in SystemVerilog code.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="cicd-for-smaller-backlog-and-better-test-reliability">CI/CD for smaller backlog and better test reliability&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>As part of our work within the newly established CHIPS Alliance SystemVerilog subgroup, Antmicro has made further steps to facilitate SystemVerilog workflows with Verible, by providing an easy to use &lt;a href="https://github.com/chipsalliance/verible-linter-action">Verible Linter GitHub Action&lt;/a>. Combined with another open source tool called &lt;a href="https://github.com/reviewdog/reviewdog">Reviewdog&lt;/a>, the action allows you to easily perform automatic code style checks and code review.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Progress on Building Open Source Infrastructure for System Verilog</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/202/news/open-source-infrastructure-for-system-verilog/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/202/news/open-source-infrastructure-for-system-verilog/</guid><description>&lt;p>SystemVerilog is a rich hardware design description and verification language that is seeing increased usage in industry. In the second Deep Dive Cafe Talk by CHIPS Alliance on July 20, Henner Zeller, who is an software developer with Google, provided an excellent in depth technical talk on building out an open source tooling ecosystem around SystemVerilog to provide a common framework that can be used by both functional simulation applications as well as logic synthesis. In case you missed the live presentation, you can watch it &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/xLxNHBzmGiI">here&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Intel joins CHIPS Alliance to promote Advanced Interface Bus (AIB) as an open standard</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/202/news/intel-joins-chips-alliance-to-promote-advanced-interface-bus-aib-as-an-open-standard/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/202/news/intel-joins-chips-alliance-to-promote-advanced-interface-bus-aib-as-an-open-standard/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>Open development for SOCs gets major boost with new collaboration&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>SAN FRANCISCO, Jan. 22, 2020 /PRNewswire/&lt;/strong> — CHIPS Alliance, the leading consortium advancing common and open hardware for interfaces, processors and systems, today announced industry leading chipmaker Intel as it’s newest member. Intel is contributing the Advanced Interface Bus (AIB) to CHIPS Alliance to foster broad adoption.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>CHIPS Alliance is hosted by the Linux Foundation to foster a collaborative environment to accelerate the creation and deployment of open SoCs, peripherals and software tools for use in mobile, computing, consumer electronics and Internet of Things (IoT) applications. The CHIPS Alliance project develops high-quality open source Register Transfer Level (RTL) code and software development tools relevant to the design of open source CPUs, SoCs, and complex peripherals for Field Programmable Gate Arrays (FPGAs) and custom silicon.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>