<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>CHIPS Alliance</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/</link><description>Recent content on CHIPS Alliance</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://chipsalliance.org/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Developer Spotlight- Building Trust, Tools, and the Future of Open Silicon</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/news/rob-mains-spotlight/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/news/rob-mains-spotlight/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>In this Developer Spotlight, Rob Mains, Executive Director of CHIPS Alliance, reflects on the lessons that shaped his career, the realities of open source silicon, and what it will take to build a sustainable, production-ready open hardware ecosystem.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>From IBM to Oracle, Rob Mains has spent decades working across the full stack of silicon development. This experience has helped shape a leadership philosophy grounded in trust, respect and collaboration. At CHIPS Alliance, this perspective supports a neutral collaboration model that allows companies to jointly develop foundational technologies without blurring competitive boundaries.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Inside the Evolution of Chisel- Jack Koenig on Open Source Silicon Design at SiFive</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/news/spotlight-jack-koenig/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/news/spotlight-jack-koenig/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>From reluctant programmer to compiler maintainer, a decade-long journey shaping open source digital design tools.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Jack Koenig is a Senior Staff Engineer at SiFive and one of the longest-standing maintainers of the Chisel and FIRRTL projects.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Over the past decade, his contributions have helped shape the foundation of open source hardware description in Scala, bridging the worlds of compiler theory, HDL design, and functional programming.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In this developer spotlight, we explore Jack&amp;rsquo;s journey into open source silicon, his technical contributions, and what lies ahead for Chisel and its ecosystem.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Support for upstream UVM 2017 in Verilator</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/news/uvm-verilator/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/news/uvm-verilator/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.accellera.org/community/uvm">Universal Verification Methodology (UVM)&lt;/a> is one of the most popular verification methods in digital design, focusing on standardization and reusability of verification IP and environments. For the last few years, Antmicro has been gradually completing milestones toward full UVM support in the open source &lt;a href="https://github.com/verilator">Verilator RTL simulator&lt;/a>, from &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/blog/2021/05/dynamic-scheduling-in-verilator/">dynamic scheduling&lt;/a> (later enhanced with &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/blog/2021/12/coroutines-for-dynamic-scheduling-in-verilator/">coroutines&lt;/a>) through a &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/blog/2023/10/running-simple-uvm-testbenches-in-verilator/">proof-of-concept UVM testbench running in Verilator&lt;/a> to &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/blog/2024/03/introducing-constrained-randomization-in-verilator/">constrained randomization&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>With this article, CHIPS Alliance is happy to announce that Verilator can now elaborate upstream UVM 2017-1.0 - &lt;a href="https://github.com/chipsalliance/uvm-verilator/pull/9">no patches or workarounds&lt;/a> required. This important milestone was spearheaded by Antmicro&amp;rsquo;s efforts within &lt;a href="https://www.chipsalliance.org/">CHIPS Alliance&lt;/a> and complemented by the work of Wilson Snyder, the maintainer of Verilator, as well as the broader open source community.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Structuring Open Silicon - A TAC Perspective with Aaron Cunningham</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/news/structuring-open-silicon/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/news/structuring-open-silicon/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="how-a-globally-distributed-program-manager-is-helping-define-the-next-phase-of-open-source-silicon-collaboration">How a globally distributed program manager is helping define the next phase of open source silicon collaboration.&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Introduction&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Aaron Cunningham serves as Chair of the CHIPS Alliance Technical Advisory Council (TAC) and is a Technical Program Manager at Google focused on tooling, architecture, and hardware optimization. From managing infrastructure in Singapore to advocating for cross-project clarity at the Linux Foundation, Aaron brings a uniquely strategic lens to the complexities of scaling open source silicon.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>CHIPS Alliance showcases innovation at OCP Global Summit</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/news/ocp-2025-recap/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/news/ocp-2025-recap/</guid><description>&lt;p>The &lt;a href="https://www.opencompute.org/blog/2025-ocp-global-summit-by-the-numbers">OCP Global Summit&lt;/a>, hosted in San Jose, CA on October 15-17, brought together leaders in open hardware, hyperscale infrastructure, silicon, and data center innovation to collaborate on the future of open computing. Around 10,835 attendees were onsite at the event, which featured keynote presentations, technical sessions and interactive demos showcasing advancements in chip design, AI infrastructure, sustainability and open source hardware standards.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>CHIPS Alliance had a strong presence at the OCP Global Summit, demonstrating how open source silicon development is advancing innovation across data centers, AI and custom silicon. CHIPS was prominently mentioned in a number of keynote sessions on Tuesday as well as Thursday’s detailed technical sessions as part of the overall &lt;a href="https://www.chipsalliance.org/news/caliptra2-1/">Caliptra&lt;/a> effort. These sessions helped drive attendance to the CHIPS Alliance booth, which was shared with the OpenPower Foundation, on the exhibition floor. Rob Mains, Executive Director of CHIPS Alliance, chatted with interested attendees about a wide range of topics including interoperability, open standards, and the importance of community-driven silicon innovation.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>CHIPS Alliance’s Caliptra Launches 2.1 RTL Release</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/news/caliptra2-1/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/news/caliptra2-1/</guid><description>&lt;p>As the Caliptra partners and CHIPS Alliance members Microsoft, Google, NVIDIA and AMD continue to push the boundaries of open hardware security, we’re excited to announce the &lt;strong>Caliptra 2.1 RTL release&lt;/strong> — another important step in building a more secure and transparent silicon ecosystem. This update builds on Caliptra 2.0, delivering refined features, improved verification, and smoother integration for adopters across the industry.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The growing momentum behind Caliptra highlights the power of collaboration between the &lt;a href="https://www.opencompute.org/">Open Compute Project (OCP)&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://www.chipsalliance.org/">CHIPS Alliance&lt;/a> communities. Our shared commitment to innovation is helping shape a future where trusted hardware security is accessible, verifiable, and built on open standards.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>CHIPS Alliance at the 2025 OCP Global Summit</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/events/ocp-10-2025/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/events/ocp-10-2025/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="ocp-c48.png" alt="OCP Booth Card">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>CHIPS Alliance at the 2025 OCP Global Summit&lt;/strong>
&lt;strong>October 13–16, 2025 | San Jose Convention Center&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>CHIPS Alliance will be onsite at the &lt;a href="https://www.opencompute.org/summit/global-summit">OCP Global Summit 2025&lt;/a> to explore the latest advances in open silicon and hardware security. This year’s program features talks on &lt;strong>Caliptra&lt;/strong>, the open source Root-of-Trust project highlighting its roadmap, security enhancements, cryptographic core, and integration into real-world cloud and platform environments.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You can also &lt;strong>meet CHIPS Alliance Executive Director Rob Mains at the OpenPOWER Foundation booth (C48)&lt;/strong> to learn more about ongoing community efforts and how to get involved. See the talk details below.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>CHIPS Alliance at the 2025 OCP Global Summit</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/news/ocp-october2025/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/news/ocp-october2025/</guid><description>&lt;p>CHIPS Alliance will be onsite at &lt;a href="https://www.opencompute.org/summit/global-summit">OCP Global Summit 2025&lt;/a>, which takes place on Monday, October 13-Thursday, October 16 at the San Jose Convention Center! We’re excited about this year’s program, which features several talks about &lt;a href="https://www.chipsalliance.org/news/chips-alliance-welcomes-the-caliptra-open-source-root-of-trust-project/">Caliptra&lt;/a>, the open source Root-of-Trust (RoT) project highlighting its roadmap, security enhancements, cryptographic core, and integration into real-world cloud and platform environments.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Check out the sessions on Thursday, October 16 and them to your calendar here:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>CHIPS Alliance at DAC 2025</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/events/chips-alliance-dac-06-2025/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/events/chips-alliance-dac-06-2025/</guid><description>&lt;p>Check out the presentation below:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Caliptra: A silicon root of trust &lt;a href="DAC_Caliptra_2025.pptx.pdf">(slides)&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Generating interactive coverage dashboards for VeeR and Caliptra with Coverview</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/news/coverage-dashboards-for-veer-and-caliptra/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/news/coverage-dashboards-for-veer-and-caliptra/</guid><description>&lt;p>Code coverage is a useful metric to keep track of while developing test suites, providing engineering teams with an actionable overview of how broad their testing goes. This is true both for executable code and digital design, but the different nature of RTL and software execution requires developers to look at different types of coverage information. On top of tracking executed code lines and visited branches, RTL coverage will also need to include information e.g. about specific bit field toggles of all the signals in the design. The thorough testing of a sufficient number of combinations of those signals can be the “make or break” for an RTL design.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>CHIPS Alliance at OCP EMEA Summit 2025</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/events/04-2025-chips-alliance-ocp/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/events/04-2025-chips-alliance-ocp/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="speaker-card-ocp-2025.png" alt="OCP Speaker Card">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Heading to the Open Compute Project Foundation EMEA Summit, and looking to learn how open source silicon is accelerating chip design? Visit Rob Mains and Stefano Righi at booth A13.
CHIPS Alliance is proud to participate as an open source partner of the event.
We&amp;rsquo;re looking forward to insightful discussions, sharing successes and challenges in collaborative hardware and firmware development, and connecting with the open compute community.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Next Chapter in Open Source Silicon- Download the CHIPS Alliance White Paper</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/news/tac-whitepaper/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/news/tac-whitepaper/</guid><description>&lt;p>CHIPS Alliance has just released a new white paper, CHIPS Alliance and the Open Hardware Landscape, designed to demystify the current state of open hardware, outline the challenges ahead, and chart a path forward for everyone from startups to silicon giants.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="why-read-this">Why Read This?&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>If you are building silicon, designing SoCs, or investing in hardware innovation, this paper is your strategic guide to understanding where open hardware is headed and how you can be part of it.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>New revision of Data Center RDIMM DDR5 Tester</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/news/new-revision-of-data-center-rdimm-ddr5-tester/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/news/new-revision-of-data-center-rdimm-ddr5-tester/</guid><description>&lt;p>A few years back, Antmicro introduced the first DDR5 capable platform to the open source &lt;a href="https://github.com/antmicro/rowhammer-tester">FPGA-based Rowhammer research framework&lt;/a> developed in cooperation with Google - the &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/blog/2022/08/extending-the-open-source-rowhammer-testing-framework-to-ddr5/">Data Center RDIMM DDR5 Tester&lt;/a>. The follow-on &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/blog/2024/02/versatile-so-dimm-lpddr5-rowhammer-testing-platform/">SO-DIMM (LP)DDR5 Tester&lt;/a> later extended the framework’s coverage to both SO-DIMM DDR5 modules and LPDDR5.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In this article, Antmicro introduces and provides an overview of a &lt;a href="https://github.com/antmicro/rdimm-ddr5-tester">new revision of the RDIMM DDR5 Tester&lt;/a> employing a more recent &lt;a href="https://designer.antmicro.com/hardware/devices/amd-xilinx-xcau25p-2ffvb676i">AMD Artix UltraScale+ XCAU25P&lt;/a> FPGA as compared to Kintex-7 series used in the previous revision. Artix UltraScale+ is a next-gen series of AMD (Xilinx) FPGAs with higher density of logic cells, higher I/O bandwidth, as well as more High Performance (HP) I/Os with a broader operating voltage range - all of which translate to concrete benefits for the platform, described below.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Constrained randomization in Verilator</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/news/constrained-randomization-verilator/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/news/constrained-randomization-verilator/</guid><description>&lt;p>Digital design verification often utilizes the so-called constrained randomization functionality offered by SystemVerilog, where in order to efficiently test designs with random but still correct data, a digital logic designer can put constraints in place. This allows verification tests to run shorter by focusing the validation of the design’s behavior on input that the designer considers useful and interesting.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A few months ago Antmicro &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/blog/2024/03/introducing-constrained-randomization-in-verilator/">introduced constrained randomization to Verilator&lt;/a> - another significant milestone on the way towards full open source support for SystemVerilog and industry-prevalent &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/blog/2023/10/running-simple-uvm-testbenches-in-verilator/">UVM testbenches&lt;/a>. This work has been highly anticipated by many industrial users and is allowing Antmicro to slowly but steadily adopt Verilator for UVM-style verification in their state of the art silicon development work like CHIPS Alliance’s &lt;a href="https://github.com/chipsalliance/Caliptra">Caliptra Root of Trust&lt;/a> project.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Caliptra - Support for VeeR EL2 with User Mode and Physical Memory Protection in Tock embedded OS</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/news/caliptra-support-for-veer/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/news/caliptra-support-for-veer/</guid><description>&lt;p>The &lt;a href="https://chipsalliance.github.io/Caliptra/">Caliptra&lt;/a> Root of Trust project, a collaboration between AMD, Google, Microsoft and NVIDIA within the &lt;a href="https://www.chipsalliance.org/">CHIPS Alliance&lt;/a>, is steadily heading towards its &lt;a href="https://www.chipsalliance.org/news/caliptra-ocp-global-summit-2024/">2.0 release&lt;/a> – an effort Antmicro is &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=hXjUoCGlXyM">actively contributing to&lt;/a>. They’ve recently described their &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/blog/2024/09/user-mode-in-veer-el2-core-for-caliptra-2-0/">implementation of User mode&lt;/a> in the RISC-V VeeR EL2 core along with extended Physical Memory Protection, and related to this work, they’ve introduced support for VeeR EL2 with User Mode and PMP to the &lt;a href="https://github.com/tock/tock">Tock&lt;/a> embedded OS. The main goal of this implementation was to test the mode switching feature of the VeeR EL2 core with PMP enabled.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Topwrap – open source toolkit for modular, parameterizable digital logic design</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/news/topwrap/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/news/topwrap/</guid><description>&lt;p>ASIC and FPGA designs consist of distinct blocks of logic bound together by a top-level design. Taking advantage of this modularity and enabling automation and reuse of blocks across designs requires tools for automated processing and generation of top level files, letting you easily parametrize and aggregate the blocks in various configurations.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To this end, Antmicro created &lt;a href="https://github.com/antmicro/topwrap">Topwrap&lt;/a>, an open source toolkit for connecting individual HDL modules into full designs of varying complexity. The toolkit is designed to take advantage of the ever-growing library of open source digital logic blocks that they also &lt;a href="https://github.com/chipsalliance/i3c-core">heavily contribute to&lt;/a> and, thanks to its structuredness, offers a user-friendly graphical interface sitting on top of a well-formed CLI. This in turn lets you mix-and-match high-level GUI-driven design with more fine-grained CLI-level adjustments and present designs in the form of a diagram thanks to the integration with Antmicro’s &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/blog/2024/02/add-web-based-guis-with-pipeline-manager/">Pipeline Manager&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Caliptra @ OCP Global Summit 2024</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/news/caliptra-ocp-global-summit-2024/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/news/caliptra-ocp-global-summit-2024/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">Introduction&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>As we continue to advance the field of hardware security, we are thrilled to celebrate the successful integration of Caliptra 1.x by our esteemed partners. Their commitment to enhancing security through the adoption of our open-source Root of Trust (RoT) is a testament to the collaborative spirit of the Open Compute Project (OCP). In this post, we also look ahead to the exciting developments planned for Caliptra 2.0.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="recognizing-caliptra-1x-integrators">Recognizing Caliptra 1.x Integrators&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>We are proud to recognize the following companies for their successful integration of Caliptra 1.x into their products. Each integrator has demonstrated a strong commitment to security, transparency, and innovation. Click on the company names to read their detailed blog posts about their integration of Caliptra:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Open Hardware Mini-Summit</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/events/chips-2024-osseu-mini-summit/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/events/chips-2024-osseu-mini-summit/</guid><description>&lt;p>Check out the presentations below:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="./presentations/2024-osseu/CHIPS-Alliance-Introduction-2024.pdf">Welcome / Opening Remarks / Accelerating Innovation with Open Hardware Design&lt;/a> - Rob Mains - General Manager, CHIPS Alliance&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="./presentations/2024-osseu/RISC-V-opportunity-and-innovation.pdf">RISC-V: Getting Involved, Latest Advancements&lt;/a> - Andrea Gallo - VP Technology, RISC-V&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="./presentations/2024-osseu/ETISS-PerfMod-Seal5-FI_OSS3public.pdf">Open Source Simulators for Pre-Silicon Validation of Safety-critical RISC-V System-on-chip&lt;/a> - Daniel Mueller-Gritschneder, Johannes Geier - Professor, TU Wien&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="./presentations/2024-osseu/OSSVienna2024-New-open-source-IP-tools-and-verification-flows-for-Caliptra-2_0.pdf">Making VeeR EL2 Caliptra 2.0-ready: enhanced functionalities, verification and documentation&lt;/a> - Karol Gugala - Engineering Manager, Antmicro&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="./presentations/2024-osseu/Sandner-LF-Chips-workshop-vienna%202024-final.pdf">Value and Opportunities in Open Source for Circuit Design&lt;/a> - Christoph Sandner - Senior Principal Engineer, Infineon&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="./presentations/2024-osseu/Open-Source-IC-design-for-Automotive.pdf">Open Source IC design for Automotive: Real World Experience&lt;/a> - Rob Taylor - Chief Strategy Officer, ChipFlow&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Initial assertion control support in Verilator</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/news/initial-assertion-control-support-in-verilator/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/news/initial-assertion-control-support-in-verilator/</guid><description>&lt;p>Antmicro is continuously working on improving productivity of ASIC design and verification workflows using open source tools as leaders of the &lt;a href="https://www.chipsalliance.org/">CHIPS Alliance&lt;/a> Tools Workgroup, as well as for customer and R&amp;amp;D projects. Extending &lt;a href="https://github.com/verilator">Verilator&lt;/a> with new verification features is a prominent example of such efforts, with the latest notable improvements including &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/blog/2023/10/running-simple-uvm-testbenches-in-verilator/">initial support for UVM testbenches&lt;/a>, the &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/blog/2024/01/analyze-verilator-processes-and-asts/">astsee tool for Verilator process and AST analysis&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/blog/2024/03/introducing-constrained-randomization-in-verilator/">constrained randomization&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In this article, Antmicro introduces initial support for global assertion control (&lt;a href="https://github.com/verilator/verilator/pull/5010">already part of mainline Verilator&lt;/a>), building on existing support for assertions available in the simulator. These changes simplify verification testing by letting developers enable or disable assertions as required by particular simulation stages or testing scenarios. Antmicro delves into the benefits of this implementation, examines several use cases where assertion control can prove useful and provide considerations for the path towards full support.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Speeding Up OpenROAD For Fast Design Feedback</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/news/speeding-up-openroad-for-fast-design-feedback/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/news/speeding-up-openroad-for-fast-design-feedback/</guid><description>&lt;p>The &lt;a href="https://theopenroadproject.org/">OpenROAD&lt;/a> project provides an open source ASIC toolchain that reduces the entry barriers to the field of hardware development and allows fast-turnaround feedback about designs, helping to increase the productivity of silicon teams. As such, it’s a great supporting tool, increasingly used in state-of-the-art industrial projects alongside other open source tools like Verilator.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Antmicro has been helping early adopters of OpenROAD-based flows in projects such as &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/blog/2021/12/sw-driven-asics-with-skywater-shuttle/">SkyWater Shuttle&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/blog/2023/03/adapting-opentitan-for-fpga-prototyping-and-tooling-development/">OpenTitan&lt;/a> or more recently, Google’s &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/blog/2023/09/accelerating-digital-block-design-with-googles-xls/">XLS&lt;/a>. As a result, there is an increasing amount of interest in improving the performance of OpenROAD to yield faster turnaround times, especially for large and complex designs.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Open Hardware and Software: Accelerating Beyond Moore’s Law and Enabling the Next Wave of Innovation</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/events/chips-2024-ossna-mini-summit/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/events/chips-2024-ossna-mini-summit/</guid><description>&lt;p>Check out the presentations below:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Introductions - Rob Mains, Linux Foundation (&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/19pvCN0KhZa-wbi0P0eJ73uIp_ThnqRDr/view?usp=drive_link">slides&lt;/a>)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>How can software developers help keep Moore&amp;rsquo;s law alive? - Michael Gielda, Antmicro (&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1NiWgD-VeILyyTTNuF8FNYOtBIN-eREaz/view?usp=drive_link">slides&lt;/a>)&lt;!-- - Open Hardware Design: Lessons Learned from OSS - Stephano Cetola, Intel ([slides](http://xxx)) -->&lt;/li>
&lt;li>HBOM talk - Kate Stewart, Linux Foundation (&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/18qBdzhXKJTCAdn3O_96sIZJf04NZihC2/view?usp=drive_link">slides&lt;/a>)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Scaling hardware design: squeezing every bit of performance of the open source OpenROAD ASIC toolchain - Karol Gugula, Antmicro (&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1JVKM7T086l6cQbhgtCHs87qCUEd-KGkz/view?usp=drive_link">slides&lt;/a>)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Accelerating EDA Flows in the AWS Cloud - David Pellerin, AWS (&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1QFaLICbUyR_zNKeX7jncM7avIdTxX8v9/view?usp=drive_link">slides&lt;/a>)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>An Introduction to RISC-V - Keith Graham, Codasip (&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1pyWnAHPkhU9pOVM_Y5GxrgNEENdfeEpq/view?usp=drive_link">slides&lt;/a>)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Accelerating the RISC-V Software Development Ecosystem - Jeffrey Osler-Mixon, Red Hat (&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1uZBNKo-DbUaGPtQ10EXrfkiGKZJ8HcBN/view?usp=drive_link">slides&lt;/a>)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Caliptra open source Root of Trust - Caleb Whitehead, Microsoft (&lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1YknoZ7SpdsMiv5UnWDqvByrI1qPJnUed/edit?usp=drive_link&amp;amp;ouid=117663238184989073790&amp;amp;rtpof=true&amp;amp;sd=true">slides&lt;/a>)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Getting “Ware” You Need to Go – Managing Open Hardware with Software (Part 1) - Maximillian Schmidt &amp;amp; Lance Albertson, Oregon State University (&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1M1NP-IoeDcAn4503xqCx6wtgDCWZJHv1/view?usp=drive_link">slides&lt;/a>)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Getting “Ware” You Need to Go - AI Software on Open Hardware (Part 2) - Christopher Sullivan , Oregon State University (&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1M1NP-IoeDcAn4503xqCx6wtgDCWZJHv1/view?usp=drive_link">slides&lt;/a>)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Google Summer of Code 2024</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/events/google-summer-of-code-2024/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/events/google-summer-of-code-2024/</guid><description>&lt;p>As in previous years, CHIPS Alliance returns as a mentor organization for Google Summer of Code 2024.
Become a contributor and join us in our mission to push forward open source hardware, ASIC and FPGA design.
Explore our list of project ideas and submit by April 2:
&lt;a href="https://github.com/chipsalliance/ideas/blob/main/gsoc-2024-ideas.md">https://github.com/chipsalliance/ideas/blob/main/gsoc-2024-ideas.md&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Adding Physical Memory Protection to the VeeR EL2 RISC-V Core</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/news/adding-physical-memory-protection-to-the-veer-el2-risc-v-core/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/news/adding-physical-memory-protection-to-the-veer-el2-risc-v-core/</guid><description>&lt;p>Antmicro’s work with CHIPS Alliance’s &lt;a href="https://github.com/chipsalliance/Caliptra">Caliptra Root of Trust&lt;/a> project, led by Google, AMD, NVIDIA, and Microsoft focuses around providing &lt;a href="https://opensource.googleblog.com/2023/11/open-source-and-ci-driven-rtl-testing-and-verification-caliptra-risc-v-veer-core.html">automated testing and verification infrastructure&lt;/a> including code quality checks, code indexing, coverage and functional testing pipelines, as well as maintaining and enhancing the RISC-V VeeR EL2 core which sits in the middle of the Caliptra design. As providers of commercial engineering services around open source tools and silicon blocks, working on Caliptra gives Antmicro both a solid starting point for assisting customers with practical RoT implementations as well as a template for CI-driven ASIC development.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Analyze Verilator processes and ASTs with the astsee suite</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/news/analyze-verilator-processes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/news/analyze-verilator-processes/</guid><description>&lt;p>Among other things, Antmicro’s work towards improving the vertical integration potential of customers designing ASIC solutions often sees them enhance one of the flagship open source projects in this space, Verilator which complements - and in fact is &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/blog/2023/09/dpi-support-in-renode-for-hdl-co-simulation-with-verilator-and-questa/">often used alongside&lt;/a> - Antmicro’s own functional simulation framework, &lt;a href="https://about.renode.io">Renode&lt;/a>. Besides contributing bug fixes and other quality-of-life improvements into Verilator, Antmicro also develops new functionalities that &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/blog/2023/10/running-simple-uvm-testbenches-in-verilator/">expand its use cases towards e.g. UVM verification&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/blog/2023/09/accelerating-model-generation-in-verilator/">continuously improve overall performance&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Versatile SO-DIMM (LP)DDR5 Rowhammer testing platform</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/news/versatile-rowhammer-testing-platform/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/news/versatile-rowhammer-testing-platform/</guid><description>&lt;p>Ten years after the &lt;a href="https://users.ece.cmu.edu/~yoonguk/papers/kim-isca14.pdf">first disclosure of the initial Rowhammer security exploit&lt;/a>, new DRAM vulnerabilities continue to be discovered, and developing new and efficient mitigation techniques requires a deep understanding of the problem considering the complexity of modern DRAM. To safeguard its Data Center and edge device use cases, Google has been using Antmicro’s advanced R&amp;amp;D capabilities to develop an &lt;a href="https://github.com/antmicro/rowhammer-tester">open source FPGA-based memory testing suite&lt;/a> and family of open hardware platforms, expanding beyond the capabilities of pure-software vulnerability testing and mitigation approaches. The targeted DDR variants have so far included &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/blog/2021/04/lpddr4-test-platform/">LPDDR4&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/blog/2021/12/open-source-data-center-rowhammer-tester/">DDR4&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/blog/2022/08/extending-the-open-source-rowhammer-testing-framework-to-ddr5/">DDR5 RDIMM&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>CHIPS Technology Update - November 2023</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/events/chips-2023-fall-event/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/events/chips-2023-fall-event/</guid><description>&lt;p>Check out the presentations below, and &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLWm-dtUGVJtDPlmNDxaa3g98N4OH9_a4C">watch the replay here&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Project Open Se Cura – Kenny Vassigh, Bangfei Pan, Cindy Liu, Kai Yick, Google, Michael Gielda, Antmicro, Brian Murray, Verisilicon (&lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/19dsfGeRU_ec79TK5oEIw0apOJDRcHCeO/edit?usp=sharing&amp;amp;ouid=111827616379981113572&amp;amp;rtpof=true&amp;amp;sd=true">slides&lt;/a>)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Caliptra Workgroup Update - Andres Lagar-Cavilla, Google (&lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1lnuCjGXgq6hQOuYpi2TCu2XfKhR-0u7n7M_5LnCYcQk/edit?usp=sharing&amp;amp;resourcekey=0-vUEiQr06SIA0mncC7bjQog">slides&lt;/a>)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Enabling UVM testbenches in Verilator - Michael Gielda, Karol Gugala, Antmicro (&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1GL-zKUKcHZaepM5SUJUIxnFZL7qdaJc4/view?usp=sharing">slides&lt;/a>)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>FuseSOC: Package manager and build abstraction tool for FPGA/ASIC development - Olof Kindgren, Qamcom (&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1f0tjKRvHG1yfoKOzfGLSKDSdTUNxbaSv/view?usp=sharing">slides&lt;/a>)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>CHIPYard: An Open Source RISC-V Design Frameowrk - Sagar Karandikar, U.C. Berkeley (&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1KNe5N_ex-aUCcs6RoVxDd1lV0OboAD6p/view?usp=sharing">slides&lt;/a>)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLWm-dtUGVJtDPlmNDxaa3g98N4OH9_a4C">Watch the Replay&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Initial Open Source Support for UVM Testbenches in Verilator</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/news/initial-open-source-support-for-uvm-testbenches-in-verilator/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/news/initial-open-source-support-for-uvm-testbenches-in-verilator/</guid><description>&lt;p>Leading the efforts of the Tools Workgroup in CHIPS Alliance, across a variety of customer projects, as well as its own R&amp;amp;D, Antmicro is actively looking for and capturing the productivity enhancements that can be achieved in ASIC design using open source. Developing and using open source-enhanced workflows is one thing, but in order for the general shift towards open source to happen, open source support for tooling and methodologies that are already prevalent across the chipmaking industry is necessary.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>RISC-V Summit North America 2023</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/events/riscv_na_2023/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/events/riscv_na_2023/</guid><description>&lt;p>Please join us at the RISC-V North American Summit November 7 - 8&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Be sure to come visit us at the CHIPS Alliance booth at the event.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Details &lt;a href="https://events.linuxfoundation.org/riscv-summit/">here: &lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>CHIPS Alliance at the Open Compute Project Global Summit</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/events/chips_ocp_2023/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/events/chips_ocp_2023/</guid><description>&lt;p>Please join us at the Open Compute Project Global Summit to hear about the Caliptra Root of Trust collaborative project.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Be sure to come visit us at booth C37 hosted by the Linux Foundation at the event.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Details &lt;a href="https://www.opencompute.org/summit/global-summit">here &lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Verilator Model Generation Performance Improvements and Initial Multithreaded Verilation Support</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/news/verilator-model-generation-performance-improvements-and-initial-multithreaded-verilation-support/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/news/verilator-model-generation-performance-improvements-and-initial-multithreaded-verilation-support/</guid><description>&lt;p>Verilator can boast the status of one of the most widely used free and open source digital design tools for ASIC and FPGA development. To stay on top of the ever-increasing complexity of ASIC and FPGA devices, as users and contributors, Antmicro, a CHIPS Alliance member and part of the &lt;a href="https://lists.chipsalliance.org/g/tools-wg">Tools Workgroup&lt;/a>, has been actively working on improving the tool and its ecosystem, &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/blog/2023/01/cpu-rtl-co-simulation-in-renode/">including adding co-simulation capabilities with Renode&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/blog/2023/01/open-source-systemverilog-uvm-support-in-verilator/">adding support for SystemVerilog UVM testbenches to Verilator&lt;/a>, or &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/blog/2022/11/scaling-verilator-for-very-large-designs/">improving scalability for very large designs&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Progress in open source SystemVerilog / UVM support in Verilator</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/news/progress-in-open-source-systemverilog-uvm-support-in-verilator/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/news/progress-in-open-source-systemverilog-uvm-support-in-verilator/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://github.com/verilator/verilator">Verilator&lt;/a> is a shining example of a widely-accepted open source tool which provides state-of-the-art results in the ASIC design space. It is commonly used for simulation and testing, but originally, due to the lack of capability to run event-driven simulations, Verilator wasn’t even considered capable of handling UVM (Universal Verification Methodology) testbenches implemented in SystemVerilog which require scheduling and other features notably absent from the tool. For some time now, Antmicro, together with Western Digital, Google and others in the &lt;a href="https://chipsalliance.org/">CHIPS Alliance&lt;/a>, has been working on enabling fully open source support for SystemVerilog UVM testbenches in Verilator. This has already resulted in significant breakthroughs we have described in this blog, such as implementing &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/blog/2021/12/coroutines-for-dynamic-scheduling-in-verilator/">event-driven simulation capabilities&lt;/a> in Verilator which has &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/jevinskie/status/1602834358561566720">enabled new and exciting use cases&lt;/a>. Since then, on the road to proper UVM testbench support, Antmicro has been working on adding various SystemVerilog constructs and UVM-specific elements into Verilator, which bring us much closer to the goal - the current status and next goals will be described in more detail in this blog note.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>CHIPS Alliance Summer Workshop 2023</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/events/chips-biannual-technology-update-2022_13_07/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/events/chips-biannual-technology-update-2022_13_07/</guid><description>&lt;p>Check out the presentations below, and &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/L-kRRL7i28g">watch the replay here&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Caliptra &amp;amp; VeeR continuous integration ecosystem – Michael Gielda, Antmicro (&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1VIwPmIN69roonMOZbKvKmAQb9EFiBarO/view?usp=drive_link">slides&lt;/a>)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Caliptra: Validating firmware against multiple hardware models in CI - Kor Nielsen, Google&lt;/li>
&lt;li>OmniXtend: coherent scaleout over commodity fabrics - Jaco Hoffman, Westen Digital (&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1C0TS2ToVfJ96VY9MMypWeKTn9eHGYKrk/view?usp=drive_link">slides&lt;/a>)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>CHISEL 3 and Beyond - Jack Koenig, SiFive (&lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/13xT3rrKjgMWJU42TAgJwxIhjOeSOZUmn/edit?usp=drive_link">slides&lt;/a>)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Single Source library for digital design and virtual prototyping - Mikhail Moiseev, Intel (&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/18HZFnT4LwVx43rVIoMJj1AJUqKFmP7rS/view?usp=drive_link">slides&lt;/a>)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Building Confidence in Open IC Design using OpenFASOC - Mehdi Saligane, University of Michigan (&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1vuVm259aIS63oI67CZHstEn-A0K2PfVk/view?usp=drive_link">slides&lt;/a>)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://youtu.be/L-kRRL7i28g">Watch the Replay&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Open source and CI-driven RTL testing and verification for Caliptra’s RISC-V VeeR core</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/news/open-source-rtl-ci-testing-and-verification-for-caliptra-veer/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/news/open-source-rtl-ci-testing-and-verification-for-caliptra-veer/</guid><description>&lt;p>As part of &lt;a href="https://www.chipsalliance.org/">CHIPS Alliance’s&lt;/a> mission to enable a software-driven approach to silicon, working with Google and other CHIPS members, Antmicro has been developing and improving a growing number of open source tools to enable effective, CI-driven silicon development.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Fully reproducible and scalable workflows based on open source tooling are especially beneficial for efforts spanning across multiple industrial and academic actors such as Caliptra, a Root of Trust project driven by Google, AMD, NVIDIA and Microsoft which &lt;a href="https://chipsalliance.org/announcement/2022/12/13/chips-alliance-welcomes-the-caliptra-open-source-root-of-trust-project/">recently joined CHIPS&lt;/a> in order to host the ongoing development and provide the necessary structure, working environment and support for the reference implementation of the standard, originally hosted by &lt;a href="https://www.opencompute.org/documents/caliptra-silicon-rot-services-09012022-pdf">Open Compute Project&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Integrating the Language Server Protocol in Verible</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/news/integrating-language-server-protocol-in-verible/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/news/integrating-language-server-protocol-in-verible/</guid><description>&lt;p>A more collaborative, open and software driven ASIC design methodology pioneered by the &lt;a href="https://chipsalliance.org">CHIPS Alliance&lt;/a> requires an open source tooling stack to enable sharing of workflows, artifacts and fostering a free exchange of insights and improvements.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>While internally often using new design methodologies and languages such as Migen, Chisel or XLS, Antmicro is conscious of the fact that a lot of the world’s ASIC development involves SystemVerilog and UVM, and so we are working on bridging traditional and new ASIC development methodologies as described in a &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/blog/2023/01/open-source-systemverilog-uvm-support-in-verilator/">recent blog note&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>CHIPS Alliance Fall Workshop 2022</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/events/chips-biannual-technology-update-2022-2/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/events/chips-biannual-technology-update-2022-2/</guid><description>&lt;p>Check out the presentations below, and &lt;a href="https://youtube.com/playlist?list=PLWm-dtUGVJtDkvxTpThB3cAu0dNxwrlHc">watch the replay here&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Caliptra – Bryan Kelly, Microsoft&lt;/li>
&lt;li>SBOM and HBOM / Zephyr - Kate Stewart, Linux Foundation&lt;/li>
&lt;li>F4PGA tools in the classroom - Mike Wirthlin, Jeff Goeders, BYU (&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1zpINI7TaM99YFFsGjjvicwwG04jwMlvZ/view?usp=sharing">slides&lt;/a>)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Datasets for Machine Learning for Chip Design - Aman Arora, UT-Austin (&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1Df-lPpZ-XhMcqfMe4hkK19ECPdtmZep5/view?usp=sharing">slides&lt;/a>)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Open source SystemVerilog / UVM support and scaling for large designs in Verilator 5.0 and beyond, Michael Gielda, Antmicro (&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1YbfE5tJ7-expgfrhhGF1ep7-WsOzBDZj/view?usp=sharing">slides&lt;/a>)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Lowering barriers to chip design using OpenFASOC, AWG activities and tapeouts, Mehdi Saligane, University of Michigan (&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/12t_dZHL7nIFWo6OXcnw7YBujIg1fSrV-/view?usp=sharing">slides&lt;/a>)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Global Foundries Open PDK, Karthik Chandrasekaran, Global Foundries&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Caravel SOC Learnings, Mohammed Kassem, Efabless, (&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1sZ82ahy_oCg6kbkKOcZkkN1W0iQx4Ulm/view?usp=sharing">slides&lt;/a>)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Intel Compiler for SystemC, Mikhail Moiseev, Intel (&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1pQ90HjaEwrfan0FN9Qk63aw5LVWqnhpI/view?usp=sharing">slides&lt;/a>)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Renode co-simulation for Caravel, Peter Gielda, Antmicro (&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1miW5NGX-ee2maolsFR5ptXI6iorfv1G-/view?usp=share_link">slides&lt;/a>)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://youtube.com/playlist?list=PLWm-dtUGVJtDkvxTpThB3cAu0dNxwrlHc">Watch the Replay&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>CHIPS Alliance Welcomes the Caliptra Open Source Root of Trust Project</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/news/chips-alliance-welcomes-the-caliptra-open-source-root-of-trust-project/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/news/chips-alliance-welcomes-the-caliptra-open-source-root-of-trust-project/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>SAN FRANCISCO, December 13, 2022&lt;/strong> – CHIPS Alliance, a Linux Foundation project and leading consortium advancing common and open hardware for interfaces, processors and systems, announced that &lt;a href="https://www.opencompute.org/blog/cloud-security-integrating-trust-into-every-chip">Caliptra&lt;/a>, the open source root of trust project founded by technology leaders AMD, Google, Microsoft and NVIDIA, has joined CHIPS Alliance to enable an open, collaborative community-driven approach to hardware security.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Caliptra is a new specification for an open source silicon root of trust (RoT) designed to meet the enhanced security requirements of modern edge and confidential computing workloads. CHIPS Alliance will oversee the open source implementation of register-transfer level (RTL) code for Caliptra that can be synthesized into current SoC designs, along with the verification suite and firmware. As part of this architecture, the open source RISC-V core hosted by the CHIPS Alliance and now relaunched as VeeR, is embedded within the Caliptra Root of Trust macro. VeeR is a true open source RISC-V core family with full RTL and verification bench all under Apache 2.0 license ready for anyone to use.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Joint Analog Workgroup / MOS-AK Panel Session</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/news/joint-analog-workgroup-mos-ak-panel-session/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/news/joint-analog-workgroup-mos-ak-panel-session/</guid><description>&lt;p>Please join us for a special joint panel webinar session for the CHIPS Alliance Analog Workgroup and MOS-AK Foundation.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This panel will feature speakers with 20 minute talks on the following topic areas:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="mailto:mehdi@umich.edu">@Mehdi Saligane&lt;/a> : Introduction to the open source EDA tool flow for IC design (with reference to [1])&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="mailto:nmakris@gmail.com">@Makris Nikolaos&lt;/a> : EKV3 in NGSPICE using ADMSXL&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="mailto:erkeite@sandia.gov">@Keiter, Eric R&lt;/a> : Xyce and its support for commercial (hSpice/spectre) libs/syntax&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="mailto:tim@efabless.com">@Tim Edwards&lt;/a> : his work on the SkyWater 130 nm compatibility with ngspice&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="mailto:cameron.eda@gmail.com">@Kevin Cameron&lt;/a> : update on the P1800 (SystemVerilog) AMS standardization efforts (public doc [2])
There will be time for Q &amp;amp; A after each talk and conversation after the presentation completion.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>This webinar can be accessed via the following Zoom link, and will be recorded:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>CHIPS Alliance Fall 2022 Technology Update December 15</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/news/chips-alliance-fall-2022-technology-update-december-15/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/news/chips-alliance-fall-2022-technology-update-december-15/</guid><description>&lt;p>Please join us on December 15 at 8:30 am PT either in person at Google or virtually for a CHIPS technology update featuring many exciting speakers. Details and registration are here: &lt;a href="https://events.linuxfoundation.org/chips-biannual-technology-update/">https://events.linuxfoundation.org/chips-biannual-technology-update/&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>F4PGA open source flow gets a new Python-based build system and CLI tool</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/news/f4pga-open-source-flow-gets-a-new-python-based-build-system-and-cli-tool/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/news/f4pga-open-source-flow-gets-a-new-python-based-build-system-and-cli-tool/</guid><description>&lt;p>One of the most recent projects developed within the workgroup is the &lt;a href="https://github.com/chipsalliance/f4pga">unified f4pga CLI tool&lt;/a>. In the broader context of our &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/blog/2021/09/fpga-interchange-format/">continuous efforts to make the FPGA space more unified and flexible&lt;/a>, creating the f4pga CLI tool was a logical next step – it allowed us to wrap the underlying tools into a single CLI, making the F4PGA toolchain a more complete flow. The currently supported architectures are AMD’s (former Xilinx) 7 Series, Lattice’s iCE40 and QuickLogic’s EOS S3. &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/blog/2022/09/f4pga-new-build-system-and-cli-tool">Details are here&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Skywater</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/news/skywater/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/news/skywater/</guid><description>&lt;p>It’s great to learn that Google &lt;a href="https://www.skywatertechnology.com/skywater-receives-funding-from-dod-partners-with-google-to-facilitate-open-source-design-for-its-new-90-nm-technology-offering/">announced&lt;/a> the expansion of its partnership with &lt;a href="https://www.skywatertechnology.com/">SkyWater Technology&lt;/a>. They are working together to release an open source process design kit (PDK) for SKY90-FD, SkyWater’s commercial 90nm fully depleted silicon on insulator (FDSOI) CMOS process technology. SKY90-FD is based on MIT Lincoln Laboratory’s 90 nm commercial FDSOI technology, and enables designers to create complex integrated circuits for a diverse range of applications.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You can read more @ &lt;a href="https://opensource.googleblog.com/2022/07/SkyWater-and-Google-expand-open-source-program-to-new-90nm-technology.html">https://opensource.googleblog.com/2022/07/SkyWater-and-Google-expand-open-source-program-to-new-90nm-technology.html&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Antmicro DDR5 Rowhammer Testing Framework</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/news/1212/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/news/1212/</guid><description>&lt;p>CHIPS Alliance is excited by the Antmicro announcement of the extensible, open, Rowhammer testing framework for DDR5. Read a detailed description of their work here: &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/blog/2022/08/extending-the-open-source-rowhammer-testing-framework-to-ddr5/">https://antmicro.com/blog/2022/08/extending-the-open-source-rowhammer-testing-framework-to-ddr5/&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Here are some graphics of the work:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="DDR5-diagram.svg" alt="DDR5 diagram">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="DDR5-photo.png" alt="DDR5 device">&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Catch us at DAC 59 in San Francisco starting July 11</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/news/catch-us-at-dac-59-in-san-francisco-starting-july-11/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/news/catch-us-at-dac-59-in-san-francisco-starting-july-11/</guid><description>&lt;p>Come learn about open source hardware and CHIPS Alliance at next week’s 59th Design Automation Conference in San Francisco. We will be at kiosk 2344 in the RISC-V pavilion. You can also here out talk at 12:30 Monday in the Open Source Central Theatre (booth 2338). We are also in a DAC Pavilion Panel: Is Democratization of Chip Design Already Happening? at 2:30 on Monday. Look forward to an exciting day in SF!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Enhanced System Verilog Support for Yosys via Antmicro plug-in</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/news/enhanced-system-verilog-support-for-yosys-via-antmicro-plug-in/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/news/enhanced-system-verilog-support-for-yosys-via-antmicro-plug-in/</guid><description>&lt;p>CHIPS Alliance is pleased to see the announcement by Antmicro for its development and contribution to the open source hardware community to provide a easy to use plug-in for any version of Yosys to allow import of System Verilog based designs. This development is made possible by the underlying utilization of the Unified Hardware Data Model (UHDM), a key open source data representation upon which EDA applications can be built. Details can be seen here from Antmicro: &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/blog/2022/02/simplifying-open-source-sv-synthesis-with-the-yosys-uhdm-plugin/">https://antmicro.com/blog/2022/02/simplifying-open-source-sv-synthesis-with-the-yosys-uhdm-plugin/&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Alibaba Cloud Announced Progress in Porting Android Functions onto RISC-V</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/news/alibaba-cloud-announced-progress-in-porting-android-functions-onto-risc-v/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/news/alibaba-cloud-announced-progress-in-porting-android-functions-onto-risc-v/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>The company also tops MLPerf Tiny v0.7 Benchmark with its IOT processor&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Hangzhou, China, April 20, 2022&lt;/strong> – Alibaba Cloud, the digital technologies and intelligence backbone of Alibaba Group, announced it has made further progress in porting basic Android functions onto the RISC-V instruction-set architecture (ISA). This proves the feasibility of using RISC-V based Android devices in scenarios ranging from multimedia to signal processing, device interconnection, and artificial intelligence.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Last year, the company reported it had successfully ported basic functions like chrome browsing in Android 10. Since the initial porting trial, further effort has been invested to rebase previous engineering on Android 12 to enable third-party vendor modules to facilitate new functions, including audio and video playback, WiFi and Bluetooth, as well as camera operation.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>CHIPS Alliance First 2022 Biannual Technology Update</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/events/chips-biannual-technology-update-2022-1/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/events/chips-biannual-technology-update-2022-1/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=L4saSRKnMF8&amp;amp;t=411s">Watch the Replay&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Check out the presentations below:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Introduction – Rob Mains, CHIPS Alliance&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Updates of Android on RISC-V – Han Mao, Alibaba
(&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1vxY0_EV5rV5K1LWDK0R6OENnpfwuXwwX/view?usp=sharing">slides&lt;/a>)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Chisel and FIRRTL for Next-Generation SoC Designs– Jack Koenig, SiFive
(&lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1ckTNFuA3FZ02ua1ad3I-ZtKVSWG8yxsh/edit?usp=sharing&amp;amp;ouid=111827616379981113572&amp;amp;rtpof=true&amp;amp;sd=true">slides&lt;/a>)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Introducting the F4PGA Workgroup– Michael Gielda, Karol Gugala, Antmicro
(&lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1y9EKrt2gIXMB1R5VxyajT6yNujT1yBkZ/edit?usp=sharing&amp;amp;ouid=111827616379981113572&amp;amp;rtpof=true&amp;amp;sd=true">slides&lt;/a>)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Chiplet IP Protocol– Dave Kehlet, Intel
(&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1hqnZRfV3kVKXuxBxccG5MStJmEE2bCfl/view?usp=sharing">slides&lt;/a>)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>NVMe Computational Storage Processor for Edge &amp;amp; Datacenter Applications, Anand Kulkarni, Wester Digital
(&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1dfz4WsyAnTCY5ZhERL7rJ3pdLcU6pqxe/view?usp=sharing">slides&lt;/a>)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Towards Open Source Models of Cryogenic CMOS : Brian Hoskins and Pragya Shrestha, NIST
(&lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1PbAu8p3cktjwp8T_lCpkik-WDsfYXlPI/edit?usp=sharing&amp;amp;ouid=111827616379981113572&amp;amp;rtpof=true&amp;amp;sd=true">slides&lt;/a>)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Latest Statistics from Google’s No Cost Shuttle Program : Tim Ansell, Google :
(&lt;a href="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://bit.ly/ca22-sky130&amp;amp;sa=D&amp;amp;source=editors&amp;amp;ust=1675105801423210&amp;amp;usg=AOvVaw1TMYq-R8UwomNAz9o2g52n">slides&lt;/a>)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=L4saSRKnMF8&amp;amp;t=411s">Watch the Replay&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>CHIPS Alliance Forms F4PGA Workgroup to Accelerate Adoption of Open Source FPGA Tooling</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/news/chips-alliance-forms-f4pga-workgroup-to-accelerate-adoption-of-open-source-fpga-tooling/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/news/chips-alliance-forms-f4pga-workgroup-to-accelerate-adoption-of-open-source-fpga-tooling/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>New workgroup draws support from industry leaders as the open FPGA toolchain matures&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>SAN FRANCISCO, Feb. 18, 2022&lt;/strong> – CHIPS Alliance, the leading consortium advancing common and open source hardware for interfaces, processors and systems, today established the FOSS Flow For FPGA (F4PGA) Workgroup to drive open source tooling, IP and research efforts for FPGAs.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>FPGA vendors such as Xilinx (now part of AMD) and QuickLogic, industrial FPGA users and contributors such as Google and Antmicro, as well as universities including Brigham Young University, University of Pennsylvania, Princeton University and University of Toronto, can now officially collaborate under the umbrella of the newly launched F4PGA Workgroup.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>CHIPS Alliance Announces Xilinx as its Newest Member</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/news/xilinx-new-member/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/news/xilinx-new-member/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>Xilinx to continue to drive forward open source FPGA innovation&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>SAN FRANCISCO, Feb. 3, 2022&lt;/strong> – CHIPS Alliance, the leading consortium advancing common and open hardware for interfaces, processors and systems, today announced that Xilinx, Inc. (NASDAQ: XLNX) has joined the CHIPS Alliance organization. Xilinx is a leader in adaptive computing, providing highly-flexible programmable silicon, enabled by a suite of advanced software and tools to drive rapid innovation across a wide span of industries and technologies – from consumer to cars to the cloud.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Towards UVM: Using Coroutines for Low-overhead Dynamic Scheduling in Verilator</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/news/towards-uvm-using-coroutines/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/news/towards-uvm-using-coroutines/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>This post was originally published at &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/blog/2021/12/coroutines-for-dynamic-scheduling-in-verilator/">Antmicro&lt;/a>.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Verilator is a popular open source SystemVerilog simulator and one of the key tools in the ASIC and FPGA ecosystem, which Antmicro is actively using and developing, e.g. by &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/blog/2021/09/co-simulation-for-zynq-with-renode-and-verilator/">enabling co-simulation with Renode&lt;/a> or &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/blog/2019/06/verilog-with-cocotb-and-verilator/">Cocotb integration&lt;/a>. It’s also one of the fastest available HDL simulators, including proprietary alternatives. It achieves that speed by generating highly optimized C++ code from a given hardware design. Verilator does a lot of work at compile-time to make the generated (‘verilated’) code extremely fast, such as ordering statements in an optimal way.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>SATA Design Implementation on FPGAs with Open Source Tools</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/news/sata-design-implementation-on-fpgas-with-open-source-tools/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/news/sata-design-implementation-on-fpgas-with-open-source-tools/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>This post was originally published at &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/blog/2021/12/sata-with-open-source-fpga-tools/">Antmicro&lt;/a>.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Real-world FPGAs designs often require high rate transmission protocols such as PCIe, USB and SATA which rely on high speed transceivers for external communication. These protocols are used to interface with various devices such as graphics cards and storage devices, and many of our clients reach out to us specifically because they need the &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/technologies/fpga/">flexibility, high-throughput and low-latency characteristics of FPGAs&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In particular, for customers that deal with high data volumes (which is very common in video applications), implementing SATA to communicate and transfer data with e.g. an SSD hard drive is a must.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Open Source FPGA Platform for Rowhammer Security Testing in the Data Center</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/news/open-source-fpga-platform-for-rowhammer-security-testing-in-the-data-center/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/news/open-source-fpga-platform-for-rowhammer-security-testing-in-the-data-center/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>This post was originally published at &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/blog/2021/12/open-source-data-center-rowhammer-tester/">Antmicro&lt;/a>.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Our work together with Google and the world’s research community on detecting and mitigating the Rowhammer problem in DRAM memories has been proving that the challenge is far from being solved and a lot of systems are still vulnerable.
&lt;a href="https://opensource.googleblog.com/2021/11/Open%20source%20DDR%20controller%20framework%20for%20mitigating%20Rowhammer.html">The DDR Rowhammer testing framework&lt;/a> that we developed together with an open hardware &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/blog/2021/04/lpddr4-test-platform/">LPDDR4 DRAM tester board&lt;/a> has been used to detect new attack methods such as &lt;a href="https://security.googleblog.com/2021/05/introducing-half-double-new-hammering.html">Half-Double&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://thehackernews.com/2021/11/new-blacksmith-exploit-bypasses-current.html">Blacksmith&lt;/a> and all data seems to suggest this more such methods will be discovered with time.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>2021 Annual Report</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/news/2021-annual-report/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/news/2021-annual-report/</guid><description>&lt;p>CHIPS Alliance was founded in March 2019 to design high-quality, open source hardware register transfer level (RTL) and develop open source hardware and software design tools. By creating an open and collaborative environment, companies and organizations can develop innovative, cost effective hardware designs optimized for the requirements of today’s silicon devices and FPGAs.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>CHIPS Alliance was incorporated by four organizations which wanted to make open source silicon a reality. Esperanto, Google, SiFive and Western Digital were the founding members. Now almost two years later, it is fitting to look back at our progress. We are pleased to present this annual report detailing the many things we have accomplished collectively in this fast growing organization.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Software-driven ASIC Prototyping Using the Open Source SkyWater Shuttle</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/news/software-driven-asic-prototyping-using-the-open-source-skywater-shuttle/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/news/software-driven-asic-prototyping-using-the-open-source-skywater-shuttle/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>This post was originally published at &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/blog/2021/12/sw-driven-asics-with-skywater-shuttle/">Antmicro&lt;/a>.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The growing cost and complexity of advanced nodes, supply chain issues and demand for silicon independence mean that the ASIC design process is in need of innovation. Antmicro believes the answer to those challenges is bound to come from the software-driven, open source approach which has shaped the Internet and gave rise to modern cloud computing. Applying the methodologies of software design to ASICs is however notoriously viewed as difficult, given the closed nature of many components needed to build chips – tools, IP and process design kits, or PDKs for short, as well as the slow turnaround of manufacturing.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Open Source Debayerization Blocks in FPGA</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/news/open-source-debayerization-blocks-in-fpga/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/news/open-source-debayerization-blocks-in-fpga/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>This post was originally published at &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/blog/2021/10/debayerization-blocks-in-fpga/">Antmicro&lt;/a>.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/platforms/custom-camera-platforms/">modern digital camera systems&lt;/a>, the captured image undergoes a complex process involving various image signal processing (ISP) techniques to reproduce the observed scene as accurately as possible while preserving bandwidth. On the most basic level, most CCD and CMOS image sensors use the Bayer pattern filter, where 50% of the pixels are green, 25% are red and 25% are blue (corresponding to the increased sensitivity of the human eye to the green color). &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Demosaicing">Demosaicing&lt;/a>, also known as debayering, is an important part of any ISP pipeline whereby an algorithm reconstructs the missing RGB components/channels of each pixel by performing interpolation of the values collected for individual pixels.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How Google is Applying Machine Learning to Macro Placement</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/news/how-google-is-applying-machine-learning-to-macro-placement/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/news/how-google-is-applying-machine-learning-to-macro-placement/</guid><description>&lt;p>CHIPS Alliance’s latest Deep Dive Cafe featured an outstanding talk by a Google physical design engineer, Young-Joon Lee, who has a PhD from Georgia Tech, and has been working on machine learning physical design projects for the past two years.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The chip placement problem is a notoriously challenging design problem, and has been explored in the electronic design automation research and development community for years. For those unfamiliar with the problem, it involves finding the optimal placement of physical cells implementing the logical function on a chip image to minimize performance, power, and area of the silicon, which in the end affects the cost of the product. The effort by Google to apply machine learning to the placement problem started as part of the Google Brain effort, which in part focuses on running algorithms at scale on large amounts of data.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Improving the OpenLane ASIC Build Flow with Open Source SystemVerilog Support</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/news/improving-the-openlane-asic-build-flow-with-open-source-systemverilog-support/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/news/improving-the-openlane-asic-build-flow-with-open-source-systemverilog-support/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>This post was originally published at &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/blog/2021/10/openlane-asic-build-flow-with-systemverliog-support/">Antmicro&lt;/a>.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Open source toolchains are key to building collaborative ecosystems, welcoming to new approaches, opportunistic/focused innovations and niche use cases. The ASIC design domain, especially in the view of the rising tensions around manufacturing and supply chains, are in dire need of a software-driven innovation based on an open source approach. The fledgling open source hardware ecosystem has been energized by the success of RISC-V and is now being vastly expanded to cover the entire ASIC design flow by &lt;a href="https://chipsalliance.org/">CHIPS Alliance&lt;/a>, and Antmicro has been playing a leadership role in both of these organizations as well as offering commercial engineering and support services to assist with early adoption of open source approaches in hardware.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Recap of the Fall 2021 CHIPS Alliance Workshop</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/news/recap-of-the-fall-2021-chips-alliance-workshop-rob-mains-chips-alliance/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/news/recap-of-the-fall-2021-chips-alliance-workshop-rob-mains-chips-alliance/</guid><description>&lt;p>We recently held our fall 2021 CHIPS Alliance workshop with nearly 160 attendees present for informative seminars covering a range of topics including porting Android to RISC-V, open source ASIC design and FPGA tooling, and OmniXtend. In case you missed the talks, a replay is available &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=auXZdPwYs10">on the CHIPS Alliance YouTube channel&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>During the seminar, we had eight exciting technical presentations, including:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="porting-android-chips_alliance-slides-v1.2-Han-Mao.pdf">Porting Android to RISC-V&lt;/a> – Guoyin Chen and Han Mao, Alibaba&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="Practical-Adoption-of-Open-Source-System-Verilog-Tools-CHIPS-Fall-Workshop-Michael-Gielda.pdf">Practical Adoption of Open Source SystemVerilog Tools&lt;/a> – Michael Gielda, Antmicro&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="ChiselTalk_ChipsAlliance_2021_October-Jack-Koenig.pdf">Chisel and FIRRTL for Next-Generation SoC Designs&lt;/a> – Jack Koenig, SiFive&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="OpenFASOC_-Open-Source-Fully-Autonomous-SoC-Synthesis-using-Customizable-Cell-Based-Synthesizable-Analog-Circuits-CHIPS-Alliance-Mehdi-Saligane.pdf">OpenFASOC: Automated Open Source Analog and Mixed-Signals IC Generation&lt;/a> – Mehdi Saligane, University of Michigan (UMICH)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="FPGA-Tooling-Interoperability-with-the-FPGA-Interchange-Format-Maciej-Kurc.pdf">FPGA Tooling Interoperability with the FPGA Interchange Format&lt;/a> – Maciej Kurc, Antmicro&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="OXLPC_ChipsAlliance-Jaco-Hofmann.pdf">OmniXtend: Scalability and LPC&lt;/a> – Jaco Hofmann, Western Digital Corporation&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="Open-Source-NVME-IP-with-AI-Acceleration-Karol-Gugala.pdf">Open Source NVME IP with AI Acceleration&lt;/a> – Anand Kulkarni, Western Digital Corporation and Karol Gugala, Antmicro&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="2021-10-CHIPS_Alliance-Sachin-Sapatnekar.pdf">Automating Analog Layout using ALIGN&lt;/a> – Sachin Sapatnekar, University of Minnesota (UMN)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Each of these talks provided informative, technical details of key aspects of the work underway by members of CHIPS Alliance who are working in an open, collaborative fashion. Of particular interest are the following topic areas:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>CHIPS Alliance Fall Workshop 2021</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/events/fall-workshop-2021/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/events/fall-workshop-2021/</guid><description>&lt;p>Check out the presentations below, and &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=auXZdPwYs10!">watch the replay here&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Porting Android to RISC-V Alibaba – Guoyin Chen and Han Mao, Alibaba (&lt;a href="https://youtu.be/auXZdPwYs10?t=218">replay&lt;/a>)
(&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1bylTKMLdhyLa6hl3LiblnpEewrhITf5S/view?usp=sharing">slides&lt;/a>)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Practical Adoption of Open Source System Verilog Tools – Michael Gielda, Antmicro (&lt;a href="https://youtu.be/auXZdPwYs10?t=1347">replay&lt;/a>)
(&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1Xt0B2OaWsLSNc1FFc4hjKD0CC7EdMWDH/view?usp=sharing">slides&lt;/a>)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Chisel and FIRRTL for Next-Generation SoC Designs– Jack Koenig, SiFive (&lt;a href="https://youtu.be/auXZdPwYs10?t=2958">replay&lt;/a>)
(&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1hH6YBvsmxBHfYYIAuSFS8Zq_96niMoWi/view?usp=sharing">slides&lt;/a>)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>OpenFASOC: Automated Open Source Analog and Mixed-Signals IC Generation – Mehdi Saligane, University of Michigan (UMICH) (&lt;a href="https://youtu.be/auXZdPwYs10?t=4326">replay&lt;/a>)
(&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1NqEDuhuLWpJs89hqKgi2x3FQpE7fQBzO/view?usp=sharing">slides&lt;/a>)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>FPGA Tooling Interoperability with the FPGA Interchange Format – Maciej Kurc, Antmicro (&lt;a href="https://youtu.be/auXZdPwYs10?t=6183">replay&lt;/a>)
(&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1_R_HLLOSQOoAnO5p3G9782xjhbVxXFdI/view?usp=sharing">slides&lt;/a>)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>OmniXtend: Scalability and LPC – Jaco Hofmann, Western Digital Corporation (&lt;a href="https://youtu.be/auXZdPwYs10?t=7671">replay&lt;/a>)
(&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1vhXgUs4z66dqUVYg24Duk_vLLIiWl3JY/view?usp=sharing">slides&lt;/a>)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Open Source NVME IP with AI Acceleration – Anand Kulkarni, Western Digital Corporation and Karol Gugala, Antmicro (&lt;a href="https://youtu.be/auXZdPwYs10?t=8693">replay&lt;/a>)
(&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1ipk2Oq5-ykehjbD9TKz0bBBtmNozR5B3/view?usp=sharing">slides&lt;/a>)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Automating Analog Layout using ALIGN – Sachin Sapatnekar, University of Minnesota (UMN) (&lt;a href="https://youtu.be/auXZdPwYs10?t=10073">replay&lt;/a>)
(&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1NqEDuhuLWpJs89hqKgi2x3FQpE7fQBzO/view?usp=sharing">slides&lt;/a>)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=auXZdPwYs10">Watch the Replay&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Open Source DDR Controller Framework for Mitigating Rowhammer</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/news/open-source-ddr-controller-framework-for-mitigating-rowhammer/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/news/open-source-ddr-controller-framework-for-mitigating-rowhammer/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>This post was originally published at &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/blog/2021/08/open-source-ddr-test-framework-for-rowhammer/">Antmicro&lt;/a>.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Row_hammer">Rowhammer&lt;/a> is a hardware vulnerability that affects DRAM memory chips and can be exploited to modify memory contents, potentially providing root access to the system. It occurs because Dynamic RAM consists of multiple memory cells packed tightly together and specific access patterns can cause unwanted effects that propagate to nearby memory cells and cause bit-flips in cells which have not been accessed by the attacker.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Listen to CHIPS Alliance’s Rob Mains on EE Journal’s FishFry Podcast</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/news/listen-to-chips-alliances-rob-mains-on-ee-journals-fishfry-podcast/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/news/listen-to-chips-alliances-rob-mains-on-ee-journals-fishfry-podcast/</guid><description>&lt;p>CHIPS Alliance’s general manager Rob Mains joined Amelia Dalton at EE Journal’s FishFry podcast for a lively discussion about how we’re working to make chip design more accessible. Rob discussed CHIPS Alliance’s work with RISC-V International to develop a new &lt;a href="https://chipsalliance.org/announcement/2021/03/24/risc-v-international-omnixtend-working-group/">unified memory standard&lt;/a>, along with our work to accelerate the design of open source chipsets with the &lt;a href="https://chipsalliance.org/announcement/2020/07/16/aib-2-0-draft-specification/">AIB 2.0 specification&lt;/a>. The conversation also touched on our efforts to provide better support for SystemVerilog using open source tools and to create a dynamic stratified scheduler implementation in Verilator.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>SkyWater Technology Joins CHIPS Alliance to Further Efforts to Make Chip Design and Production More Accessible</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/news/skywater-technology-joins-chips-alliance-to-further-efforts-to-make-chip-design-and-production-more-accessible/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/news/skywater-technology-joins-chips-alliance-to-further-efforts-to-make-chip-design-and-production-more-accessible/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>SkyWater furthers collaboration with CHIPS Alliance members on open source shuttle projects&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>SAN FRANCISCO, Sept. 16, 2021&lt;/strong> – CHIPS Alliance, the leading consortium advancing common and open hardware for interfaces, processors and systems, today announced that &lt;a href="https://www.skywatertechnology.com/">SkyWater Technology&lt;/a> (NASDAQ: SKYT) has become a member of the organization. SkyWater provides custom development, volume manufacturing and advanced packaging services for a wide range of silicon, including solutions based on the free and open RISC-V instruction set architecture (ISA).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>SymbiFlow FPGA Interchange Format to Enable Interoperable FPGA Tooling</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/news/symbiflow-fpga-interchange-format-to-enable-interoperable-fpga-tooling/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/news/symbiflow-fpga-interchange-format-to-enable-interoperable-fpga-tooling/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>This post was originally published at &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/blog/2021/09/symbiflow-fpga-interchange-format/">Antmicro&lt;/a>.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/technologies/fpga/">Field Programmable Gate Arrays (FPGAs)&lt;/a> have been around for several decades, but historically development of toolchains targeting specific platforms was done in separate ecosystems and driven by the vendors themselves. Only in recent years, the development of vendor-neutral open source toolchains has revealed the need of having an abstraction layer to describe and define an FPGA architecture through a standard format.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>FPGA toolchains are not trivial as they comprise several elements which themselves can be quite complex: roughly speaking, you can divide the process of “compiling” FPGA-targeted code in a Hardware Description Language (HDL) into three stages: synthesis, place and route, bitstream generation. A standard format could provide a common description of the various architectures and serve as a bridge between the multitude of open source and closed proprietary tools that deal with the entire process or parts thereof, including the open source Yosys for synthesis and VtR and nextpnr for place and route, to relevant vendor tooling from Xilinx, Intel, Lattice, QuickLogic, etc.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Automatic SystemVerilog Linting in GitHub Actions with Verible</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/news/automatic-systemverilog-linting-in-github-actions-with-verible/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/news/automatic-systemverilog-linting-in-github-actions-with-verible/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>This post was originally published at &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/blog/2021/08/verible-integration-with-github-actions/">Antmicro&lt;/a>.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>With the recent advances in open source &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/blog/2021/07/open-source-systemverilog-tools-in-asic-design/">ASIC development tools&lt;/a> such as Verible, it has become easier to automate tasks and boost developer productivity. The Verible linter is a static code analysis tool that has been helping us and our collaborators to spot and fix stylistic errors and bugs in SystemVerilog code.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="cicd-for-smaller-backlog-and-better-test-reliability">CI/CD for smaller backlog and better test reliability&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>As part of our work within the newly established CHIPS Alliance SystemVerilog subgroup, Antmicro has made further steps to facilitate SystemVerilog workflows with Verible, by providing an easy to use &lt;a href="https://github.com/chipsalliance/verible-linter-action">Verible Linter GitHub Action&lt;/a>. Combined with another open source tool called &lt;a href="https://github.com/reviewdog/reviewdog">Reviewdog&lt;/a>, the action allows you to easily perform automatic code style checks and code review.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Open Source Custom GitHub Actions Runners with Google Cloud and Terraform</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/news/open-source-custom-github-actions-runners-with-google-cloud-and-terraform/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/news/open-source-custom-github-actions-runners-with-google-cloud-and-terraform/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>This post was originally published at &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/blog/2021/08/open-source-github-actions-runners-with-gcp-and-terraform/">Antmicro&lt;/a>.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In order to fulfill our internal and our customers’ needs, we have developed and successfully deployed an &lt;a href="https://github.com/antmicro/runner">open source custom GitHub Actions runner&lt;/a> that allows us to mix the GitHub default and your custom hardware and software. The runner software itself operates within a Google Cloud Platform project, spawns &lt;a href="https://cloud.google.com/compute/docs/instances">Compute Engine instances&lt;/a> and orchestrates the build, providing a number of interesting advantages that were needed in our ASIC and FPGA-related work. As is typical for us, we have released all the necessary components as open source – read on to learn how the solution works, the benefits it offers and how to build and deploy this software in your organization (which we can also help with as part of our commercial support and engineering services).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Open Source SystemVerilog Tools in ASIC Design</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/news/open-source-systemverilog-tools-in-asic-design/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/news/open-source-systemverilog-tools-in-asic-design/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>This post was originally published at &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/blog/2021/07/open-source-systemverilog-tools-in-asic-design/">Antmicro&lt;/a>.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Open source hardware is undeniably undergoing a renaissance whose origin can be traced to the establishment of RISC-V Foundation (later redubbed RISC-V International). The open ISA and ecosystem, in which Antmicro participated since the beginning as a Founding member, has sparked many open source CPU implementations but also new tooling, methodologies and trends which allow for more collaborative and software driven design.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Many of those broader open hardware activities have been finding a home in &lt;a href="https://chipsalliance.org/">CHIPS Alliance&lt;/a>, an open source organization we participate in as a Platinum member alongside Google, Intel, Western Digital, SiFive and others, whose goals explicitly encompass:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Advanced Co-simulation with Renode and Verilator: PolarFire SoC and FastVDMA</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/news/renode-and-verilator-polarfire-soc-and-fastvdma/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/news/renode-and-verilator-polarfire-soc-and-fastvdma/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>This post was originally published at &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/blog/2021/06/advanced-co-simulation-with-renode-and-verilator/">Antmicro&lt;/a>.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/blog/2019/09/renode-verilator-hdl-co-simulation/">Co-simulating HDL has been possible in Renode since the 1.7.1 release&lt;/a>, but the functionality – critical for hardware/software co-development as well as FPGA use cases – is constantly evolving based on the needs of our customers like Google and Microchip as well as our work in open source groups including &lt;a href="https://chipsalliance.org/">CHIPS Alliance&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://riscv.org/">RISC-V International&lt;/a>. To quickly recap, by co-simulation we mean a scenario where a part of the system is simulated in Renode but some specific peripheral or subsystem is simulated directly from HDL, e.g. Verilog. To achieve this, Renode integrates with Verilator, a fast and popular open source HDL simulator, which we are helping our customers adopt as well as expanding its capabilities to cover new use cases. Peripherals simulated directly from HDL are typically called Verilated peripherals.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Progress on Building Open Source Infrastructure for System Verilog</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/news/open-source-infrastructure-for-system-verilog/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/news/open-source-infrastructure-for-system-verilog/</guid><description>&lt;p>SystemVerilog is a rich hardware design description and verification language that is seeing increased usage in industry. In the second Deep Dive Cafe Talk by CHIPS Alliance on July 20, Henner Zeller, who is an software developer with Google, provided an excellent in depth technical talk on building out an open source tooling ecosystem around SystemVerilog to provide a common framework that can be used by both functional simulation applications as well as logic synthesis. In case you missed the live presentation, you can watch it &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/xLxNHBzmGiI">here&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>What You Need to Know About Verilator Open Source Tooling</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/news/what-you-need-to-know-about-verilator-open-source-tooling/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/news/what-you-need-to-know-about-verilator-open-source-tooling/</guid><description>&lt;p>Verilator is a high performance, open source functional simulator that has gained tremendous popularity in its usage and adoption in the verification of chip design. The ASIC development community has widely embraced Verilator as an effective, often even superior alternative to proprietary solutions, and it is now the standard approach in RISC-V CPU design as the community has worked to provide Verilator simulation capabilities out of the box. CHIPS Alliance and RISC-V leaders Antmicro and Western Digital have been collaborating to make Verilator even more useful for ASIC design purposes, working towards supporting industry-standard verification methods in a completely open source flow.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Efabless Launches chipIgnite with SkyWater to Bring Chip Creation to the Masses</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/news/efabless-launches-chipignite/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/news/efabless-launches-chipignite/</guid><description>&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Program includes a pre-designed carrier chip and automated open source design flow from Efabless&lt;/li>
&lt;li>SkyWater’s open source SKY130 process is the first node to be used to fabricate chips for the program&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Initiative removes access barriers by significantly reducing cost and the need for deep semiconductor experience to design chips&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.globenewswire.com/Tracker?data=_QfpiutgK9BkRkwqOZ_QgaW-wScChSfzrLoisG3jrx29CaZIKTRoBuySTDuHXJZP0EbK1_N1KyzIRCW2sFc5NA==">Efabless&lt;/a>, a community chip creation platform, today announced the launch of its new chipIgnite program to bring chip design and fabrication to the masses and a collaboration with &lt;a href="https://www.globenewswire.com/Tracker?data=P477GUgP-WxQLcA8zmSX8V24RDJ0fqqGp8teNuFfFkL7nLvoEPgkh9Uyo0a6ZDG-JNw_Hz99p5lNq7zs7gL_EsV6v-ZGI8zuNwlyMu1wbZ4=">SkyWater Technology&lt;/a> for the first node supported in the program. The chipIgnite program expands upon the SKY130-based open source chip manufacturing program sponsored by Google and supports private commercial designs that include non-open source IP. This initiative represents another step forward in the industry to broaden access to chip design by giving people the ability to more easily create and fabricate chips.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Antmicro’s ARVSOM RISC-V Module Announced</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/news/antmicros-arvsom-risc-v-module-announced/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/news/antmicros-arvsom-risc-v-module-announced/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>This post was originally published at &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/blog/2021/04/arv-som-announcement/">Antmicro&lt;/a>.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We are excited to announce the ARVSOM – Antmicro’s &lt;a href="https://github.com/antmicro/arvsom">fully open source&lt;/a>, RISC-V-based system-on-module featuring the StarFive 71×0 SoC. Using the RISC-V architecture, which Antmicro has been heavily involved in since the early days as a Founding Member of RISC-V International, the SoM is going to enable unprecedented openness, reusability and functionality across different verticals.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We are excited to announce the ARVSOM – Antmicro’s &lt;a href="https://github.com/antmicro/arvsom">fully open source&lt;/a>, RISC-V-based system-on-module featuring the StarFive 71×0 SoC. Using the RISC-V architecture, which Antmicro has been heavily involved in since the early days as a Founding Member of RISC-V International, the SoM is going to enable unprecedented openness, reusability and functionality across different verticals.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Dynamic Scheduling in Verilator – Milestone Towards Open Source UVM</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/news/dynamic-scheduling-in-verilator/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/news/dynamic-scheduling-in-verilator/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>This post was originally published at &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/blog/2021/05/dynamic-scheduling-in-verilator/">Antmicro&lt;/a>.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>UVM is a verification methodology traditionally used in chip design which has historically been missing from the open source landscape of verification-focused tooling. While new, open source approaches to verification have emerged that include the excellent Python-based Cocotb (that &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/blog/2019/12/testing-usb-cores-with-python-and-cocotb/">we also use&lt;/a> &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/blog/2019/06/verilog-with-cocotb-and-verilator/">and support&lt;/a>) maintained by &lt;a href="https://www.fossi-foundation.org/">FOSSi Foundation&lt;/a>, not everyone can easily adopt it, especially in long-running projects and existing codebases that use a different verification approach. Leading the efforts towards comprehensive UVM / SystemVerilog support in open source tools, we have been gradually completing milestones, getting closer to what will essentially be a modular, collaboration-driven chips design methodology/workflow. Some examples of our activity in this space include &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/blog/2020/12/ibex-support-in-verilator-yosys-via-uhdm-surelog/">enabling open source synthesis and simulation of the Ibex CPU&lt;/a> in &lt;a href="https://github.com/antmicro/verilator/tree/uhdm-verilator">Verilator&lt;/a>/&lt;a href="https://github.com/antmicro/yosys/tree/uhdm-yosys">Yosys&lt;/a> via UHDM/Surelog, and the most recent joint project with Western Digital in which we have developed &lt;a href="https://github.com/antmicro/verilator-dynamic-scheduler-examples">dynamic scheduling in Verilator&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>New MPW-TWO Program Will Provide Fabrication For Fully Open Source Projects</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/news/new-mpw-two-program/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/news/new-mpw-two-program/</guid><description>&lt;p>CHIPS Alliance is excited to announce that the hardware development community can submit their open source design projects to Efabless.com for space on their forthcoming shuttle. This opportunity comes after the success of having 40 submissions for the MPW-ONE shuttle; 60% of those designs were submitted by first-time ASIC designers. &lt;a href="https://efabless.com/open_shuttle_program/2">MPW-TWO&lt;/a> is the second Open MPW Shuttle providing fabrication for fully open-source projects using the SkyWater Open Source PDK announced by Google and SkyWater.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Modular, Open-source FPGA-based LPDDR4 Test Platform</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/news/modular-open-source-fpga-based-lpddr4-test-platform/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/news/modular-open-source-fpga-based-lpddr4-test-platform/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>This post was originally published at &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/blog/2021/04/lpddr4-test-platform/">Antmicro&lt;/a>.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The flexibility of FPGAs makes them an excellent choice not only for parallel processing applications but also for research and experimentation in a range of technological areas.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We often provide our customers with flexible R&amp;amp;D platforms that can be easily adapted to changing requirements and new use cases as a result of our practice of using open source hardware, software, FPGA IP and tooling.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>CHIPS Alliance Spring Workshop 2021</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/events/spring-workshop-2021/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/events/spring-workshop-2021/</guid><description>&lt;p>Check out the presentations below, and &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/bLfBFpACh2s">watch the replay here&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Chipyard - Bora Nikolic, UC Berkeley (&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1-Ceb2yWoaUgZqq7RHeuTiudmyWZ5U-VC/view?usp=sharing">slides&lt;/a>)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>RISC-V DV Workgroup Updates Tao Liu / Matt Cockrell, Google (&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1-pOrlH0ctzATL6Bxcu8sRoAZPb_niJqb/view?usp=sharing">slides&lt;/a>)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Open Source Flows in ASIC &amp;amp; FPGA Development Michael Gielda, Antmicro&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Open-Source AIB Chiplet Ecosystem David Kehlet, Intel (&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1-QeaTxGHASYtOCwgEvWoZAmP4plWSois/view?usp=sharing">slides&lt;/a>)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>OmniXtend Milestone Updates Dejan Vucinic, Western Digital (&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1-TWL4dUQQUvghb_NfzDK2QGNKue2_XnO/view?usp=sharing">slides&lt;/a>)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Chisel advances for next-gen SOC Designs Jack Koenig, SiFive (&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1-UV8gtlKfkGnDRArE7zezl89q4ZotUUz/view?usp=sharing">slides&lt;/a>)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Codasip SweRV Core Support Package in a Nutshell Zdenek Prikyl, Codasip (&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1-bz1cOamEru2oo_So2G7vQc6ixRelr52/view?usp=sharing">slides&lt;/a>)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>An Introduction to the OpenROAD project Andrew Kahng / Tom Spyrou, OpenROAD (&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1-daHmgNlC6yTFztQ7O3eWDJ7lDRdE1gU/view?usp=sharing">slides&lt;/a>)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Open Source FPGA Tooling Brian Faith, Quicklogic (&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1-Bt6-720HuOQpw-zZoedQSGkV9msMifw/view?usp=sharing">slides&lt;/a>)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fully Open Silicon Down to the Transistor Tim Ansell, Google (&lt;a href="https://j.mp/ca21-sky130">slides&lt;/a>)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://youtu.be/bLfBFpACh2s">Watch the Replay&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>CHIPS Alliance and RISC-V International Invite the RISC-V Community to Participate in Updating a New Unified Memory Architecture Standard</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/news/risc-v-international-omnixtend-working-group/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/news/risc-v-international-omnixtend-working-group/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>New joint working group will enhance the OmniXtend Cache Coherency architecture&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>SAN FRANCISCO, March 24, 2020&lt;/strong> – &lt;a href="https://riscv.org/">RISC-V International&lt;/a>, a non-profit corporation controlled by its members to drive the adoption and implementation of the free and open RISC-V instruction set architecture (ISA), and &lt;a href="https://chipsalliance.org/">CHIPS Alliance&lt;/a>, the leading consortium advancing common and open hardware for interfaces, processors and systems, today announced a joint collaboration to update the OmniXtend Cache Coherency specification and protocol, along with building out developer tools for OmniXtend.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>GitHub Actions Self-hosted Runners, Build Event Server and Google Cloud</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/news/github-actions-self-hosted-runners-build-event-server-and-google-cloud/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/news/github-actions-self-hosted-runners-build-event-server-and-google-cloud/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>This post was originally published at &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/blog/2021/03/github-actions-self-hosted-runners/">Antmicro&lt;/a>.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Continuous Integration and smart lifecycle management are key for high-tech product development, which is often a complex and multi-faceted process that requires automation to be efficient and failure-proof. At Antmicro, we’ve been creating various open source cloud and hybrid cloud solutions for our customers, helping them to encapsulate the complexity of their software stack. Lots of those projects cross the hardware/software boundary and involve a mix of open source and proprietary code, which means that fine-grained control of the CI setups are needed to make them work.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Goings-on in the FuseSoC Project and Other Open Source Silicon Related News</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/news/goings-on-in-the-fusesoc-project-and-other-open-source-silicon-related-news/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/news/goings-on-in-the-fusesoc-project-and-other-open-source-silicon-related-news/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>This post was originally published by &lt;a href="https://olofkindgren.blogspot.com/2021/02/fossi-fever-2020.html">Olof Kindgren&lt;/a>&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="fossi-fever-2020">FOSSi Fever 2020&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="fuckload.png" alt="">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2020 was a year with a lot of bad news and so it feels slightly strange to cheerfully write about a very specific topic in the light of this. But there will always be good and bad things happening in the world. So let’s keep fighting the bad things and for now take look at what happened last year within the amazing world of open source silicon. I will start by mentioning the most significant, but by no means the only, milestones for the FOSSi movement as a whole and then take a more personal look at the work where I have been directly involved.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>CHIPS Alliance Welcomes Antmicro and VeriSilicon to the Platinum Membership Level</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/news/chips-alliance-welcomes-antmicro-and-verisilicon-to-the-platinum-membership-level/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/news/chips-alliance-welcomes-antmicro-and-verisilicon-to-the-platinum-membership-level/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>CHIPS Alliance continues to grow with more than 25 companies collaborating on open source hardware and software technologies&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>SAN FRANCISCO, Feb. 11, 2021&lt;/strong> – CHIPS Alliance, the leading consortium advancing common and open hardware for interfaces, processors and systems, today welcomed Antmicro and VeriSilicon to the company’s Platinum membership level. Antmicro, one of the initial members of the CHIPS Alliance, has upgraded to the Platinum membership level to reflect its deepening involvement in the organization. VeriSilicon is new to the CHIPS Alliance, although the company is heavily involved in open source activities.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>High-Throughput Open Source PCIe on Xilinx VU19P-Based ASIC Prototyping Platform</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/news/high-throughput-open-source-pcie/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/news/high-throughput-open-source-pcie/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>This post was originally published at &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/blog/2021/02/high-throughput-open-source-pcie-on-xilinx-vu19/">Antmicro&lt;/a>.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In our daily work at Antmicro we use FPGAs primarily for their flexibility and parallel data processing capabilities that make them remarkably effective in advanced vision and audio processing systems involving high-speed interfaces such as PCI Express, USB, Ethernet, HDMI, SDI etc. that we develop and integrate as open source, portable building blocks. Many of our customers, however, use FPGAs also in a different context, namely for designing ASICs, which is a highly specialized market that typically involves large FPGAs, proprietary flows and IP. In one such project, we were working with one of the largest FPGAs in production today, the 9-million LUT Xilinx VU19. Being a design with considerable complexity, it needed a high-throughput link between the FPGA and the host PC that could be thoroughly benchmarked, analyzed and optimized for the use case.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>CHIPS Alliance Brings on Rob Mains as New Executive Director</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/news/chips-alliance-brings-on-rob-mains-as-new-executive-director/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/news/chips-alliance-brings-on-rob-mains-as-new-executive-director/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>Industry veteran to lead open hardware consortium democratizing silicon innovation&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>SAN FRANCISCO, Feb. 8, 2021&lt;/strong> – CHIPS Alliance, the leading consortium advancing common and open hardware for interfaces, processors and systems, today announced the appointment of Rob Mains as the organization’s new executive director.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Rob has over 35 years of experience in software engineering and development, with 25 years of experience as an EDA software architect focused on microprocessor design and advanced process node technologies. He most recently served as a technology advisor at Spillbox, and prior to that worked in leadership and senior engineering roles at Qualcomm, Sun Microsystems (staying on at Oracle after the acquisition) and IBM. Throughout his career, Rob has worked closely with hardware developers to play a hands-on role in helping to devise innovative solutions for a wide range of applications.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Enabling Open Source Ibex Synthesis and Simulation in Verilator/Yosys via UHDM/Surelog</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/news/ibex-synthesis-and-simulation/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/news/ibex-synthesis-and-simulation/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>This post was originally published at &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/blog/2020/12/ibex-support-in-verilator-yosys-via-uhdm-surelog/">Antmicro&lt;/a>.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Throughout 2020 we were hard at work developing proper, portable SystemVerilog support for multiple open-source FPGA and ASIC design tools used by us and our customers, most notably &lt;a href="https://github.com/YosysHQ/yosys">Yosys&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://github.com/verilator/verilator">Verilator&lt;/a>. We strongly believe that the support is a necessary step in building a collaborative ecosystem and scalable and reproducible CIs, especially publicly accessible ones that are common in multi-organization projects such as &lt;a href="https://opentitan.org/">OpenTitan&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://chipsalliance.org/">CHIPS Alliance&lt;/a>. Leading the efforts towards achieving this goal, we’ve been developing a fully open source SystemVerilog parsing flow for Yosys and Verilator using UHDM and Surelog, achieving an important milestone: being able to fully parse, synthesize and simulate OpenTitan’s Ibex core directly from the SystemVerilog source.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>2020 Annual Report</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/news/2020-annual-report/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/news/2020-annual-report/</guid><description>&lt;p>CHIPS Alliance was founded in March 2019 to design high-quality, open source hardware register transfer level (RTL) and develop open source hardware and software design tools. By creating an open and collaborative environment, companies and organizations can develop innovative, cost effective hardware designs optimized for the requirements of today’s silicon devices and FPGAs.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>CHIPS Alliance was incorporated by four organizations which wanted to make open source silicon a reality. Esperanto, Google, SiFive and Western Digital were the founding members. Now that one year has passed since the organization’s founding, it is fitting to look back at our progress so far. We are pleased to present this annual report detailing the many things we have accomplished collectively in this fast growing organization.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Efabless Joins CHIPS Alliance to Accelerate the Growth of the Open Source Chip Ecosystem</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/news/efabless-joins-chips-alliance-to-accelerate-the-growth-of-the-open-source-chip-ecosystem/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/news/efabless-joins-chips-alliance-to-accelerate-the-growth-of-the-open-source-chip-ecosystem/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>Efabless to give a talk on the OpenROAD project at the CHIPS Alliance Workshop on Sept. 17&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>SAN FRANCISCO, Sept. 15, 2020&lt;/strong> – CHIPS Alliance, the leading consortium advancing common and open hardware for interfaces, processors and systems, today welcomed Efabless, a crowdsourcing design platform for custom silicon, as its latest member. Efabless is already an active participant in several open source initiatives that the CHIPS Alliance is involved in, including the OpenROAD project and the Open Source Shuttle Program.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>CHIPS Alliance to Collaborate with RISC-V to Standardize an Open Unified Memory Leveraging OmniXtend</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/news/omnixtend/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/news/omnixtend/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>CHIPS Alliance to highlight OmniXtend advances at RISC-V Summit&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>SAN FRANCISCO, Dec. 8, 2020&lt;/strong> – CHIPS Alliance, the leading consortium advancing common and open hardware for interfaces, processors and systems, today announced that the organization will highlight OmniXtend advances in a presentation at the &lt;a href="https://tmt.knect365.com/risc-v-summit/">RISC-V Summit&lt;/a>, taking place virtually from Dec. 8-10, 2020. The CHIPS Alliance plans to work with RISC-V International to standardize an open unified memory coherency bus leveraging OmniXtend to foster innovation for data-centric applications.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The CHIPS Alliance Workshop: 10 Talks From Industry Leaders, All For Free</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/news/the-chips-alliance-workshop-overview/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/news/the-chips-alliance-workshop-overview/</guid><description>&lt;p>Mark your calendars! The &lt;a href="https://events.linuxfoundation.org/chips-alliance-workshop/">CHIPS Alliance Workshop&lt;/a> is coming up on Thursday, Sept. 17 from 11 a.m. to 2 p.m. PT. This free, virtual event will feature talks from industry leaders including Antmicro, Efabless, Google, Intel, Mentor, Metrics, OpenROAD, QuickLogic, SiFive, UC Berkeley and Western Digital.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The CHIPS Alliance Workshop will fit 10 sessions into three hours for a jam-packed event covering a range of interesting topics in the open source community. You’ll hear about open source ASICs, chiplets, FPGAs and SoCs, in addition to open source design verification, FPGA tooling, machine learning accelerators and more. Read on for additional details, and make sure to &lt;a href="https://events.linuxfoundation.org/chips-alliance-workshop/register/">register&lt;/a> before it’s too late.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>CHIPS Alliance Welcomes Mentor as its Newest Member</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/news/chips-alliance-welcomes-mentor-as-its-newest-member/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/news/chips-alliance-welcomes-mentor-as-its-newest-member/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>Mentor to present at the virtual CHIPS Alliance Workshop on Sept. 17&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>SAN FRANCISCO, Aug. 18, 2020&lt;/strong> – CHIPS Alliance, the leading consortium advancing common and open hardware for interfaces, processors and systems, today announced that Mentor, a Siemens business, has joined as its newest member. The CHIPS Alliance has a roster of more than 20 members collaborating to accelerate the creation and deployment of open system-on-chips (SoCs), peripherals and software tools for a wide range of applications.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>QuickLogic Joins CHIPS Alliance to Expand Open Source FPGA Efforts</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/news/quicklogic-joins-chips-alliance-to-expand-open-source-fpga-efforts/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/news/quicklogic-joins-chips-alliance-to-expand-open-source-fpga-efforts/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>QuickLogic to present at the virtual CHIPS Alliance Workshop on Sept. 17&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>SAN FRANCISCO, Aug. 11, 2020&lt;/strong> – CHIPS Alliance, the leading consortium advancing common and open hardware for interfaces, processors and systems, today announced that QuickLogic Corporation (NASDAQ: QUIK), a developer of ultra-low power multi-core voice-enabled SoCs, embedded FPGA IP, and Endpoint AI solutions, has joined as its newest member.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>“Over the past few years the electronics industry has seen a big shift towards open source hardware and software, and we’re proud to be one of the companies at the forefront of that movement,” said Brian Faith, president and CEO at QuickLogic. “We have already been working closely with several CHIPS Alliance members to make FPGA tools and devices more accessible, and we look forward to continuing these efforts as an official member of the organization.”&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>CHIPS Alliance Announces AIB 2.0 Draft Specification to Accelerate Design of Open Source Chiplets</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/news/aib-2-0-draft-specification/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/news/aib-2-0-draft-specification/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>AIB reduces design barriers, costs, and leverages generators to ease development of chiplet-based designs&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>SAN FRANCISCO, July 16, 2020&lt;/strong> – CHIPS Alliance, the leading consortium advancing common and open hardware for interfaces, processors and systems, today announced that it has released the Advanced Interface Bus (AIB) version 2.0 draft specification on &lt;a href="https://github.com/chipsalliance/AIB-specification">GitHub&lt;/a>. The AIB standard is an open-source, royalty-free PHY-level standard for connecting multiple semiconductor die within the same package. AIB is ideal for designing SoCs, FPGAs, SerDes chiplets, high-performance ADC/DAC chiplets, optical networking chiplets and more.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>CHIPS SweRV Cores and the Open Tools Ecosystem</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/news/chips-swerv-cores-and-the-open-tools-ecosystem/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/news/chips-swerv-cores-and-the-open-tools-ecosystem/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>This post was originally published at &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/blog/2020/07/swerv-cores-tools-ecosystem/">Antmicro&lt;/a>.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Antmicro’s open source work spans all parts of the computing stack, from software and AI, to PCBs, FPGAs and, most recently, custom silicon. We connect those areas with an overarching vision of open source tooling and methodology, and a software-driven approach that allows us to move fast and build future-centric solutions. Our partners and customers, many of whom work with us also in the context of organizations such as &lt;a href="https://chipsalliance.org/">CHIPS Alliance&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://riscv.org/">RISC-V&lt;/a>, share our approach to developing open systems. We were recently very happy to be invited to give a talk at the &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ODU1b9amCG8&amp;amp;feature=emb_title">“Production grade, open RISC-V SweRV Core Solutions in CHIPS Alliance”&lt;/a> meetup organized by Western Digital where we presented our systems approach on the example of the open source tools ecosystem that targets their SweRV cores and which we are helping to develop.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Open Source Process Design Kit from Google, SkyWater Technologies and Partners Released</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/news/open-source-process-design-kit-from-google-skywater-technologies-and-partners-released/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/news/open-source-process-design-kit-from-google-skywater-technologies-and-partners-released/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>This post was originally published at &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/blog/2020/06/skywater-open-source-pdk/">Antmicro&lt;/a>.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The ASIC design and manufacturing flow has for a long time been dominated by proprietary tools and processes. The growing complexity of chip-building has been reinforcing the claim that “hardware is too hard to be open source”, as the cost and time needed to build an ASIC have kept small, more agile, software-oriented teams and individuals away from the hardware domain. Thus, ASICs have not been able to benefit from the enthusiasm and collaboration which have been fuelling software development for decades now. Thanks to the continued effort of many entities which Antmicro is very proud to be among, this is now changing quickly.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Semiconductor Engineering: About The SweRV Core EH2</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/news/semiconductor-engineering-swerv-core-eh2/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/news/semiconductor-engineering-swerv-core-eh2/</guid><description>&lt;p>In mid-May, CHIPS Alliance announced the open sourcing of the SweRV Core EH2 and SweRV Core EL2 designed by &lt;a href="https://www.westerndigital.com/company/innovations/risc-v">Western Digital&lt;/a>. These cores, as well as the earlier EH1, are now supported by Codasip’s SweRV Core Support Package which provides all of the components necessary to design, implement, test, and write software for a SweRV Core-based system-on-chip. But what is SweRV Core EH2?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The SweRV Core EH1 was the first to be released through CHIPS Alliance and was a core aimed at high-end embedded applications including Western Digital’s flash controllers and SSDs. The core is a dual issue, superscalar, high-performance core with 9 pipeline stages. The EH2 is an exciting further development aimed at delivering even more performance for IoT, artificial intelligence and data-intensive embedded applications.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>QuickLogic Announces Open Reconfigurable Computing Initiative</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/news/quicklogic-announces-open-reconfigurable-computing-initiative/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/news/quicklogic-announces-open-reconfigurable-computing-initiative/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>&lt;a href="https://ir.quicklogic.com/press-releases/detail/535/quicklogic-announces-open-reconfigurable-computing">Originally issued&lt;/a> by QuickLogic, the following press release announces the QORC initiative including the world’s first vendor-supported open FPGA toolchain using SymbiFlow, and describes the contribution of CHIPS Alliance members Antmicro and Google.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>QuickLogic Open Reconfigurable Computing (QORC) initiative, developed by Antmicro in collaboration with QuickLogic and Google, broadens access to company’s FPGA technology and eFPGA IP for all embedded systems developers&lt;/li>
&lt;li>First Programmable Logic Company to Embrace Open Source FPGA Development Tools&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>San Jose, CA&lt;/strong> – June 16, 2020 – QuickLogic Corporation (NASDAQ: QUIK), a developer of ultra-low power multi-core voice-enabled SoCs, embedded FPGA IP, and Endpoint AI solutions, today announced its ground breaking QORC (QuickLogic Open Reconfigurable Computing) initiative, making it the first programmable logic vendor to actively embrace a fully open source suite of development tools for its FPGA devices and eFPGA technology. This initiative engenders the emerging trend toward open source tooling, significantly broadens access to the company’s products, and enables both hardware and software developers with tools supported by both the user community and QuickLogic.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>A Look Back at the CHIPS Alliance’s Incredible Growth</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/news/chips-alliances-incredible-growth/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/news/chips-alliances-incredible-growth/</guid><description>&lt;p>It’s been just over a year since the CHIPS Alliance was founded with the mission of making open source hardware development more accessible to companies, universities and individuals. We’re working to bring the dynamics of the hugely successful open source software development model into ASIC design, building on the groundwork set by the RISC-V community. Progress over the past year is detailed in our &lt;a href="https://chipsalliance.org/chips-alliance-2020-annual-report/">Annual Report&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>CHIPS Alliance is focused on expanding on this open hardware vision by:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>CHIPS Alliance’s Newly Enhanced SweRV Cores Available to All for Free</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/news/newly-enhanced-swerv-cores/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/news/newly-enhanced-swerv-cores/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>CHIPS Alliance to host online event to help community innovating with SweRV Core EH2 and EL2 Solutions&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>SAN FRANCISCO, May 14, 2020&lt;/strong> – CHIPS Alliance, the leading consortium advancing common and open hardware for interfaces, processors and systems, today announced new enhancements to the SweRV Core™ EH2 and SweRV Core EL2, &lt;a href="https://www.westerndigital.com/company/newsroom/press-releases/2019/2019-12-10-western-digital-brings-memory-closer-to-compute-with-new-risc-v-innovations">developed&lt;/a> for the open-source community by Western Digital. Since the introduction of the cores earlier this year, the CHIPS Alliance has worked with its community to exhaustedly validate the cores through a transparent and rigorous process, as well as incorporate a variety of new updates.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>SystemVerilog Linting and Formatting with FuseSoC – Verible Integration</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/news/systemverilog-linting-and-formatting-with-fusesoc-verible-integration/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/news/systemverilog-linting-and-formatting-with-fusesoc-verible-integration/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>This post was originally published at &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/blog/2020/04/systemverilog-linter-and-formatter-in-fusesoc/">Antmicro&lt;/a>.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Although new ASIC design methodologies and tools such as Chisel are on the rise, most ASIC projects still use SystemVerilog, the support of which in open source tools has traditionally lagged behind. This is unfortunate, as using proprietary alternatives with the CI systems of open source projects is neither scalable due to licensing costs and restrictions nor simple due to the need for license management and obfuscation.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Intel joins CHIPS Alliance to promote Advanced Interface Bus (AIB) as an open standard</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/news/intel-joins-chips-alliance-to-promote-advanced-interface-bus-aib-as-an-open-standard/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/news/intel-joins-chips-alliance-to-promote-advanced-interface-bus-aib-as-an-open-standard/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>Open development for SOCs gets major boost with new collaboration&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>SAN FRANCISCO, Jan. 22, 2020 /PRNewswire/&lt;/strong> — CHIPS Alliance, the leading consortium advancing common and open hardware for interfaces, processors and systems, today announced industry leading chipmaker Intel as it’s newest member. Intel is contributing the Advanced Interface Bus (AIB) to CHIPS Alliance to foster broad adoption.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>CHIPS Alliance is hosted by the Linux Foundation to foster a collaborative environment to accelerate the creation and deployment of open SoCs, peripherals and software tools for use in mobile, computing, consumer electronics and Internet of Things (IoT) applications. The CHIPS Alliance project develops high-quality open source Register Transfer Level (RTL) code and software development tools relevant to the design of open source CPUs, SoCs, and complex peripherals for Field Programmable Gate Arrays (FPGAs) and custom silicon.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Open Source USB test suite</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/news/open-source-usb-test-suite/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/news/open-source-usb-test-suite/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>Note&lt;/strong>: the open source test suite will be demonstrated at the CHIPS Alliance booth at the &lt;a href="https://tmt.knect365.com/risc-v-summit/">RISC-V Summit 2019&lt;/a> – join us Dec 10-12 in the San Jose Convention Center!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>USB is often a daunting topic for developers, and implementing support for it from scratch is a time consuming task. When the expected result is more complicated than a USB-to-serial bridge, the solution would be to either use a hardware transceiver or, especially for older USB standards, use an open source core to implement one directly in the FPGA fabric. But which core to use?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>CHIPS Alliance announces technical milestones, three new workgroups including Chisel and the 3rd Chisel Community Conference</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/news/chips-alliance-announces-technical-milestones-three-new-workgroups-including-chisel-and-the-3rd-chisel-community-conference/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/news/chips-alliance-announces-technical-milestones-three-new-workgroups-including-chisel-and-the-3rd-chisel-community-conference/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>SAN FRANCISCO, Nov. 7, 2019&lt;/strong> — CHIPS Alliance, the leading consortium advancing common, open hardware for interfaces, processors and systems, today announced the creation of Interconnects, Rocket and Chisel workgroups. In addition, a November verification workshop in Munich and a Chisel conference in January will be held giving engineers an opportunity to learn about open source development efforts in CHIPS Alliance. Lastly, the CHIPS Alliance toolchain and cores workgroups have made contributions to open source development tools.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>CHIPS Alliance growth continues with new members and design workshop this November</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/news/chips-alliance-growth-continues-with-new-members-and-design-workshop-this-november/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/news/chips-alliance-growth-continues-with-new-members-and-design-workshop-this-november/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>SAN FRANCISCO, Oct. 15, 2019 /PRNewswire/&lt;/strong> — CHIPS Alliance, the leading consortium advancing common, open hardware for interfaces, processors and systems, today announced Codasip GmbH and Munich University of Applied Science have joined the CHIPS Alliance. In addition, on November 14–15, CHIPS Alliance will be joining the university for &lt;a href="https://c212.net/c/link/?t=0&amp;amp;l=en&amp;amp;o=2611936-1&amp;amp;h=3241488071&amp;amp;u=https%3A%2F%2Fchipsalliance.org%2Fworkshops-meetings%2F&amp;amp;a=workshop+on+open+source+design+verification">a workshop on open source design verification&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>CHIPS Alliance is a project hosted by the Linux Foundation to foster a collaborative environment to accelerate the creation and deployment of open SoCs, peripherals and software tools for use in mobile, computing, consumer electronics, and Internet of Things (IoT) applications. The CHIPS Alliance project develops high-quality open source Register Transfer Level (RTL) code relevant to the design of open source CPUs, RISC-V-based SoCs, and complex peripherals for Field Programmable Gate Arrays (FPGAs) and custom silicon.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>CHIPS Alliance featured in All About Circuits</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/news/chips-alliance-featured-in-all-about-circuits/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/news/chips-alliance-featured-in-all-about-circuits/</guid><description>&lt;p>All About Circuits recently featured an interview with Ted Marena, Yunsup Lee, Amir Salek, and Zvonimir Bandic, discussing the formation of the CHIPS Alliance, its relationship to the RISC-V Foundation, the CHIPS Alliance’s open development model, and initial open source contributions.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.allaboutcircuits.com/news/linux-chips-alliance-open-source-hardware-collaboration/">Read the article&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>CHIPS Alliance Builds Momentum and Community with Newest Members Imperas Software and Metrics</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/news/chips-alliance-builds-momentum-and-community-with-newest-members-imperas-software-and-metrics/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/news/chips-alliance-builds-momentum-and-community-with-newest-members-imperas-software-and-metrics/</guid><description>&lt;p>Imperas and Metrics joining CHIPS Alliance to help drive the verification of RISC-V Open ISA implementations&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>SAN FRANCISCO – June 18, 2019&lt;/strong> – CHIPS Alliance, the leading consortium advancing common, open hardware for interfaces, processors and systems, today announced Imperas and Metrics are joining the organization and the Verification Working Group. Imperas is an independent provider of processor simulation technology and tools for virtual platforms and
analysis tools for multicore SoC software development. Metrics leads the cloud-based solutions for SoC designers with hardware simulation for both design management flexibility and on-demand capacity. The CHIPS Alliance welcomes Imperas and Metrics among its current members Antmicro, Esperanto Technologies, Google, SiFive, Western Digital.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Podcast – Embedded Computing Design – Five Minutes With… Zvonimir Bandic, Chairman, Chips Alliance</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/news/podcast-embedded-computing-design-five-minutes-with-zvonimir-bandic-chairman-chips-alliance/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/news/podcast-embedded-computing-design-five-minutes-with-zvonimir-bandic-chairman-chips-alliance/</guid><description>&lt;p>Zvonimir Bandic wears lots of hats. He is the Senior Director of Hardware Platforms for &lt;a href="https://www.westerndigital.com/">Western Digital&lt;/a>; he’s a Member of the Board of Directors for the &lt;a href="https://riscv.org/">RISC-V Foundation&lt;/a>, and he’s the Chairman of the &lt;a href="https://chipsalliance.org/">Chips Alliance&lt;/a>. It’s that latter capacity that we discussed in this week’s Five Minutes With…discussion. The organization focuses on things like open source hardware, software tools, RTL development, and related topics. They will be holding their &lt;a href="https://events.linuxfoundation.org/events/chips-alliance-workshop-2019/">inaugural workshop&lt;/a> in just a few weeks, so it was timely to understand the purpose of the Alliance. And now I do, as will you.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>CHIPS Alliance to Reveal Project Details, Strategy and Roadmap at Inaugural Workshop Hosted at Google</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/news/chips-alliance-to-reveal-project-details-strategy-and-roadmap-at-inaugural-workshop-hosted-at-google/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/news/chips-alliance-to-reveal-project-details-strategy-and-roadmap-at-inaugural-workshop-hosted-at-google/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>SAN FRANCISCO – May 7, 2019&lt;/strong> – CHIPS Alliance, the leading consortium advancing common, open hardware for interfaces, processors and systems, today announced it is holding its inaugural workshop on June 19, 2019 at Google at 111 W. Java Drive, Sunnyvale, Calif.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Project details, strategy and roadmaps will be presented by member companies, and attendees will have an opportunity to propose Register Transfer Level (RTL) projects and development flow ideas. The workshop will focus on open source hardware, software tools, RTL development, design verification tools and related topics. The agenda and registration details are available at &lt;a href="https://events.linuxfoundation.org/events/chips-alliance-workshop-2019">https://events.linuxfoundation.org/events/chips-alliance-workshop-2019&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Open Hardware Group – CHIPS Alliance – Building Momentum and Community with Newest Member Antmicro</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/news/open-hardware-group-chips-alliance-building-momentum-and-community-with-newest-member-antmicro/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/news/open-hardware-group-chips-alliance-building-momentum-and-community-with-newest-member-antmicro/</guid><description>&lt;p>Antmicro Joins CHIPS Alliance to develop open source cores, IP blocks and tools for CPUs, RISC-V-based SoCs and peripherals&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>SAN FRANCISCO – April 18, 2019&lt;/strong> – CHIPS Alliance, the leading consortium advancing common, open hardware for interfaces, processors and systems, today announced Antmicro is joining the organization. Antmicro is a software-driven technology company focused on introducing open source into strategic areas of industry, especially edge AI. &lt;a href="https://www.linuxfoundation.org/press-release/2019/03/linux-foundation-to-host-chips-alliance-project-to-propel-industry-innovation-through-open-source-cpu-chip-and-soc-design/">Announced just last month&lt;/a>, the CHIPS Alliance welcomes Antmicro among its initial members Esperanto Technologies, Google, SiFive, and Western Digital.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Linux Foundation to Host CHIPS Alliance Project to Propel Industry Innovation Through Open Source CPU Chip and SoC Design</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/news/linux-foundation-to-host-chips-alliance-project-to-propel-industry-innovation-through-open-source-cpu-chip-and-soc-design/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/news/linux-foundation-to-host-chips-alliance-project-to-propel-industry-innovation-through-open-source-cpu-chip-and-soc-design/</guid><description>&lt;p>New Linux Foundation Project to Foster Flexible, Next-Generation Chip Design for Diverse Data-Centric Applications and Workloads&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>SAN FRANCISCO – March 11, 2019&lt;/strong> – &lt;a href="http://linuxfoundation.org/">The Linux Foundation&lt;/a>, the nonprofit organization enabling mass innovation through open source, today announced its intent to form the CHIPS Alliance project to host and curate high-quality open source code relevant to the design of silicon devices. CHIPS Alliance will foster a collaborative environment that will enable accelerated creation and deployment of more efficient and flexible chip designs for use in mobile, computing, consumer electronics, and Internet of Things (IoT) applications.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Caliptra Workgroup</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/workgroups/caliptra/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/workgroups/caliptra/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://github.com/chipsalliance/Caliptra?tab=readme-ov-file#discussion-channels">How To Join&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Chisel Workgroup</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/workgroups/chisel/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/workgroups/chisel/</guid><description>&lt;p>The &lt;a href="https://www.chisel-lang.org/">Chisel&lt;/a> Workgroup is formed around the eponymous hardware design language (HDL) that facilitates advanced circuit generation and design reuse for both ASIC and FPGA digital logic designs. Chisel adds hardware construction primitives to the &lt;a href="https://www.scala-lang.org/">Scala&lt;/a> programming language, providing designers with the power of a modern programming language to write complex, parameterizable circuit generators that produce synthesizable Verilog. Chisel is powered by &lt;a href="https://github.com/chipsalliance/firrtl">FIRRTL (Flexible Intermediate Representation for RTL)&lt;/a>, a hardware compiler framework that performs optimizations of Chisel-generated circuits and supports custom user-defined circuit transformations on an Intermediate Representation. The WG also covers tools such as &lt;a href="https://github.com/chipsalliance/treadle">Treadle&lt;/a> which is an experimental circuit simulator that executes the Firrtl IR.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Contact</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/about/contact/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/about/contact/</guid><description>&lt;script charset="utf-8" type="text/javascript" src="//js.hsforms.net/forms/embed/v2.js">&lt;/script>
&lt;script>
 hbspt.forms.create({
 region: "na1",
 portalId: "8112310",
 formId: "94557cae-71ce-4536-a54f-8eff19aab9f9",
 sfdcCampaignId: "7012M000001FetwQAC"
 });
&lt;/script>
&lt;h2 id="mailing-address">Mailing Address&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>CHIPS Alliance&lt;/strong>&lt;br>
1 Letterman Drive, Building D, Suite D4700&lt;br>
San Francisco, CA 94129&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>F4PGA Workgroup</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/workgroups/f4pga/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/workgroups/f4pga/</guid><description>&lt;p>The F4PGA Workgroup was formed to drive open source tooling, IP cores and research for FPGA devices. It includes three major groups whose collaboration is critical to the success of the open source approach in this space: FPGA vendors, industrial users and university members. Its main focus is enabling rapid prototyping and software-driven development of FPGA-oriented systems in areas such as ML and video processing. The workgroup provides an open collaboration platform for its members, aiming at accelerating the speed of innovation in FPGAs and the general availability of the technology. The initial projects contributed into CHIPS Alliance within the F4PGA Workgroup are focused around the free and open source FPGA toolchain formerly known as SymbiFlow, as well as the so-called FPGA Interchange format.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Frequently Asked Questions</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/about/faq/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/about/faq/</guid><description>&lt;div class="accordion" id="accordionExample">
 
&lt;div class="accordion-item">
 &lt;span>1&lt;/span>
 &lt;h2 class="accordion-header" id="heading1">
 &lt;button
 class="accordion-button collapsed"
 type="button"
 data-bs-toggle="collapse"
 data-bs-target="#collapse1"
 aria-expanded="false"
 aria-controls="collapse1"
 >
 &lt;p class="header-content">What is CHIPS Alliance?&lt;/p>
 &lt;/button>
 &lt;/h2>
 &lt;div
 id="collapse1"
 class="accordion-collapse collapse"
 aria-labelledby="heading1"
 data-bs-parent="#accordionExample"
 >
 &lt;div class="accordion-body">CHIPS Alliance, a member of the Linux Foundation, is championing open source based collaboration in the chip design community. This includes architectures, specifications, reference implementations, PDKs and EDA tooling. CHIPS Alliance hosts different workgroups to bring community members together to focus on topics of shared interest.&lt;/div>
 &lt;/div>
&lt;/div>

&lt;div class="accordion-item">
 &lt;span>2&lt;/span>
 &lt;h2 class="accordion-header" id="heading2">
 &lt;button
 class="accordion-button collapsed"
 type="button"
 data-bs-toggle="collapse"
 data-bs-target="#collapse2"
 aria-expanded="false"
 aria-controls="collapse2"
 >
 &lt;p class="header-content">Why do we need open source hardware, chips, FPGAs, etc.?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Getting Started</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/getting-started/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/getting-started/</guid><description>&lt;p>By creating an open and collaborative environment, the CHIPS Alliance shares resources to lower the cost of development. Companies and individuals can work together to develop open source CPUs, various peripherals, complex IP blocks, tools and workflows.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The CHIPS Alliance is open to all organizations who are interested in collaborating on open source hardware or software tools to accelerate the creation of more efficient and innovative chip designs.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>THe CHIPS Alliance is hosted by &lt;a href="https://linuxfoundation.org">The Linux Foundation&lt;/a>, a 501(c)6 non-profit.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Governance</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/about/governance/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/about/governance/</guid><description>&lt;p>In addition to the top-level structure of The CHIPS Alliance, each hosted open source project has its own process, structure, and community. While the Technical Advisory Council (TAC) sets high-level technical policy, projects have a great deal of flexibility in day-to-day operations, and would typically each adopt their own &lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/document/d/1_NeUOrl8IG7ih-Ji31LehKqv0KGT3VJcotvv4SwBmIg/edit">technical charter based on a common template&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="rob-mains---general-manager">Rob Mains - General Manager&lt;/h2>
&lt;section class="specialfeature">
 
 &lt;div class="row align-items-center">
 &lt;div class="col-lg-8 order-2 order-lg-1">
 &lt;p>The General Manager works with the Governing Board, our members, and our projects to ensure the CHIPS Alliance is a healthy, sustainable, and neutral home for open source technical collaborations.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Interconnect Workgroup</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/workgroups/interconnect/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/workgroups/interconnect/</guid><description>&lt;p>The Interconnect workgroup researches open networking protocols to facilitate direct coherency messaging between components such as processor caches, memory controllers, and various accelerators in RISC-V cores. The interconnections provided by this group play a crucial role in SoCs, chiplets, and various hardware designs. We offer design guidelines for interconnects and manage open-source interconnect IP based on these guidelines. Interconnect WG supports the advancement of the open-source hardware ecosystem.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Join</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/join/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/join/</guid><description>&lt;p>The CHIPS Alliance is an organization which works collaboratively to develop high quality, open source hardware designs relevant to silicon devices and FPGAs. By sharing openly resources and ideas, we hope to lower the cost of hardware development.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As a collection of open source projects, anyone is welcome to participate in the technical development process. The Technical Advisory Council oversees the technical direction of the project.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The CHIPS Alliance also welcomes corporate members. By participating as a corporate member, your organization provides vital funding for the infrastructure and activities that support our open and collaborative development process.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Members</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/about/members/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/about/members/</guid><description>&lt;p>When an organization joins the CHIPS Alliance, they are making a tangible commitment to the success and sustainability of open source projects which help to achieve these goals. The CHIPS Alliance recognizes the critical supporting role of these organizations, and thanks them for their ongoing support of our project communities.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="chips-alliance-members">CHIPS Alliance Members&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>
&lt;a href="../../join/" class="btn btn-primary btn-sm"> Become a Member &lt;/a>
&lt;/p>

&lt;div class="members-listing container text-center mb-5 mt-5">
 &lt;h3>Platinum Members&lt;/h3>

 
 &lt;div class="row row-cols-1 row-cols-sm-2 row-cols-md-3 row-cols-lg-4">
 
 &lt;div class="col my-auto">
 
 &lt;a href="https://www.amd.com/en" target="_blank">&lt;img alt="AMD logo" src="https://chipsalliance.org/images/members/amd.svg">&lt;/a>
 &lt;/div>
 
 &lt;div class="col my-auto">
 
 &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/" target="_blank">&lt;img alt="Antmicro logo" src="https://chipsalliance.org/images/members/antmicro.png">&lt;/a>
 &lt;/div>
 
 &lt;div class="col my-auto">
 
 &lt;a href="https://www.futurewei.com/" target="_blank">&lt;img alt="Futurewei logo" src="https://chipsalliance.org/images/members/futurewei-tech.png">&lt;/a>
 &lt;/div>
 
 &lt;div class="col my-auto">
 
 &lt;a href="https://google.com/" target="_blank">&lt;img alt="Google logo" src="https://chipsalliance.org/images/members/google.png">&lt;/a>
 &lt;/div>
 
 &lt;div class="col my-auto">
 
 &lt;a href="https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/?ql=4" target="_blank">&lt;img alt="Microsoft logo" src="https://chipsalliance.org/images/members/microsoft.svg">&lt;/a>
 &lt;/div>
 
 &lt;div class="col my-auto">
 
 &lt;a href="https://www.sifive.com/" target="_blank">&lt;img alt="SiFive logo" src="https://chipsalliance.org/images/members/sifive.png">&lt;/a>
 &lt;/div>
 
 &lt;div class="col my-auto">
 
 &lt;a href="https://verisilicon.com/" target="_blank">&lt;img alt="VeriSilicon logo" src="https://chipsalliance.org/images/members/verisilicon.png">&lt;/a>
 &lt;/div>
 
 &lt;/div>
 

&lt;/div>




&lt;div class="members-listing container text-center mb-5 mt-5">
 &lt;h3>Gold Members&lt;/h3>

 
 &lt;div class="row row-cols-1 row-cols-sm-2 row-cols-md-3 row-cols-lg-5">
 
 &lt;div class="col my-auto">
 
 &lt;a href="https://www.iscas.ac.cn/" target="_blank">&lt;img alt="ISCAS logo" src="https://chipsalliance.org/images/members/iscas.png">&lt;/a>
 &lt;/div>
 
 &lt;div class="col my-auto">
 
 &lt;a href="https://www.marvell.com/" target="_blank">&lt;img alt="Marvell logo" src="https://chipsalliance.org/images/members/marvell.svg">&lt;/a>
 &lt;/div>
 
 &lt;/div>
 

&lt;/div>




&lt;div class="members-listing container text-center mb-5 mt-5">
 &lt;h3>Silver Members&lt;/h3>

 
 &lt;div class="row row-cols-1 row-cols-sm-2 row-cols-md-3 row-cols-lg-5">
 
 &lt;div class="col my-auto">
 
 &lt;a href="https://www.ami.com/" target="_blank">&lt;img alt="AMI US Holdings Inc logo" src="https://chipsalliance.org/images/members/american-megatrendsinternational-llc.svg">&lt;/a>
 &lt;/div>
 
 &lt;div class="col my-auto">
 
 &lt;a href="https://block.xyz/" target="_blank">&lt;img alt="Block, Inc logo" src="https://chipsalliance.org/images/members/block-inc.svg">&lt;/a>
 &lt;/div>
 
 &lt;div class="col my-auto">
 
 &lt;a href="https://www.cisco.com/" target="_blank">&lt;img alt="Cisco Systems logo" src="https://chipsalliance.org/images/members/cisco-systems-inc.svg">&lt;/a>
 &lt;/div>
 
 &lt;div class="col my-auto">
 
 &lt;a href="https://www.etri.re.kr/eng/main/main.etri" target="_blank">&lt;img alt="Electronic and Telecommunications Research Institute logo" src="https://chipsalliance.org/images/members/ETRI.png">&lt;/a>
 &lt;/div>
 
 &lt;div class="col my-auto">
 
 &lt;a href="https://intel.com/" target="_blank">&lt;img alt="Intel logo" src="https://chipsalliance.org/images/members/intel.png">&lt;/a>
 &lt;/div>
 
 &lt;div class="col my-auto">
 
 &lt;a href="https://www.microchip.com/" target="_blank">&lt;img alt="Microchip logo" src="https://chipsalliance.org/images/members/microchip.svg">&lt;/a>
 &lt;/div>
 
 &lt;div class="col my-auto">
 
 &lt;a href="https://www.nvidia.com/en-us/" target="_blank">&lt;img alt="Nvidia logo" src="https://chipsalliance.org/images/members/nvidia.jpg">&lt;/a>
 &lt;/div>
 
 &lt;div class="col my-auto">
 
 &lt;a href="https://www.sandisk.com/" target="_blank">&lt;img alt="SanDisk Corporation logo" src="https://chipsalliance.org/images/members/sandiskcorporation.svg">&lt;/a>
 &lt;/div>
 
 &lt;div class="col my-auto">
 
 &lt;a href="https://www.synopsys.com/" target="_blank">&lt;img alt="Synopsys logo" src="https://chipsalliance.org/images/members/synopsys.svg">&lt;/a>
 &lt;/div>
 
 &lt;div class="col my-auto">
 
 &lt;a href="https://www.westerndigital.com/" target="_blank">&lt;img alt="Western Digital logo" src="https://chipsalliance.org/images/members/western-digital.svg">&lt;/a>
 &lt;/div>
 
 &lt;/div>
 

&lt;/div>




&lt;div class="members-listing container text-center mb-5 mt-5">
 &lt;h3>Auditor Members&lt;/h3>

 
 &lt;div class="row row-cols-1 row-cols-sm-2 row-cols-md-3 row-cols-lg-5">
 
 &lt;div class="col my-auto">
 
 &lt;a href="https://innogritcorp.com/" target="_blank">&lt;img alt="Innogrit Corporation logo" src="https://chipsalliance.org/images/members/innogrit-corporation.svg">&lt;/a>
 &lt;/div>
 
 &lt;div class="col my-auto">
 
 &lt;a href="https://precisioninno.com/" target="_blank">&lt;img alt="Precision Innovations logo" src="https://chipsalliance.org/images/members/precision-innovations.png">&lt;/a>
 &lt;/div>
 
 &lt;div class="col my-auto">
 
 &lt;a href="https://rambus.com/" target="_blank">&lt;img alt="Rambus, Inc logo" src="https://chipsalliance.org/images/members/rambus.svg">&lt;/a>
 &lt;/div>
 
 &lt;/div>
 

&lt;/div>




&lt;div class="members-listing container text-center mb-5 mt-5">
 &lt;h3>Associate Members&lt;/h3>

 
 &lt;div class="row row-cols-1 row-cols-sm-2 row-cols-md-3 row-cols-lg-5">
 
 &lt;div class="col my-auto">
 
 &lt;a href="https://asu.edu/" target="_blank">&lt;img alt="ASU logo" src="https://chipsalliance.org/images/members/arizona-state-u.svg">&lt;/a>
 &lt;/div>
 
 &lt;div class="col my-auto">
 
 &lt;a href="https://www.berkeley.edu/admissions/" target="_blank">&lt;img alt="Berkeley logo" src="https://chipsalliance.org/images/members/ucberkeley.svg">&lt;/a>
 &lt;/div>
 
 &lt;div class="col my-auto">
 
 &lt;a href="https://www.byu.edu/" target="_blank">&lt;img alt="BYU logo" src="https://chipsalliance.org/images/members/byu.svg">&lt;/a>
 &lt;/div>
 
 &lt;div class="col my-auto">
 
 &lt;a href="https://www.columbia.edu/" target="_blank">&lt;img alt="Columbia University logo" src="https://chipsalliance.org/images/members/columbia.svg">&lt;/a>
 &lt;/div>
 
 &lt;div class="col my-auto">
 
 &lt;a href="https://www.hm.edu/" target="_blank">&lt;img alt="Hochschule logo" src="https://chipsalliance.org/images/members/hochschule.png">&lt;/a>
 &lt;/div>
 
 &lt;div class="col my-auto">
 
 &lt;a href="https://www.ihp-microelectronics.com/" target="_blank">&lt;img alt="IHP logo" src="https://chipsalliance.org/images/members/ihp.svg">&lt;/a>
 &lt;/div>
 
 &lt;div class="col my-auto">
 
 &lt;a href="https://www.iitm.ac.in/" target="_blank">&lt;img alt="IIT logo" src="https://chipsalliance.org/images/members/iit.png">&lt;/a>
 &lt;/div>
 
 &lt;div class="col my-auto">
 
 &lt;a href="https://www.ku.dk/" target="_blank">&lt;img alt="Københavns Universitet logo" src="https://chipsalliance.org/images/members/kobenhavns.svg">&lt;/a>
 &lt;/div>
 
 &lt;div class="col my-auto">
 
 &lt;a href="https://nebrija.es/" target="_blank">&lt;img alt="Nebrija logo" src="https://chipsalliance.org/images/members/universidad-nebrija.png">&lt;/a>
 &lt;/div>
 
 &lt;div class="col my-auto">
 
 &lt;a href="https://www.nydesign.org/" target="_blank">&lt;img alt="NYDesign logo" src="https://chipsalliance.org/images/members/NYDesign.png">&lt;/a>
 &lt;/div>
 
 &lt;div class="col my-auto">
 
 &lt;a href="https://openpowerfoundation.org/" target="_blank">&lt;img alt="OpenPOWER Foundation logo" src="https://chipsalliance.org/images/members/OpenPower.jpg">&lt;/a>
 &lt;/div>
 
 &lt;div class="col my-auto">
 
 &lt;a href="https://theopenroadproject.org/" target="_blank">&lt;img alt="OpenRoad logo" src="https://chipsalliance.org/images/members/openroad.png">&lt;/a>
 &lt;/div>
 
 &lt;div class="col my-auto">
 
 &lt;a href="https://www.opensusi.org/" target="_blank">&lt;img alt="OpenSUSI logo" src="https://chipsalliance.org/images/members/opensusi.svg">&lt;/a>
 &lt;/div>
 
 &lt;div class="col my-auto">
 
 &lt;a href="https://rioslab.org/" target="_blank">&lt;img alt="Rios logo" src="https://chipsalliance.org/images/members/rios.png">&lt;/a>
 &lt;/div>
 
 &lt;div class="col my-auto">
 
 &lt;a href="https://riscv.org/" target="_blank">&lt;img alt="RISC-V logo" src="https://chipsalliance.org/images/members/risc-v.svg">&lt;/a>
 &lt;/div>
 
 &lt;div class="col my-auto">
 
 &lt;a href="https://engineering.stanford.edu/" target="_blank">&lt;img alt="Stanford Engineering logo" src="https://chipsalliance.org/images/members/stanford-eng.png">&lt;/a>
 &lt;/div>
 
 &lt;div class="col my-auto">
 
 &lt;a href="https://www.dtu.dk/" target="_blank">&lt;img alt="Technical University of Denmark logo" src="https://chipsalliance.org/images/members/techincal-u-of-denmark.svg">&lt;/a>
 &lt;/div>
 
 &lt;div class="col my-auto">
 
 &lt;a href="https://ucsd.edu/" target="_blank">&lt;img alt="UC San Diego logo" src="https://chipsalliance.org/images/members/uc-san-diego.png">&lt;/a>
 &lt;/div>
 
 &lt;div class="col my-auto">
 
 &lt;a href="https://www.ucsc.edu/" target="_blank">&lt;img alt="UC Santa Cruz logo" src="https://chipsalliance.org/images/members/uc-santa-cruz.png">&lt;/a>
 &lt;/div>
 
 &lt;div class="col my-auto">
 
 &lt;a href="https://www.uit.edu/" target="_blank">&lt;img alt="UIT logo" src="https://chipsalliance.org/images/members/uit-merl.png">&lt;/a>
 &lt;/div>
 
 &lt;div class="col my-auto">
 
 &lt;a href="https://kg.ac.rs/" target="_blank">&lt;img alt="University de Kragujevac logo" src="https://chipsalliance.org/images/members/university-kragujevac.png">&lt;/a>
 &lt;/div>
 
 &lt;div class="col my-auto">
 
 &lt;a href="https://www.hawaii.edu/" target="_blank">&lt;img alt="University of Hawaii logo" src="https://chipsalliance.org/images/members/university-of-hawaii-system.svg">&lt;/a>
 &lt;/div>
 
 &lt;div class="col my-auto">
 
 &lt;a href="https://www.manchester.ac.uk/" target="_blank">&lt;img alt="University of Manchester logo" src="https://chipsalliance.org/images/members/university-of-manchester.png">&lt;/a>
 &lt;/div>
 
 &lt;div class="col my-auto">
 
 &lt;a href="https://micl.engin.umich.edu/" target="_blank">&lt;img alt="University of Michigan logo" src="https://chipsalliance.org/images/members/university-of-michigan.png">&lt;/a>
 &lt;/div>
 
 &lt;div class="col my-auto">
 
 &lt;a href="https://umn.edu/" target="_blank">&lt;img alt="University of Minnesota logo" src="https://chipsalliance.org/images/members/university-of-minnesota.png">&lt;/a>
 &lt;/div>
 
 &lt;div class="col my-auto">
 
 &lt;a href="https://www.unb.ca/" target="_blank">&lt;img alt="University of New Brunswick logo" src="https://chipsalliance.org/images/members/unb.png">&lt;/a>
 &lt;/div>
 
 &lt;div class="col my-auto">
 
 &lt;a href="https://www.utoronto.ca/" target="_blank">&lt;img alt="University of Toronto logo" src="https://chipsalliance.org/images/members/university-of-toronto.png">&lt;/a>
 &lt;/div>
 
 &lt;div class="col my-auto">
 
 &lt;a href="https://yale.edu/" target="_blank">&lt;img alt="Yale University logo" src="https://chipsalliance.org/images/members/yale-university.png">&lt;/a>
 &lt;/div>
 
 &lt;/div>
 

&lt;/div></description></item><item><title>Projects</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/projects/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/projects/</guid><description>&lt;h2 class="mt-3">Graduated Projects&lt;/h2>
 &lt;article class="blog-post">
 &lt;div class="blog-post-content">

 
 
 
 
 
&lt;div class="projects-box mb-5">

&lt;div class="projects-box-col1">
 
 
 
 
 
 &lt;a href="https://github.com/chipsalliance/Caliptra/blob/main/README.md" target="_blank">
 
 
 
 
 &lt;img src="https://chipsalliance.org/images/projects/caliptra.svg" loading="lazy" alt="Caliptra">
 
 
 &lt;/a>
 
&lt;/div>

&lt;div class="projects-box-col2">
 &lt;h3 class="mt-0">Caliptra&lt;/h3>
 &lt;p> The Caliptra project focuses on development of HW and SW IP for the Caliptra Root of Trust &lt;/p>

 &lt;ul class="list-unstyled">
 &lt;li>Repositories:&lt;/li>
 &lt;ul class="list-unstyled mb-0 ms-5">
 
 
 
 
 
 
 &lt;li>&lt;i class="ph-git-branch">&lt;/i> &lt;a href="https://github.com/chipsalliance/caliptra" target="_blank">caliptra&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 
 
 
 &lt;li>&lt;i class="ph-git-branch">&lt;/i> &lt;a href="https://github.com/chipsalliance/caliptra-rtl" target="_blank">caliptra-rtl&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 
 
 
 &lt;li>&lt;i class="ph-git-branch">&lt;/i> &lt;a href="https://github.com/chipsalliance/caliptra-sw" target="_blank">caliptra-sw&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 
 
 
 &lt;li>&lt;i class="ph-git-branch">&lt;/i> &lt;a href="https://github.com/chipsalliance/caliptra-ureg" target="_blank">caliptra-ureg&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 
 
 
 &lt;li>&lt;i class="ph-git-branch">&lt;/i> &lt;a href="https://github.com/chipsalliance/caliptra-dpe" target="_blank">caliptra-dpe&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;i class="ph-clipboard-text">&lt;/i> &lt;a href="https://github.com/chipsalliance/Caliptra/issues" target="_blank">Issue Tracker&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 
 
 
 
 &lt;i class="ph-link">&lt;/i> &lt;a href="https://github.com/chipsalliance/Caliptra/blob/main/README.md" target="_blank">Website&lt;/a>
 
 
 &lt;li>&lt;i class="ph-user-square">&lt;/i> &lt;a href="mailto:andreslc@google.com" target="_blank">Contact: Andres Lagar-Cavilla&lt;/a> (&lt;a href="https://github.com/andreslagarcavilla" target="_blank">GitHub&lt;/a>)&lt;/li>
 
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>

 
 
 
 
&lt;div class="projects-box mb-5">

&lt;div class="projects-box-col1">
 
 
 
 
 
 &lt;a href="https://www.chisel-lang.org/" target="_blank">
 
 
 
 
 &lt;img src="https://chipsalliance.org/images/projects/chisel.svg" loading="lazy" alt="Chisel">
 
 
 &lt;/a>
 
&lt;/div>

&lt;div class="projects-box-col2">
 &lt;h3 class="mt-0">Chisel&lt;/h3>
 &lt;p> Support the Chisel Hardware Construction Language and related projects &lt;/p>

 &lt;ul class="list-unstyled">
 &lt;li>Repositories:&lt;/li>
 &lt;ul class="list-unstyled mb-0 ms-5">
 
 
 
 
 
 
 &lt;li>&lt;i class="ph-git-branch">&lt;/i> &lt;a href="https://github.com/chipsalliance/chisel" target="_blank">chisel&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;i class="ph-clipboard-text">&lt;/i> &lt;a href="https://github.com/chipsalliance/chisel/issues" target="_blank">Issue Tracker&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 
 
 
 
 &lt;i class="ph-link">&lt;/i> &lt;a href="https://www.chisel-lang.org/" target="_blank">Website&lt;/a>
 
 
 &lt;li>&lt;i class="ph-user-square">&lt;/i> &lt;a href="mailto:koenig@sifive.com" target="_blank">Contact: Jack Koenig&lt;/a> (&lt;a href="https://github.com/https://github.com/jackkoenig" target="_blank">GitHub&lt;/a>)&lt;/li>
 
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>

 
 
 
 
&lt;div class="projects-box mb-5">

&lt;div class="projects-box-col1">
 
 
 
 
 
 &lt;a href="https://f4pga.org" target="_blank">
 
 
 
 
 &lt;img src="https://chipsalliance.org/images/projects/f4pga.svg" loading="lazy" alt="F4PGA">
 
 
 &lt;/a>
 
&lt;/div>

&lt;div class="projects-box-col2">
 &lt;h3 class="mt-0">F4PGA&lt;/h3>
 &lt;p> Free and open source toolchain for FPGA devices &lt;/p>

 &lt;ul class="list-unstyled">
 &lt;li>Repositories:&lt;/li>
 &lt;ul class="list-unstyled mb-0 ms-5">
 
 
 
 
 
 
 &lt;li>&lt;i class="ph-git-branch">&lt;/i> &lt;a href="https://github.com/chipsalliance/f4pga" target="_blank">f4pga&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;i class="ph-clipboard-text">&lt;/i> &lt;a href="https://github.com/chipsalliance/f4pga/issues" target="_blank">Issue Tracker&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 
 
 
 
 &lt;i class="ph-link">&lt;/i> &lt;a href="https://f4pga.org" target="_blank">Website&lt;/a>
 
 
 &lt;li>&lt;i class="ph-user-square">&lt;/i> &lt;a href="mailto:tmichalak@antmicro.com" target="_blank">Contact: Tomasz Michalak&lt;/a> (&lt;a href="https://github.com/tmichalak" target="_blank">GitHub&lt;/a>)&lt;/li>
 
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>

 
 
 
 
&lt;div class="projects-box mb-5">

&lt;div class="projects-box-col1">
 
 
 
 
 
 &lt;a href="https://github.com/chipsalliance/systemc-compiler/wiki" target="_blank">
 
 
 
 
 &lt;img src="https://chipsalliance.org/images/muted-logo.svg" loading="lazy" alt="Placeholder project logo">
 
 
 &lt;/a>
 
&lt;/div>

&lt;div class="projects-box-col2">
 &lt;h3 class="mt-0">Intel Compiler for SystemC&lt;/h3>
 &lt;p> Open source SystemC to SystemVerilog translation tool and SingleSource library. &lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Rocket Workgroup</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/workgroups/rocket/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/workgroups/rocket/</guid><description>&lt;p>The Rocket Chip Workgroup covers the “Rocket” pipelined implementation of a RISC-V core as well as a TileLink uncore and cache coherent memory hierarchy. The main rocket-chip repository that the group maintains is a meta-repository containing tools needed to generate and test RTL implementations of SoC designs. This repository contains code that is used to generate RTL using &lt;a href="http://chisel.eecs.berkeley.edu/">Chisel&lt;/a> and Diplomacy: the Rocket Chip generator itself is a Scala program that invokes the Diplomacy library and Chisel compiler in order to emit RTL describing a complete SoC.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>SystemVerilog Tools Workgroup</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/workgroups/tools/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/workgroups/tools/</guid><description>&lt;p>The SystemVerilog Tools workgroup (WG) of CHIPS Alliance covers a wide array of open source SystemVerilog tooling for ASIC and FPGA design, mostly focusing around digital design (as there is a separate Analog WG that focuses on AMS design flows). The topics covered include simulation, synthesis, place and route, IP aggregation, linting, formatting, and many more.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Who We Are</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/about/who-we-are/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/about/who-we-are/</guid><description>&lt;p>The CHIPS Alliance leverages common hardware development efforts by developing IP blocks that can be broadly used, such as RISC-V cores and neural network accelerator cores. We recognize that verification contributions benefit all who participate in the project, and prioritize joint resources for design verification.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The scope of the Project includes hardware and software design and development under an open source (Apache v2) license:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Verified IP blocks (compute cores, accelerators etc)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Verified SoC designs (based on RISC-V and other open source cores)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Open source software development tools for ASIC development&lt;/li>
&lt;li>High value IP including analog peripherals, mixed signal blocks and compute acceleration&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Exploration of new design flows such as Python-based design verification.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The CHIPS Alliance welcomes technical contributions from members and non-members alike. We encourage everyone to use, extend, and contribute back to our projects, and to participate on the Technical Steering Committee.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>We also welcome organizations and institutions who wish to participate in the CHIPS Alliance governance process by &lt;a href="../../join/">becoming members&lt;/a>. If you have questions, please reach out to &lt;a href="mailto:membership@chipsalliance.org">membership@chipsalliance.org&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>