<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>omnixtend on CHIPS Alliance</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/184/tags/omnixtend/</link><description>Recent content in omnixtend on CHIPS Alliance</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 24 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://chipsalliance.org/preview/184/tags/omnixtend/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>CHIPS Alliance and RISC-V International Invite the RISC-V Community to Participate in Updating a New Unified Memory Architecture Standard</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/184/news/risc-v-international-omnixtend-working-group/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/184/news/risc-v-international-omnixtend-working-group/</guid><description>New joint working group will enhance the OmniXtend Cache Coherency architecture
SAN FRANCISCO, March 24, 2020 – RISC-V International, a non-profit corporation controlled by its members to drive the adoption and implementation of the free and open RISC-V instruction set architecture (ISA), and CHIPS Alliance, the leading consortium advancing common and open hardware for interfaces, processors and systems, today announced a joint collaboration to update the OmniXtend Cache Coherency specification and protocol, along with building out developer tools for OmniXtend.</description></item><item><title>CHIPS Alliance to Collaborate with RISC-V to Standardize an Open Unified Memory Leveraging OmniXtend</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/184/news/omnixtend/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/184/news/omnixtend/</guid><description>CHIPS Alliance to highlight OmniXtend advances at RISC-V Summit
SAN FRANCISCO, Dec. 8, 2020 – CHIPS Alliance, the leading consortium advancing common and open hardware for interfaces, processors and systems, today announced that the organization will highlight OmniXtend advances in a presentation at the RISC-V Summit, taking place virtually from Dec. 8-10, 2020. The CHIPS Alliance plans to work with RISC-V International to standardize an open unified memory coherency bus leveraging OmniXtend to foster innovation for data-centric applications.</description></item></channel></rss>