<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>surelog on CHIPS Alliance</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/tags/surelog/</link><description>Recent content in surelog on CHIPS Alliance</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://chipsalliance.org/tags/surelog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Improving the OpenLane ASIC Build Flow with Open Source SystemVerilog Support</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/news/improving-the-openlane-asic-build-flow-with-open-source-systemverilog-support/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/news/improving-the-openlane-asic-build-flow-with-open-source-systemverilog-support/</guid><description>This post was originally published at Antmicro.
Open source toolchains are key to building collaborative ecosystems, welcoming to new approaches, opportunistic/focused innovations and niche use cases. The ASIC design domain, especially in the view of the rising tensions around manufacturing and supply chains, are in dire need of a software-driven innovation based on an open source approach. The fledgling open source hardware ecosystem has been energized by the success of RISC-V and is now being vastly expanded to cover the entire ASIC design flow by CHIPS Alliance, and Antmicro has been playing a leadership role in both of these organizations as well as offering commercial engineering and support services to assist with early adoption of open source approaches in hardware.</description></item><item><title>Progress on Building Open Source Infrastructure for System Verilog</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/news/open-source-infrastructure-for-system-verilog/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/news/open-source-infrastructure-for-system-verilog/</guid><description>SystemVerilog is a rich hardware design description and verification language that is seeing increased usage in industry. In the second Deep Dive Cafe Talk by CHIPS Alliance on July 20, Henner Zeller, who is an software developer with Google, provided an excellent in depth technical talk on building out an open source tooling ecosystem around SystemVerilog to provide a common framework that can be used by both functional simulation applications as well as logic synthesis.</description></item><item><title>Enabling Open Source Ibex Synthesis and Simulation in Verilator/Yosys via UHDM/Surelog</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/news/ibex-synthesis-and-simulation/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/news/ibex-synthesis-and-simulation/</guid><description>This post was originally published at Antmicro.
Throughout 2020 we were hard at work developing proper, portable SystemVerilog support for multiple open-source FPGA and ASIC design tools used by us and our customers, most notably Yosys and Verilator. We strongly believe that the support is a necessary step in building a collaborative ecosystem and scalable and reproducible CIs, especially publicly accessible ones that are common in multi-organization projects such as OpenTitan and CHIPS Alliance.</description></item></channel></rss>