<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>F4pga on CHIPS Alliance</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/206/tags/f4pga/</link><description>Recent content in F4pga on CHIPS Alliance</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://chipsalliance.org/preview/206/tags/f4pga/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>CHIPS Alliance - Our Vision and Priorities for 2026</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/206/news/2026-vision/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/206/news/2026-vision/</guid><description>&lt;p>Dear CHIPS Alliance Community,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As we approach 2026, the CHIPS Alliance is evolving. Over the past few years, we have grown from a collection of ambitious projects into a central hub for open-source silicon innovation. Our vision for 2026 is centered on &lt;strong>sustainability, technical rigor, and established trust&lt;/strong>. We are transitioning from an incubation phase to a mature, community-driven ecosystem focused on high-quality, verifiable IP and robust tooling for design and validation enablement.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>F4PGA open source flow gets a new Python-based build system and CLI tool</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/206/news/f4pga-open-source-flow-gets-a-new-python-based-build-system-and-cli-tool/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/206/news/f4pga-open-source-flow-gets-a-new-python-based-build-system-and-cli-tool/</guid><description>&lt;p>One of the most recent projects developed within the workgroup is the &lt;a href="https://github.com/chipsalliance/f4pga">unified f4pga CLI tool&lt;/a>. In the broader context of our &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/blog/2021/09/fpga-interchange-format/">continuous efforts to make the FPGA space more unified and flexible&lt;/a>, creating the f4pga CLI tool was a logical next step – it allowed us to wrap the underlying tools into a single CLI, making the F4PGA toolchain a more complete flow. The currently supported architectures are AMD’s (former Xilinx) 7 Series, Lattice’s iCE40 and QuickLogic’s EOS S3. &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/blog/2022/09/f4pga-new-build-system-and-cli-tool">Details are here&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>CHIPS Alliance Forms F4PGA Workgroup to Accelerate Adoption of Open Source FPGA Tooling</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/206/news/chips-alliance-forms-f4pga-workgroup-to-accelerate-adoption-of-open-source-fpga-tooling/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/206/news/chips-alliance-forms-f4pga-workgroup-to-accelerate-adoption-of-open-source-fpga-tooling/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>New workgroup draws support from industry leaders as the open FPGA toolchain matures&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>SAN FRANCISCO, Feb. 18, 2022&lt;/strong> – CHIPS Alliance, the leading consortium advancing common and open source hardware for interfaces, processors and systems, today established the FOSS Flow For FPGA (F4PGA) Workgroup to drive open source tooling, IP and research efforts for FPGAs.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>FPGA vendors such as Xilinx (now part of AMD) and QuickLogic, industrial FPGA users and contributors such as Google and Antmicro, as well as universities including Brigham Young University, University of Pennsylvania, Princeton University and University of Toronto, can now officially collaborate under the umbrella of the newly launched F4PGA Workgroup.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>SymbiFlow FPGA Interchange Format to Enable Interoperable FPGA Tooling</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/206/news/symbiflow-fpga-interchange-format-to-enable-interoperable-fpga-tooling/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/206/news/symbiflow-fpga-interchange-format-to-enable-interoperable-fpga-tooling/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>This post was originally published at &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/blog/2021/09/symbiflow-fpga-interchange-format/">Antmicro&lt;/a>.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/technologies/fpga/">Field Programmable Gate Arrays (FPGAs)&lt;/a> have been around for several decades, but historically development of toolchains targeting specific platforms was done in separate ecosystems and driven by the vendors themselves. Only in recent years, the development of vendor-neutral open source toolchains has revealed the need of having an abstraction layer to describe and define an FPGA architecture through a standard format.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>FPGA toolchains are not trivial as they comprise several elements which themselves can be quite complex: roughly speaking, you can divide the process of “compiling” FPGA-targeted code in a Hardware Description Language (HDL) into three stages: synthesis, place and route, bitstream generation. A standard format could provide a common description of the various architectures and serve as a bridge between the multitude of open source and closed proprietary tools that deal with the entire process or parts thereof, including the open source Yosys for synthesis and VtR and nextpnr for place and route, to relevant vendor tooling from Xilinx, Intel, Lattice, QuickLogic, etc.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Efabless Launches chipIgnite with SkyWater to Bring Chip Creation to the Masses</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/206/news/efabless-launches-chipignite/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/206/news/efabless-launches-chipignite/</guid><description>&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Program includes a pre-designed carrier chip and automated open source design flow from Efabless&lt;/li>
&lt;li>SkyWater’s open source SKY130 process is the first node to be used to fabricate chips for the program&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Initiative removes access barriers by significantly reducing cost and the need for deep semiconductor experience to design chips&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.globenewswire.com/Tracker?data=_QfpiutgK9BkRkwqOZ_QgaW-wScChSfzrLoisG3jrx29CaZIKTRoBuySTDuHXJZP0EbK1_N1KyzIRCW2sFc5NA==">Efabless&lt;/a>, a community chip creation platform, today announced the launch of its new chipIgnite program to bring chip design and fabrication to the masses and a collaboration with &lt;a href="https://www.globenewswire.com/Tracker?data=P477GUgP-WxQLcA8zmSX8V24RDJ0fqqGp8teNuFfFkL7nLvoEPgkh9Uyo0a6ZDG-JNw_Hz99p5lNq7zs7gL_EsV6v-ZGI8zuNwlyMu1wbZ4=">SkyWater Technology&lt;/a> for the first node supported in the program. The chipIgnite program expands upon the SKY130-based open source chip manufacturing program sponsored by Google and supports private commercial designs that include non-open source IP. This initiative represents another step forward in the industry to broaden access to chip design by giving people the ability to more easily create and fabricate chips.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Efabless Joins CHIPS Alliance to Accelerate the Growth of the Open Source Chip Ecosystem</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/206/news/efabless-joins-chips-alliance-to-accelerate-the-growth-of-the-open-source-chip-ecosystem/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/206/news/efabless-joins-chips-alliance-to-accelerate-the-growth-of-the-open-source-chip-ecosystem/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>Efabless to give a talk on the OpenROAD project at the CHIPS Alliance Workshop on Sept. 17&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>SAN FRANCISCO, Sept. 15, 2020&lt;/strong> – CHIPS Alliance, the leading consortium advancing common and open hardware for interfaces, processors and systems, today welcomed Efabless, a crowdsourcing design platform for custom silicon, as its latest member. Efabless is already an active participant in several open source initiatives that the CHIPS Alliance is involved in, including the OpenROAD project and the Open Source Shuttle Program.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>QuickLogic Announces Open Reconfigurable Computing Initiative</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/206/news/quicklogic-announces-open-reconfigurable-computing-initiative/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/206/news/quicklogic-announces-open-reconfigurable-computing-initiative/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>&lt;a href="https://ir.quicklogic.com/press-releases/detail/535/quicklogic-announces-open-reconfigurable-computing">Originally issued&lt;/a> by QuickLogic, the following press release announces the QORC initiative including the world’s first vendor-supported open FPGA toolchain using SymbiFlow, and describes the contribution of CHIPS Alliance members Antmicro and Google.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>QuickLogic Open Reconfigurable Computing (QORC) initiative, developed by Antmicro in collaboration with QuickLogic and Google, broadens access to company’s FPGA technology and eFPGA IP for all embedded systems developers&lt;/li>
&lt;li>First Programmable Logic Company to Embrace Open Source FPGA Development Tools&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>San Jose, CA&lt;/strong> – June 16, 2020 – QuickLogic Corporation (NASDAQ: QUIK), a developer of ultra-low power multi-core voice-enabled SoCs, embedded FPGA IP, and Endpoint AI solutions, today announced its ground breaking QORC (QuickLogic Open Reconfigurable Computing) initiative, making it the first programmable logic vendor to actively embrace a fully open source suite of development tools for its FPGA devices and eFPGA technology. This initiative engenders the emerging trend toward open source tooling, significantly broadens access to the company’s products, and enables both hardware and software developers with tools supported by both the user community and QuickLogic.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>