<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Report on CHIPS Alliance</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/204/tags/report/</link><description>Recent content in Report on CHIPS Alliance</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 28 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://chipsalliance.org/preview/204/tags/report/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Next Chapter in Open Source Silicon- Download the CHIPS Alliance White Paper</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/204/news/tac-whitepaper/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/204/news/tac-whitepaper/</guid><description>&lt;p>CHIPS Alliance has just released a new white paper, CHIPS Alliance and the Open Hardware Landscape, designed to demystify the current state of open hardware, outline the challenges ahead, and chart a path forward for everyone from startups to silicon giants.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="why-read-this">Why Read This?&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>If you are building silicon, designing SoCs, or investing in hardware innovation, this paper is your strategic guide to understanding where open hardware is headed and how you can be part of it.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>A Look Back at the CHIPS Alliance’s Incredible Growth</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/204/news/chips-alliances-incredible-growth/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/204/news/chips-alliances-incredible-growth/</guid><description>&lt;p>It’s been just over a year since the CHIPS Alliance was founded with the mission of making open source hardware development more accessible to companies, universities and individuals. We’re working to bring the dynamics of the hugely successful open source software development model into ASIC design, building on the groundwork set by the RISC-V community. Progress over the past year is detailed in our &lt;a href="https://chipsalliance.org/chips-alliance-2020-annual-report/">Annual Report&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>CHIPS Alliance is focused on expanding on this open hardware vision by:&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>