<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>announcement on CHIPS Alliance</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/192/tags/announcement/</link><description>Recent content in announcement on CHIPS Alliance</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://chipsalliance.org/preview/192/tags/announcement/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>CHIPS Alliance’s Caliptra Launches 2.1 RTL Release</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/192/news/caliptra2-1/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/192/news/caliptra2-1/</guid><description>As the Caliptra partners and CHIPS Alliance members Microsoft, Google, NVIDIA and AMD continue to push the boundaries of open hardware security, we’re excited to announce the Caliptra 2.1 RTL release — another important step in building a more secure and transparent silicon ecosystem. This update builds on Caliptra 2.0, delivering refined features, improved verification, and smoother integration for adopters across the industry.
The growing momentum behind Caliptra highlights the power of collaboration between the Open Compute Project (OCP) and CHIPS Alliance communities.</description></item><item><title>CHIPS Alliance Welcomes the Caliptra Open Source Root of Trust Project</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/192/news/chips-alliance-welcomes-the-caliptra-open-source-root-of-trust-project/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/192/news/chips-alliance-welcomes-the-caliptra-open-source-root-of-trust-project/</guid><description>SAN FRANCISCO, December 13, 2022 – CHIPS Alliance, a Linux Foundation project and leading consortium advancing common and open hardware for interfaces, processors and systems, announced that Caliptra, the open source root of trust project founded by technology leaders AMD, Google, Microsoft and NVIDIA, has joined CHIPS Alliance to enable an open, collaborative community-driven approach to hardware security.
Caliptra is a new specification for an open source silicon root of trust (RoT) designed to meet the enhanced security requirements of modern edge and confidential computing workloads.</description></item><item><title>Joint Analog Workgroup / MOS-AK Panel Session</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/192/news/joint-analog-workgroup-mos-ak-panel-session/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/192/news/joint-analog-workgroup-mos-ak-panel-session/</guid><description>Please join us for a special joint panel webinar session for the CHIPS Alliance Analog Workgroup and MOS-AK Foundation.
This panel will feature speakers with 20 minute talks on the following topic areas:
@Mehdi Saligane : Introduction to the open source EDA tool flow for IC design (with reference to [1]) @Makris Nikolaos : EKV3 in NGSPICE using ADMSXL @Keiter, Eric R : Xyce and its support for commercial (hSpice/spectre) libs/syntax @Tim Edwards : his work on the SkyWater 130 nm compatibility with ngspice @Kevin Cameron : update on the P1800 (SystemVerilog) AMS standardization efforts (public doc [2]) There will be time for Q &amp;amp; A after each talk and conversation after the presentation completion.</description></item><item><title>CHIPS Alliance Fall 2022 Technology Update December 15</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/192/news/chips-alliance-fall-2022-technology-update-december-15/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/192/news/chips-alliance-fall-2022-technology-update-december-15/</guid><description>Please join us on December 15 at 8:30 am PT either in person at Google or virtually for a CHIPS technology update featuring many exciting speakers. Details and registration are here: https://events.linuxfoundation.org/chips-biannual-technology-update/</description></item><item><title>Catch us at DAC 59 in San Francisco starting July 11</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/192/news/catch-us-at-dac-59-in-san-francisco-starting-july-11/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/192/news/catch-us-at-dac-59-in-san-francisco-starting-july-11/</guid><description>Come learn about open source hardware and CHIPS Alliance at next week’s 59th Design Automation Conference in San Francisco. We will be at kiosk 2344 in the RISC-V pavilion. You can also here out talk at 12:30 Monday in the Open Source Central Theatre (booth 2338). We are also in a DAC Pavilion Panel: Is Democratization of Chip Design Already Happening? at 2:30 on Monday. Look forward to an exciting day in SF!</description></item><item><title>Alibaba Cloud Announced Progress in Porting Android Functions onto RISC-V</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/192/news/alibaba-cloud-announced-progress-in-porting-android-functions-onto-risc-v/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/192/news/alibaba-cloud-announced-progress-in-porting-android-functions-onto-risc-v/</guid><description>The company also tops MLPerf Tiny v0.7 Benchmark with its IOT processor
Hangzhou, China, April 20, 2022 – Alibaba Cloud, the digital technologies and intelligence backbone of Alibaba Group, announced it has made further progress in porting basic Android functions onto the RISC-V instruction-set architecture (ISA). This proves the feasibility of using RISC-V based Android devices in scenarios ranging from multimedia to signal processing, device interconnection, and artificial intelligence.
Last year, the company reported it had successfully ported basic functions like chrome browsing in Android 10.</description></item><item><title>CHIPS Alliance Forms F4PGA Workgroup to Accelerate Adoption of Open Source FPGA Tooling</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/192/news/chips-alliance-forms-f4pga-workgroup-to-accelerate-adoption-of-open-source-fpga-tooling/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/192/news/chips-alliance-forms-f4pga-workgroup-to-accelerate-adoption-of-open-source-fpga-tooling/</guid><description>New workgroup draws support from industry leaders as the open FPGA toolchain matures
SAN FRANCISCO, Feb. 18, 2022 – CHIPS Alliance, the leading consortium advancing common and open source hardware for interfaces, processors and systems, today established the FOSS Flow For FPGA (F4PGA) Workgroup to drive open source tooling, IP and research efforts for FPGAs.
FPGA vendors such as Xilinx (now part of AMD) and QuickLogic, industrial FPGA users and contributors such as Google and Antmicro, as well as universities including Brigham Young University, University of Pennsylvania, Princeton University and University of Toronto, can now officially collaborate under the umbrella of the newly launched F4PGA Workgroup.</description></item><item><title>CHIPS Alliance Announces Xilinx as its Newest Member</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/192/news/xilinx-new-member/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/192/news/xilinx-new-member/</guid><description>Xilinx to continue to drive forward open source FPGA innovation
SAN FRANCISCO, Feb. 3, 2022 – CHIPS Alliance, the leading consortium advancing common and open hardware for interfaces, processors and systems, today announced that Xilinx, Inc. (NASDAQ: XLNX) has joined the CHIPS Alliance organization. Xilinx is a leader in adaptive computing, providing highly-flexible programmable silicon, enabled by a suite of advanced software and tools to drive rapid innovation across a wide span of industries and technologies – from consumer to cars to the cloud.</description></item><item><title>SkyWater Technology Joins CHIPS Alliance to Further Efforts to Make Chip Design and Production More Accessible</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/192/news/skywater-technology-joins-chips-alliance-to-further-efforts-to-make-chip-design-and-production-more-accessible/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/192/news/skywater-technology-joins-chips-alliance-to-further-efforts-to-make-chip-design-and-production-more-accessible/</guid><description>SkyWater furthers collaboration with CHIPS Alliance members on open source shuttle projects
SAN FRANCISCO, Sept. 16, 2021 – CHIPS Alliance, the leading consortium advancing common and open hardware for interfaces, processors and systems, today announced that SkyWater Technology (NASDAQ: SKYT) has become a member of the organization. SkyWater provides custom development, volume manufacturing and advanced packaging services for a wide range of silicon, including solutions based on the free and open RISC-V instruction set architecture (ISA).</description></item><item><title>Efabless Launches chipIgnite with SkyWater to Bring Chip Creation to the Masses</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/192/news/efabless-launches-chipignite/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/192/news/efabless-launches-chipignite/</guid><description>Program includes a pre-designed carrier chip and automated open source design flow from Efabless SkyWater’s open source SKY130 process is the first node to be used to fabricate chips for the program Initiative removes access barriers by significantly reducing cost and the need for deep semiconductor experience to design chips Efabless, a community chip creation platform, today announced the launch of its new chipIgnite program to bring chip design and fabrication to the masses and a collaboration with SkyWater Technology for the first node supported in the program.</description></item><item><title>Antmicro’s ARVSOM RISC-V Module Announced</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/192/news/antmicros-arvsom-risc-v-module-announced/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/192/news/antmicros-arvsom-risc-v-module-announced/</guid><description>This post was originally published at Antmicro.
We are excited to announce the ARVSOM – Antmicro’s fully open source, RISC-V-based system-on-module featuring the StarFive 71×0 SoC. Using the RISC-V architecture, which Antmicro has been heavily involved in since the early days as a Founding Member of RISC-V International, the SoM is going to enable unprecedented openness, reusability and functionality across different verticals.
We are excited to announce the ARVSOM – Antmicro’s fully open source, RISC-V-based system-on-module featuring the StarFive 71×0 SoC.</description></item><item><title>New MPW-TWO Program Will Provide Fabrication For Fully Open Source Projects</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/192/news/new-mpw-two-program/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/192/news/new-mpw-two-program/</guid><description>CHIPS Alliance is excited to announce that the hardware development community can submit their open source design projects to Efabless.com for space on their forthcoming shuttle. This opportunity comes after the success of having 40 submissions for the MPW-ONE shuttle; 60% of those designs were submitted by first-time ASIC designers. MPW-TWO is the second Open MPW Shuttle providing fabrication for fully open-source projects using the SkyWater Open Source PDK announced by Google and SkyWater.</description></item><item><title>CHIPS Alliance and RISC-V International Invite the RISC-V Community to Participate in Updating a New Unified Memory Architecture Standard</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/192/news/risc-v-international-omnixtend-working-group/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/192/news/risc-v-international-omnixtend-working-group/</guid><description>New joint working group will enhance the OmniXtend Cache Coherency architecture
SAN FRANCISCO, March 24, 2020 – RISC-V International, a non-profit corporation controlled by its members to drive the adoption and implementation of the free and open RISC-V instruction set architecture (ISA), and CHIPS Alliance, the leading consortium advancing common and open hardware for interfaces, processors and systems, today announced a joint collaboration to update the OmniXtend Cache Coherency specification and protocol, along with building out developer tools for OmniXtend.</description></item><item><title>CHIPS Alliance Welcomes Antmicro and VeriSilicon to the Platinum Membership Level</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/192/news/chips-alliance-welcomes-antmicro-and-verisilicon-to-the-platinum-membership-level/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/192/news/chips-alliance-welcomes-antmicro-and-verisilicon-to-the-platinum-membership-level/</guid><description>CHIPS Alliance continues to grow with more than 25 companies collaborating on open source hardware and software technologies
SAN FRANCISCO, Feb. 11, 2021 – CHIPS Alliance, the leading consortium advancing common and open hardware for interfaces, processors and systems, today welcomed Antmicro and VeriSilicon to the company’s Platinum membership level. Antmicro, one of the initial members of the CHIPS Alliance, has upgraded to the Platinum membership level to reflect its deepening involvement in the organization.</description></item><item><title>CHIPS Alliance Brings on Rob Mains as New Executive Director</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/192/news/chips-alliance-brings-on-rob-mains-as-new-executive-director/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/192/news/chips-alliance-brings-on-rob-mains-as-new-executive-director/</guid><description>Industry veteran to lead open hardware consortium democratizing silicon innovation
SAN FRANCISCO, Feb. 8, 2021 – CHIPS Alliance, the leading consortium advancing common and open hardware for interfaces, processors and systems, today announced the appointment of Rob Mains as the organization’s new executive director.
Rob has over 35 years of experience in software engineering and development, with 25 years of experience as an EDA software architect focused on microprocessor design and advanced process node technologies.</description></item><item><title>Efabless Joins CHIPS Alliance to Accelerate the Growth of the Open Source Chip Ecosystem</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/192/news/efabless-joins-chips-alliance-to-accelerate-the-growth-of-the-open-source-chip-ecosystem/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/192/news/efabless-joins-chips-alliance-to-accelerate-the-growth-of-the-open-source-chip-ecosystem/</guid><description>Efabless to give a talk on the OpenROAD project at the CHIPS Alliance Workshop on Sept. 17
SAN FRANCISCO, Sept. 15, 2020 – CHIPS Alliance, the leading consortium advancing common and open hardware for interfaces, processors and systems, today welcomed Efabless, a crowdsourcing design platform for custom silicon, as its latest member. Efabless is already an active participant in several open source initiatives that the CHIPS Alliance is involved in, including the OpenROAD project and the Open Source Shuttle Program.</description></item><item><title>CHIPS Alliance to Collaborate with RISC-V to Standardize an Open Unified Memory Leveraging OmniXtend</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/192/news/omnixtend/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/192/news/omnixtend/</guid><description>CHIPS Alliance to highlight OmniXtend advances at RISC-V Summit
SAN FRANCISCO, Dec. 8, 2020 – CHIPS Alliance, the leading consortium advancing common and open hardware for interfaces, processors and systems, today announced that the organization will highlight OmniXtend advances in a presentation at the RISC-V Summit, taking place virtually from Dec. 8-10, 2020. The CHIPS Alliance plans to work with RISC-V International to standardize an open unified memory coherency bus leveraging OmniXtend to foster innovation for data-centric applications.</description></item><item><title>The CHIPS Alliance Workshop: 10 Talks From Industry Leaders, All For Free</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/192/news/the-chips-alliance-workshop-overview/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/192/news/the-chips-alliance-workshop-overview/</guid><description>Mark your calendars! The CHIPS Alliance Workshop is coming up on Thursday, Sept. 17 from 11 a.m. to 2 p.m. PT. This free, virtual event will feature talks from industry leaders including Antmicro, Efabless, Google, Intel, Mentor, Metrics, OpenROAD, QuickLogic, SiFive, UC Berkeley and Western Digital.
The CHIPS Alliance Workshop will fit 10 sessions into three hours for a jam-packed event covering a range of interesting topics in the open source community.</description></item><item><title>CHIPS Alliance Welcomes Mentor as its Newest Member</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/192/news/chips-alliance-welcomes-mentor-as-its-newest-member/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/192/news/chips-alliance-welcomes-mentor-as-its-newest-member/</guid><description>Mentor to present at the virtual CHIPS Alliance Workshop on Sept. 17
SAN FRANCISCO, Aug. 18, 2020 – CHIPS Alliance, the leading consortium advancing common and open hardware for interfaces, processors and systems, today announced that Mentor, a Siemens business, has joined as its newest member. The CHIPS Alliance has a roster of more than 20 members collaborating to accelerate the creation and deployment of open system-on-chips (SoCs), peripherals and software tools for a wide range of applications.</description></item><item><title>QuickLogic Joins CHIPS Alliance to Expand Open Source FPGA Efforts</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/192/news/quicklogic-joins-chips-alliance-to-expand-open-source-fpga-efforts/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/192/news/quicklogic-joins-chips-alliance-to-expand-open-source-fpga-efforts/</guid><description>QuickLogic to present at the virtual CHIPS Alliance Workshop on Sept. 17
SAN FRANCISCO, Aug. 11, 2020 – CHIPS Alliance, the leading consortium advancing common and open hardware for interfaces, processors and systems, today announced that QuickLogic Corporation (NASDAQ: QUIK), a developer of ultra-low power multi-core voice-enabled SoCs, embedded FPGA IP, and Endpoint AI solutions, has joined as its newest member.
“Over the past few years the electronics industry has seen a big shift towards open source hardware and software, and we’re proud to be one of the companies at the forefront of that movement,” said Brian Faith, president and CEO at QuickLogic.</description></item><item><title>CHIPS Alliance Announces AIB 2.0 Draft Specification to Accelerate Design of Open Source Chiplets</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/192/news/aib-2-0-draft-specification/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/192/news/aib-2-0-draft-specification/</guid><description>AIB reduces design barriers, costs, and leverages generators to ease development of chiplet-based designs
SAN FRANCISCO, July 16, 2020 – CHIPS Alliance, the leading consortium advancing common and open hardware for interfaces, processors and systems, today announced that it has released the Advanced Interface Bus (AIB) version 2.0 draft specification on GitHub. The AIB standard is an open-source, royalty-free PHY-level standard for connecting multiple semiconductor die within the same package. AIB is ideal for designing SoCs, FPGAs, SerDes chiplets, high-performance ADC/DAC chiplets, optical networking chiplets and more.</description></item><item><title>QuickLogic Announces Open Reconfigurable Computing Initiative</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/192/news/quicklogic-announces-open-reconfigurable-computing-initiative/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/192/news/quicklogic-announces-open-reconfigurable-computing-initiative/</guid><description>Originally issued by QuickLogic, the following press release announces the QORC initiative including the world’s first vendor-supported open FPGA toolchain using SymbiFlow, and describes the contribution of CHIPS Alliance members Antmicro and Google.
QuickLogic Open Reconfigurable Computing (QORC) initiative, developed by Antmicro in collaboration with QuickLogic and Google, broadens access to company’s FPGA technology and eFPGA IP for all embedded systems developers First Programmable Logic Company to Embrace Open Source FPGA Development Tools San Jose, CA – June 16, 2020 – QuickLogic Corporation (NASDAQ: QUIK), a developer of ultra-low power multi-core voice-enabled SoCs, embedded FPGA IP, and Endpoint AI solutions, today announced its ground breaking QORC (QuickLogic Open Reconfigurable Computing) initiative, making it the first programmable logic vendor to actively embrace a fully open source suite of development tools for its FPGA devices and eFPGA technology.</description></item><item><title>A Look Back at the CHIPS Alliance’s Incredible Growth</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/192/news/chips-alliances-incredible-growth/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/192/news/chips-alliances-incredible-growth/</guid><description>It’s been just over a year since the CHIPS Alliance was founded with the mission of making open source hardware development more accessible to companies, universities and individuals. We’re working to bring the dynamics of the hugely successful open source software development model into ASIC design, building on the groundwork set by the RISC-V community. Progress over the past year is detailed in our Annual Report.
CHIPS Alliance is focused on expanding on this open hardware vision by:</description></item><item><title>CHIPS Alliance’s Newly Enhanced SweRV Cores Available to All for Free</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/192/news/newly-enhanced-swerv-cores/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/192/news/newly-enhanced-swerv-cores/</guid><description>CHIPS Alliance to host online event to help community innovating with SweRV Core EH2 and EL2 Solutions
SAN FRANCISCO, May 14, 2020 – CHIPS Alliance, the leading consortium advancing common and open hardware for interfaces, processors and systems, today announced new enhancements to the SweRV Core™ EH2 and SweRV Core EL2, developed for the open-source community by Western Digital. Since the introduction of the cores earlier this year, the CHIPS Alliance has worked with its community to exhaustedly validate the cores through a transparent and rigorous process, as well as incorporate a variety of new updates.</description></item><item><title>CHIPS Alliance announces technical milestones, three new workgroups including Chisel and the 3rd Chisel Community Conference</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/192/news/chips-alliance-announces-technical-milestones-three-new-workgroups-including-chisel-and-the-3rd-chisel-community-conference/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/192/news/chips-alliance-announces-technical-milestones-three-new-workgroups-including-chisel-and-the-3rd-chisel-community-conference/</guid><description>SAN FRANCISCO, Nov. 7, 2019 — CHIPS Alliance, the leading consortium advancing common, open hardware for interfaces, processors and systems, today announced the creation of Interconnects, Rocket and Chisel workgroups. In addition, a November verification workshop in Munich and a Chisel conference in January will be held giving engineers an opportunity to learn about open source development efforts in CHIPS Alliance. Lastly, the CHIPS Alliance toolchain and cores workgroups have made contributions to open source development tools.</description></item><item><title>CHIPS Alliance growth continues with new members and design workshop this November</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/192/news/chips-alliance-growth-continues-with-new-members-and-design-workshop-this-november/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/192/news/chips-alliance-growth-continues-with-new-members-and-design-workshop-this-november/</guid><description>SAN FRANCISCO, Oct. 15, 2019 /PRNewswire/ — CHIPS Alliance, the leading consortium advancing common, open hardware for interfaces, processors and systems, today announced Codasip GmbH and Munich University of Applied Science have joined the CHIPS Alliance. In addition, on November 14–15, CHIPS Alliance will be joining the university for a workshop on open source design verification.
CHIPS Alliance is a project hosted by the Linux Foundation to foster a collaborative environment to accelerate the creation and deployment of open SoCs, peripherals and software tools for use in mobile, computing, consumer electronics, and Internet of Things (IoT) applications.</description></item><item><title>CHIPS Alliance featured in All About Circuits</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/192/news/chips-alliance-featured-in-all-about-circuits/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/192/news/chips-alliance-featured-in-all-about-circuits/</guid><description>All About Circuits recently featured an interview with Ted Marena, Yunsup Lee, Amir Salek, and Zvonimir Bandic, discussing the formation of the CHIPS Alliance, its relationship to the RISC-V Foundation, the CHIPS Alliance’s open development model, and initial open source contributions.
Read the article.</description></item><item><title>CHIPS Alliance Builds Momentum and Community with Newest Members Imperas Software and Metrics</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/192/news/chips-alliance-builds-momentum-and-community-with-newest-members-imperas-software-and-metrics/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/192/news/chips-alliance-builds-momentum-and-community-with-newest-members-imperas-software-and-metrics/</guid><description>Imperas and Metrics joining CHIPS Alliance to help drive the verification of RISC-V Open ISA implementations
SAN FRANCISCO – June 18, 2019 – CHIPS Alliance, the leading consortium advancing common, open hardware for interfaces, processors and systems, today announced Imperas and Metrics are joining the organization and the Verification Working Group. Imperas is an independent provider of processor simulation technology and tools for virtual platforms and analysis tools for multicore SoC software development.</description></item><item><title>CHIPS Alliance to Reveal Project Details, Strategy and Roadmap at Inaugural Workshop Hosted at Google</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/192/news/chips-alliance-to-reveal-project-details-strategy-and-roadmap-at-inaugural-workshop-hosted-at-google/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/192/news/chips-alliance-to-reveal-project-details-strategy-and-roadmap-at-inaugural-workshop-hosted-at-google/</guid><description>SAN FRANCISCO – May 7, 2019 – CHIPS Alliance, the leading consortium advancing common, open hardware for interfaces, processors and systems, today announced it is holding its inaugural workshop on June 19, 2019 at Google at 111 W. Java Drive, Sunnyvale, Calif.
Project details, strategy and roadmaps will be presented by member companies, and attendees will have an opportunity to propose Register Transfer Level (RTL) projects and development flow ideas. The workshop will focus on open source hardware, software tools, RTL development, design verification tools and related topics.</description></item><item><title>Open Hardware Group – CHIPS Alliance – Building Momentum and Community with Newest Member Antmicro</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/192/news/open-hardware-group-chips-alliance-building-momentum-and-community-with-newest-member-antmicro/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/192/news/open-hardware-group-chips-alliance-building-momentum-and-community-with-newest-member-antmicro/</guid><description>Antmicro Joins CHIPS Alliance to develop open source cores, IP blocks and tools for CPUs, RISC-V-based SoCs and peripherals
SAN FRANCISCO – April 18, 2019 – CHIPS Alliance, the leading consortium advancing common, open hardware for interfaces, processors and systems, today announced Antmicro is joining the organization. Antmicro is a software-driven technology company focused on introducing open source into strategic areas of industry, especially edge AI. Announced just last month, the CHIPS Alliance welcomes Antmicro among its initial members Esperanto Technologies, Google, SiFive, and Western Digital.</description></item><item><title>Linux Foundation to Host CHIPS Alliance Project to Propel Industry Innovation Through Open Source CPU Chip and SoC Design</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/192/news/linux-foundation-to-host-chips-alliance-project-to-propel-industry-innovation-through-open-source-cpu-chip-and-soc-design/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/192/news/linux-foundation-to-host-chips-alliance-project-to-propel-industry-innovation-through-open-source-cpu-chip-and-soc-design/</guid><description>New Linux Foundation Project to Foster Flexible, Next-Generation Chip Design for Diverse Data-Centric Applications and Workloads
SAN FRANCISCO – March 11, 2019 – The Linux Foundation, the nonprofit organization enabling mass innovation through open source, today announced its intent to form the CHIPS Alliance project to host and curate high-quality open source code relevant to the design of silicon devices. CHIPS Alliance will foster a collaborative environment that will enable accelerated creation and deployment of more efficient and flexible chip designs for use in mobile, computing, consumer electronics, and Internet of Things (IoT) applications.</description></item></channel></rss>