<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Openprot on CHIPS Alliance</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/207/tags/openprot/</link><description>Recent content in Openprot on CHIPS Alliance</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://chipsalliance.org/preview/207/tags/openprot/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>CHIPS Alliance - Our Vision and Priorities for 2026</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/207/news/2026-vision/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/207/news/2026-vision/</guid><description>&lt;p>Dear CHIPS Alliance Community,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As we approach 2026, the CHIPS Alliance is evolving. Over the past few years, we have grown from a collection of ambitious projects into a central hub for open-source silicon innovation. Our vision for 2026 is centered on &lt;strong>sustainability, technical rigor, and established trust&lt;/strong>. We are transitioning from an incubation phase to a mature, community-driven ecosystem focused on high-quality, verifiable IP and robust tooling for design and validation enablement.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>CHIPS Alliance 2025- A Year of Breakthroughs in Open Silicon and the Road Ahead</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/207/news/2025-recap/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/207/news/2025-recap/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>Author: Rob Mains, Executive Director of CHIPS Alliance&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>CHIPS Alliance is a six-year-old organization that is part of the Linux Foundation, whose mission is to foster collaborative, open source development in the silicon hardware design ecosystem. CHIPS champions all aspects of hardware development including:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Chip design architecture&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Electronic design automation for design entry, design verification, and physical implementation&lt;/li>
&lt;li>FPGA tools&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Repository of chip designs and verification design benches&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Firmware&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Artificial intelligence and chip design&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>