<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Skywater on CHIPS Alliance</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/208/tags/skywater/</link><description>Recent content in Skywater on CHIPS Alliance</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 05 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://chipsalliance.org/preview/208/tags/skywater/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Joint Analog Workgroup / MOS-AK Panel Session</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/208/news/joint-analog-workgroup-mos-ak-panel-session/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/208/news/joint-analog-workgroup-mos-ak-panel-session/</guid><description>&lt;p>Please join us for a special joint panel webinar session for the CHIPS Alliance Analog Workgroup and MOS-AK Foundation.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This panel will feature speakers with 20 minute talks on the following topic areas:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="mailto:mehdi@umich.edu">@Mehdi Saligane&lt;/a> : Introduction to the open source EDA tool flow for IC design (with reference to [1])&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="mailto:nmakris@gmail.com">@Makris Nikolaos&lt;/a> : EKV3 in NGSPICE using ADMSXL&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="mailto:erkeite@sandia.gov">@Keiter, Eric R&lt;/a> : Xyce and its support for commercial (hSpice/spectre) libs/syntax&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="mailto:tim@efabless.com">@Tim Edwards&lt;/a> : his work on the SkyWater 130 nm compatibility with ngspice&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="mailto:cameron.eda@gmail.com">@Kevin Cameron&lt;/a> : update on the P1800 (SystemVerilog) AMS standardization efforts (public doc [2])
There will be time for Q &amp;amp; A after each talk and conversation after the presentation completion.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>This webinar can be accessed via the following Zoom link, and will be recorded:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Skywater</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/208/news/skywater/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/208/news/skywater/</guid><description>&lt;p>It’s great to learn that Google &lt;a href="https://www.skywatertechnology.com/skywater-receives-funding-from-dod-partners-with-google-to-facilitate-open-source-design-for-its-new-90-nm-technology-offering/">announced&lt;/a> the expansion of its partnership with &lt;a href="https://www.skywatertechnology.com/">SkyWater Technology&lt;/a>. They are working together to release an open source process design kit (PDK) for SKY90-FD, SkyWater’s commercial 90nm fully depleted silicon on insulator (FDSOI) CMOS process technology. SKY90-FD is based on MIT Lincoln Laboratory’s 90 nm commercial FDSOI technology, and enables designers to create complex integrated circuits for a diverse range of applications.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You can read more @ &lt;a href="https://opensource.googleblog.com/2022/07/SkyWater-and-Google-expand-open-source-program-to-new-90nm-technology.html">https://opensource.googleblog.com/2022/07/SkyWater-and-Google-expand-open-source-program-to-new-90nm-technology.html&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Software-driven ASIC Prototyping Using the Open Source SkyWater Shuttle</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/208/news/software-driven-asic-prototyping-using-the-open-source-skywater-shuttle/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/208/news/software-driven-asic-prototyping-using-the-open-source-skywater-shuttle/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>This post was originally published at &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/blog/2021/12/sw-driven-asics-with-skywater-shuttle/">Antmicro&lt;/a>.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The growing cost and complexity of advanced nodes, supply chain issues and demand for silicon independence mean that the ASIC design process is in need of innovation. Antmicro believes the answer to those challenges is bound to come from the software-driven, open source approach which has shaped the Internet and gave rise to modern cloud computing. Applying the methodologies of software design to ASICs is however notoriously viewed as difficult, given the closed nature of many components needed to build chips – tools, IP and process design kits, or PDKs for short, as well as the slow turnaround of manufacturing.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>SkyWater Technology Joins CHIPS Alliance to Further Efforts to Make Chip Design and Production More Accessible</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/208/news/skywater-technology-joins-chips-alliance-to-further-efforts-to-make-chip-design-and-production-more-accessible/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/208/news/skywater-technology-joins-chips-alliance-to-further-efforts-to-make-chip-design-and-production-more-accessible/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>SkyWater furthers collaboration with CHIPS Alliance members on open source shuttle projects&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>SAN FRANCISCO, Sept. 16, 2021&lt;/strong> – CHIPS Alliance, the leading consortium advancing common and open hardware for interfaces, processors and systems, today announced that &lt;a href="https://www.skywatertechnology.com/">SkyWater Technology&lt;/a> (NASDAQ: SKYT) has become a member of the organization. SkyWater provides custom development, volume manufacturing and advanced packaging services for a wide range of silicon, including solutions based on the free and open RISC-V instruction set architecture (ISA).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>New MPW-TWO Program Will Provide Fabrication For Fully Open Source Projects</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/208/news/new-mpw-two-program/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/208/news/new-mpw-two-program/</guid><description>&lt;p>CHIPS Alliance is excited to announce that the hardware development community can submit their open source design projects to Efabless.com for space on their forthcoming shuttle. This opportunity comes after the success of having 40 submissions for the MPW-ONE shuttle; 60% of those designs were submitted by first-time ASIC designers. &lt;a href="https://efabless.com/open_shuttle_program/2">MPW-TWO&lt;/a> is the second Open MPW Shuttle providing fabrication for fully open-source projects using the SkyWater Open Source PDK announced by Google and SkyWater.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Open Source Process Design Kit from Google, SkyWater Technologies and Partners Released</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/208/news/open-source-process-design-kit-from-google-skywater-technologies-and-partners-released/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/208/news/open-source-process-design-kit-from-google-skywater-technologies-and-partners-released/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>This post was originally published at &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/blog/2020/06/skywater-open-source-pdk/">Antmicro&lt;/a>.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The ASIC design and manufacturing flow has for a long time been dominated by proprietary tools and processes. The growing complexity of chip-building has been reinforcing the claim that “hardware is too hard to be open source”, as the cost and time needed to build an ASIC have kept small, more agile, software-oriented teams and individuals away from the hardware domain. Thus, ASICs have not been able to benefit from the enthusiasm and collaboration which have been fuelling software development for decades now. Thanks to the continued effort of many entities which Antmicro is very proud to be among, this is now changing quickly.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>