<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>veer on CHIPS Alliance</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/194/tags/veer/</link><description>Recent content in veer on CHIPS Alliance</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 22 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://chipsalliance.org/preview/194/tags/veer/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Generating interactive coverage dashboards for VeeR and Caliptra with Coverview</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/194/news/coverage-dashboards-for-veer-and-caliptra/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/194/news/coverage-dashboards-for-veer-and-caliptra/</guid><description>Code coverage is a useful metric to keep track of while developing test suites, providing engineering teams with an actionable overview of how broad their testing goes. This is true both for executable code and digital design, but the different nature of RTL and software execution requires developers to look at different types of coverage information. On top of tracking executed code lines and visited branches, RTL coverage will also need to include information e.</description></item><item><title>Open source and CI-driven RTL testing and verification for Caliptra’s RISC-V VeeR core</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/194/news/open-source-rtl-ci-testing-and-verification-for-caliptra-veer/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/194/news/open-source-rtl-ci-testing-and-verification-for-caliptra-veer/</guid><description>As part of CHIPS Alliance’s mission to enable a software-driven approach to silicon, working with Google and other CHIPS members, Antmicro has been developing and improving a growing number of open source tools to enable effective, CI-driven silicon development.
Fully reproducible and scalable workflows based on open source tooling are especially beneficial for efforts spanning across multiple industrial and academic actors such as Caliptra, a Root of Trust project driven by Google, AMD, NVIDIA and Microsoft which recently joined CHIPS in order to host the ongoing development and provide the necessary structure, working environment and support for the reference implementation of the standard, originally hosted by Open Compute Project.</description></item></channel></rss>