<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Blog on CHIPS Alliance</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/categories/blog/</link><description>Recent content in Blog on CHIPS Alliance</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 05 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://chipsalliance.org/categories/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Joint Analog Workgroup / MOS-AK Panel Session</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/news/joint-analog-workgroup-mos-ak-panel-session/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/news/joint-analog-workgroup-mos-ak-panel-session/</guid><description>Please join us for a special joint panel webinar session for the CHIPS Alliance Analog Workgroup and MOS-AK Foundation.
This panel will feature speakers with 20 minute talks on the following topic areas:
@Mehdi Saligane : Introduction to the open source EDA tool flow for IC design (with reference to [1]) @Makris Nikolaos : EKV3 in NGSPICE using ADMSXL @Keiter, Eric R : Xyce and its support for commercial (hSpice/spectre) libs/syntax @Tim Edwards : his work on the SkyWater 130 nm compatibility with ngspice @Kevin Cameron : update on the P1800 (SystemVerilog) AMS standardization efforts (public doc [2]) There will be time for Q &amp;amp; A after each talk and conversation after the presentation completion.</description></item><item><title>F4PGA open source flow gets a new Python-based build system and CLI tool</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/news/f4pga-open-source-flow-gets-a-new-python-based-build-system-and-cli-tool/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/news/f4pga-open-source-flow-gets-a-new-python-based-build-system-and-cli-tool/</guid><description>One of the most recent projects developed within the workgroup is the unified f4pga CLI tool. In the broader context of our continuous efforts to make the FPGA space more unified and flexible, creating the f4pga CLI tool was a logical next step – it allowed us to wrap the underlying tools into a single CLI, making the F4PGA toolchain a more complete flow. The currently supported architectures are AMD’s (former Xilinx) 7 Series, Lattice’s iCE40 and QuickLogic’s EOS S3.</description></item><item><title>Skywater</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/news/skywater/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/news/skywater/</guid><description>It’s great to learn that Google announced the expansion of its partnership with SkyWater Technology. They are working together to release an open source process design kit (PDK) for SKY90-FD, SkyWater’s commercial 90nm fully depleted silicon on insulator (FDSOI) CMOS process technology. SKY90-FD is based on MIT Lincoln Laboratory’s 90 nm commercial FDSOI technology, and enables designers to create complex integrated circuits for a diverse range of applications.
You can read more @ https://opensource.</description></item><item><title>Antmicro DDR5 Rowhammer Testing Framework</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/news/1212/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/news/1212/</guid><description>CHIPS Alliance is excited by the Antmicro announcement of the extensible, open, Rowhammer testing framework for DDR5. Read a detailed description of their work here: https://antmicro.com/blog/2022/08/extending-the-open-source-rowhammer-testing-framework-to-ddr5/
Here are some graphics of the work:</description></item><item><title>Enhanced System Verilog Support for Yosys via Antmicro plug-in</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/news/enhanced-system-verilog-support-for-yosys-via-antmicro-plug-in/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/news/enhanced-system-verilog-support-for-yosys-via-antmicro-plug-in/</guid><description>CHIPS Alliance is pleased to see the announcement by Antmicro for its development and contribution to the open source hardware community to provide a easy to use plug-in for any version of Yosys to allow import of System Verilog based designs. This development is made possible by the underlying utilization of the Unified Hardware Data Model (UHDM), a key open source data representation upon which EDA applications can be built. Details can be seen here from Antmicro: https://antmicro.</description></item><item><title>Towards UVM: Using Coroutines for Low-overhead Dynamic Scheduling in Verilator</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/news/towards-uvm-using-coroutines/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/news/towards-uvm-using-coroutines/</guid><description>This post was originally published at Antmicro.
Verilator is a popular open source SystemVerilog simulator and one of the key tools in the ASIC and FPGA ecosystem, which Antmicro is actively using and developing, e.g. by enabling co-simulation with Renode or Cocotb integration. It’s also one of the fastest available HDL simulators, including proprietary alternatives. It achieves that speed by generating highly optimized C++ code from a given hardware design. Verilator does a lot of work at compile-time to make the generated (‘verilated’) code extremely fast, such as ordering statements in an optimal way.</description></item><item><title>SATA Design Implementation on FPGAs with Open Source Tools</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/news/sata-design-implementation-on-fpgas-with-open-source-tools/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/news/sata-design-implementation-on-fpgas-with-open-source-tools/</guid><description>This post was originally published at Antmicro.
Real-world FPGAs designs often require high rate transmission protocols such as PCIe, USB and SATA which rely on high speed transceivers for external communication. These protocols are used to interface with various devices such as graphics cards and storage devices, and many of our clients reach out to us specifically because they need the flexibility, high-throughput and low-latency characteristics of FPGAs.
In particular, for customers that deal with high data volumes (which is very common in video applications), implementing SATA to communicate and transfer data with e.</description></item><item><title>Open Source FPGA Platform for Rowhammer Security Testing in the Data Center</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/news/open-source-fpga-platform-for-rowhammer-security-testing-in-the-data-center/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/news/open-source-fpga-platform-for-rowhammer-security-testing-in-the-data-center/</guid><description>This post was originally published at Antmicro.
Our work together with Google and the world’s research community on detecting and mitigating the Rowhammer problem in DRAM memories has been proving that the challenge is far from being solved and a lot of systems are still vulnerable. The DDR Rowhammer testing framework that we developed together with an open hardware LPDDR4 DRAM tester board has been used to detect new attack methods such as Half-Double and Blacksmith and all data seems to suggest this more such methods will be discovered with time.</description></item><item><title>Software-driven ASIC Prototyping Using the Open Source SkyWater Shuttle</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/news/software-driven-asic-prototyping-using-the-open-source-skywater-shuttle/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/news/software-driven-asic-prototyping-using-the-open-source-skywater-shuttle/</guid><description>This post was originally published at Antmicro.
The growing cost and complexity of advanced nodes, supply chain issues and demand for silicon independence mean that the ASIC design process is in need of innovation. Antmicro believes the answer to those challenges is bound to come from the software-driven, open source approach which has shaped the Internet and gave rise to modern cloud computing. Applying the methodologies of software design to ASICs is however notoriously viewed as difficult, given the closed nature of many components needed to build chips – tools, IP and process design kits, or PDKs for short, as well as the slow turnaround of manufacturing.</description></item><item><title>Open Source Debayerization Blocks in FPGA</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/news/open-source-debayerization-blocks-in-fpga/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/news/open-source-debayerization-blocks-in-fpga/</guid><description>This post was originally published at Antmicro.
In modern digital camera systems, the captured image undergoes a complex process involving various image signal processing (ISP) techniques to reproduce the observed scene as accurately as possible while preserving bandwidth. On the most basic level, most CCD and CMOS image sensors use the Bayer pattern filter, where 50% of the pixels are green, 25% are red and 25% are blue (corresponding to the increased sensitivity of the human eye to the green color).</description></item></channel></rss>