<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Fpga on CHIPS Alliance</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/209/tags/fpga/</link><description>Recent content in Fpga on CHIPS Alliance</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://chipsalliance.org/preview/209/tags/fpga/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>New revision of Data Center RDIMM DDR5 Tester</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/209/news/new-revision-of-data-center-rdimm-ddr5-tester/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/209/news/new-revision-of-data-center-rdimm-ddr5-tester/</guid><description>&lt;p>A few years back, Antmicro introduced the first DDR5 capable platform to the open source &lt;a href="https://github.com/antmicro/rowhammer-tester">FPGA-based Rowhammer research framework&lt;/a> developed in cooperation with Google - the &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/blog/2022/08/extending-the-open-source-rowhammer-testing-framework-to-ddr5/">Data Center RDIMM DDR5 Tester&lt;/a>. The follow-on &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/blog/2024/02/versatile-so-dimm-lpddr5-rowhammer-testing-platform/">SO-DIMM (LP)DDR5 Tester&lt;/a> later extended the framework’s coverage to both SO-DIMM DDR5 modules and LPDDR5.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In this article, Antmicro introduces and provides an overview of a &lt;a href="https://github.com/antmicro/rdimm-ddr5-tester">new revision of the RDIMM DDR5 Tester&lt;/a> employing a more recent &lt;a href="https://designer.antmicro.com/hardware/devices/amd-xilinx-xcau25p-2ffvb676i">AMD Artix UltraScale+ XCAU25P&lt;/a> FPGA as compared to Kintex-7 series used in the previous revision. Artix UltraScale+ is a next-gen series of AMD (Xilinx) FPGAs with higher density of logic cells, higher I/O bandwidth, as well as more High Performance (HP) I/Os with a broader operating voltage range - all of which translate to concrete benefits for the platform, described below.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Topwrap – open source toolkit for modular, parameterizable digital logic design</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/209/news/topwrap/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/209/news/topwrap/</guid><description>&lt;p>ASIC and FPGA designs consist of distinct blocks of logic bound together by a top-level design. Taking advantage of this modularity and enabling automation and reuse of blocks across designs requires tools for automated processing and generation of top level files, letting you easily parametrize and aggregate the blocks in various configurations.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To this end, Antmicro created &lt;a href="https://github.com/antmicro/topwrap">Topwrap&lt;/a>, an open source toolkit for connecting individual HDL modules into full designs of varying complexity. The toolkit is designed to take advantage of the ever-growing library of open source digital logic blocks that they also &lt;a href="https://github.com/chipsalliance/i3c-core">heavily contribute to&lt;/a> and, thanks to its structuredness, offers a user-friendly graphical interface sitting on top of a well-formed CLI. This in turn lets you mix-and-match high-level GUI-driven design with more fine-grained CLI-level adjustments and present designs in the form of a diagram thanks to the integration with Antmicro’s &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/blog/2024/02/add-web-based-guis-with-pipeline-manager/">Pipeline Manager&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Versatile SO-DIMM (LP)DDR5 Rowhammer testing platform</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/209/news/versatile-rowhammer-testing-platform/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/209/news/versatile-rowhammer-testing-platform/</guid><description>&lt;p>Ten years after the &lt;a href="https://users.ece.cmu.edu/~yoonguk/papers/kim-isca14.pdf">first disclosure of the initial Rowhammer security exploit&lt;/a>, new DRAM vulnerabilities continue to be discovered, and developing new and efficient mitigation techniques requires a deep understanding of the problem considering the complexity of modern DRAM. To safeguard its Data Center and edge device use cases, Google has been using Antmicro’s advanced R&amp;amp;D capabilities to develop an &lt;a href="https://github.com/antmicro/rowhammer-tester">open source FPGA-based memory testing suite&lt;/a> and family of open hardware platforms, expanding beyond the capabilities of pure-software vulnerability testing and mitigation approaches. The targeted DDR variants have so far included &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/blog/2021/04/lpddr4-test-platform/">LPDDR4&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/blog/2021/12/open-source-data-center-rowhammer-tester/">DDR4&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/blog/2022/08/extending-the-open-source-rowhammer-testing-framework-to-ddr5/">DDR5 RDIMM&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>SATA Design Implementation on FPGAs with Open Source Tools</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/209/news/sata-design-implementation-on-fpgas-with-open-source-tools/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/209/news/sata-design-implementation-on-fpgas-with-open-source-tools/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>This post was originally published at &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/blog/2021/12/sata-with-open-source-fpga-tools/">Antmicro&lt;/a>.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Real-world FPGAs designs often require high rate transmission protocols such as PCIe, USB and SATA which rely on high speed transceivers for external communication. These protocols are used to interface with various devices such as graphics cards and storage devices, and many of our clients reach out to us specifically because they need the &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/technologies/fpga/">flexibility, high-throughput and low-latency characteristics of FPGAs&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In particular, for customers that deal with high data volumes (which is very common in video applications), implementing SATA to communicate and transfer data with e.g. an SSD hard drive is a must.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Open Source Debayerization Blocks in FPGA</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/209/news/open-source-debayerization-blocks-in-fpga/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/209/news/open-source-debayerization-blocks-in-fpga/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>This post was originally published at &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/blog/2021/10/debayerization-blocks-in-fpga/">Antmicro&lt;/a>.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/platforms/custom-camera-platforms/">modern digital camera systems&lt;/a>, the captured image undergoes a complex process involving various image signal processing (ISP) techniques to reproduce the observed scene as accurately as possible while preserving bandwidth. On the most basic level, most CCD and CMOS image sensors use the Bayer pattern filter, where 50% of the pixels are green, 25% are red and 25% are blue (corresponding to the increased sensitivity of the human eye to the green color). &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Demosaicing">Demosaicing&lt;/a>, also known as debayering, is an important part of any ISP pipeline whereby an algorithm reconstructs the missing RGB components/channels of each pixel by performing interpolation of the values collected for individual pixels.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Recap of the Fall 2021 CHIPS Alliance Workshop</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/209/news/recap-of-the-fall-2021-chips-alliance-workshop-rob-mains-chips-alliance/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/209/news/recap-of-the-fall-2021-chips-alliance-workshop-rob-mains-chips-alliance/</guid><description>&lt;p>We recently held our fall 2021 CHIPS Alliance workshop with nearly 160 attendees present for informative seminars covering a range of topics including porting Android to RISC-V, open source ASIC design and FPGA tooling, and OmniXtend. In case you missed the talks, a replay is available &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=auXZdPwYs10">on the CHIPS Alliance YouTube channel&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>During the seminar, we had eight exciting technical presentations, including:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="porting-android-chips_alliance-slides-v1.2-Han-Mao.pdf">Porting Android to RISC-V&lt;/a> – Guoyin Chen and Han Mao, Alibaba&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="Practical-Adoption-of-Open-Source-System-Verilog-Tools-CHIPS-Fall-Workshop-Michael-Gielda.pdf">Practical Adoption of Open Source SystemVerilog Tools&lt;/a> – Michael Gielda, Antmicro&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="ChiselTalk_ChipsAlliance_2021_October-Jack-Koenig.pdf">Chisel and FIRRTL for Next-Generation SoC Designs&lt;/a> – Jack Koenig, SiFive&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="OpenFASOC_-Open-Source-Fully-Autonomous-SoC-Synthesis-using-Customizable-Cell-Based-Synthesizable-Analog-Circuits-CHIPS-Alliance-Mehdi-Saligane.pdf">OpenFASOC: Automated Open Source Analog and Mixed-Signals IC Generation&lt;/a> – Mehdi Saligane, University of Michigan (UMICH)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="FPGA-Tooling-Interoperability-with-the-FPGA-Interchange-Format-Maciej-Kurc.pdf">FPGA Tooling Interoperability with the FPGA Interchange Format&lt;/a> – Maciej Kurc, Antmicro&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="OXLPC_ChipsAlliance-Jaco-Hofmann.pdf">OmniXtend: Scalability and LPC&lt;/a> – Jaco Hofmann, Western Digital Corporation&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="Open-Source-NVME-IP-with-AI-Acceleration-Karol-Gugala.pdf">Open Source NVME IP with AI Acceleration&lt;/a> – Anand Kulkarni, Western Digital Corporation and Karol Gugala, Antmicro&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="2021-10-CHIPS_Alliance-Sachin-Sapatnekar.pdf">Automating Analog Layout using ALIGN&lt;/a> – Sachin Sapatnekar, University of Minnesota (UMN)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Each of these talks provided informative, technical details of key aspects of the work underway by members of CHIPS Alliance who are working in an open, collaborative fashion. Of particular interest are the following topic areas:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Modular, Open-source FPGA-based LPDDR4 Test Platform</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/209/news/modular-open-source-fpga-based-lpddr4-test-platform/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/209/news/modular-open-source-fpga-based-lpddr4-test-platform/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>This post was originally published at &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/blog/2021/04/lpddr4-test-platform/">Antmicro&lt;/a>.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The flexibility of FPGAs makes them an excellent choice not only for parallel processing applications but also for research and experimentation in a range of technological areas.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We often provide our customers with flexible R&amp;amp;D platforms that can be easily adapted to changing requirements and new use cases as a result of our practice of using open source hardware, software, FPGA IP and tooling.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>QuickLogic Joins CHIPS Alliance to Expand Open Source FPGA Efforts</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/209/news/quicklogic-joins-chips-alliance-to-expand-open-source-fpga-efforts/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/209/news/quicklogic-joins-chips-alliance-to-expand-open-source-fpga-efforts/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>QuickLogic to present at the virtual CHIPS Alliance Workshop on Sept. 17&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>SAN FRANCISCO, Aug. 11, 2020&lt;/strong> – CHIPS Alliance, the leading consortium advancing common and open hardware for interfaces, processors and systems, today announced that QuickLogic Corporation (NASDAQ: QUIK), a developer of ultra-low power multi-core voice-enabled SoCs, embedded FPGA IP, and Endpoint AI solutions, has joined as its newest member.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>“Over the past few years the electronics industry has seen a big shift towards open source hardware and software, and we’re proud to be one of the companies at the forefront of that movement,” said Brian Faith, president and CEO at QuickLogic. “We have already been working closely with several CHIPS Alliance members to make FPGA tools and devices more accessible, and we look forward to continuing these efforts as an official member of the organization.”&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>