<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>fpga on CHIPS Alliance</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/184/tags/fpga/</link><description>Recent content in fpga on CHIPS Alliance</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://chipsalliance.org/preview/184/tags/fpga/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>New revision of Data Center RDIMM DDR5 Tester</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/184/news/new-revision-of-data-center-rdimm-ddr5-tester/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/184/news/new-revision-of-data-center-rdimm-ddr5-tester/</guid><description>A few years back, Antmicro introduced the first DDR5 capable platform to the open source FPGA-based Rowhammer research framework developed in cooperation with Google - the Data Center RDIMM DDR5 Tester. The follow-on SO-DIMM (LP)DDR5 Tester later extended the framework’s coverage to both SO-DIMM DDR5 modules and LPDDR5.
In this article, Antmicro introduces and provides an overview of a new revision of the RDIMM DDR5 Tester employing a more recent AMD Artix UltraScale+ XCAU25P FPGA as compared to Kintex-7 series used in the previous revision.</description></item><item><title>Topwrap – open source toolkit for modular, parameterizable digital logic design</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/184/news/topwrap/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/184/news/topwrap/</guid><description>ASIC and FPGA designs consist of distinct blocks of logic bound together by a top-level design. Taking advantage of this modularity and enabling automation and reuse of blocks across designs requires tools for automated processing and generation of top level files, letting you easily parametrize and aggregate the blocks in various configurations.
To this end, Antmicro created Topwrap, an open source toolkit for connecting individual HDL modules into full designs of varying complexity.</description></item><item><title>Versatile SO-DIMM (LP)DDR5 Rowhammer testing platform</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/184/news/versatile-rowhammer-testing-platform/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/184/news/versatile-rowhammer-testing-platform/</guid><description>Ten years after the first disclosure of the initial Rowhammer security exploit, new DRAM vulnerabilities continue to be discovered, and developing new and efficient mitigation techniques requires a deep understanding of the problem considering the complexity of modern DRAM. To safeguard its Data Center and edge device use cases, Google has been using Antmicro’s advanced R&amp;amp;D capabilities to develop an open source FPGA-based memory testing suite and family of open hardware platforms, expanding beyond the capabilities of pure-software vulnerability testing and mitigation approaches.</description></item><item><title>Modular, Open-source FPGA-based LPDDR4 Test Platform</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/184/news/modular-open-source-fpga-based-lpddr4-test-platform/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/184/news/modular-open-source-fpga-based-lpddr4-test-platform/</guid><description>This post was originally published at Antmicro.
The flexibility of FPGAs makes them an excellent choice not only for parallel processing applications but also for research and experimentation in a range of technological areas.
We often provide our customers with flexible R&amp;amp;D platforms that can be easily adapted to changing requirements and new use cases as a result of our practice of using open source hardware, software, FPGA IP and tooling.</description></item></channel></rss>