<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Risc-V on CHIPS Alliance</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/206/tags/risc-v/</link><description>Recent content in Risc-V on CHIPS Alliance</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://chipsalliance.org/preview/206/tags/risc-v/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Constrained randomization in Verilator</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/206/news/constrained-randomization-verilator/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/206/news/constrained-randomization-verilator/</guid><description>&lt;p>Digital design verification often utilizes the so-called constrained randomization functionality offered by SystemVerilog, where in order to efficiently test designs with random but still correct data, a digital logic designer can put constraints in place. This allows verification tests to run shorter by focusing the validation of the design’s behavior on input that the designer considers useful and interesting.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A few months ago Antmicro &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/blog/2024/03/introducing-constrained-randomization-in-verilator/">introduced constrained randomization to Verilator&lt;/a> - another significant milestone on the way towards full open source support for SystemVerilog and industry-prevalent &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/blog/2023/10/running-simple-uvm-testbenches-in-verilator/">UVM testbenches&lt;/a>. This work has been highly anticipated by many industrial users and is allowing Antmicro to slowly but steadily adopt Verilator for UVM-style verification in their state of the art silicon development work like CHIPS Alliance’s &lt;a href="https://github.com/chipsalliance/Caliptra">Caliptra Root of Trust&lt;/a> project.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Caliptra - Support for VeeR EL2 with User Mode and Physical Memory Protection in Tock embedded OS</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/206/news/caliptra-support-for-veer/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/206/news/caliptra-support-for-veer/</guid><description>&lt;p>The &lt;a href="https://chipsalliance.github.io/Caliptra/">Caliptra&lt;/a> Root of Trust project, a collaboration between AMD, Google, Microsoft and NVIDIA within the &lt;a href="https://www.chipsalliance.org/">CHIPS Alliance&lt;/a>, is steadily heading towards its &lt;a href="https://www.chipsalliance.org/news/caliptra-ocp-global-summit-2024/">2.0 release&lt;/a> – an effort Antmicro is &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=hXjUoCGlXyM">actively contributing to&lt;/a>. They’ve recently described their &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/blog/2024/09/user-mode-in-veer-el2-core-for-caliptra-2-0/">implementation of User mode&lt;/a> in the RISC-V VeeR EL2 core along with extended Physical Memory Protection, and related to this work, they’ve introduced support for VeeR EL2 with User Mode and PMP to the &lt;a href="https://github.com/tock/tock">Tock&lt;/a> embedded OS. The main goal of this implementation was to test the mode switching feature of the VeeR EL2 core with PMP enabled.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Caliptra @ OCP Global Summit 2024</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/206/news/caliptra-ocp-global-summit-2024/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/206/news/caliptra-ocp-global-summit-2024/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">Introduction&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>As we continue to advance the field of hardware security, we are thrilled to celebrate the successful integration of Caliptra 1.x by our esteemed partners. Their commitment to enhancing security through the adoption of our open-source Root of Trust (RoT) is a testament to the collaborative spirit of the Open Compute Project (OCP). In this post, we also look ahead to the exciting developments planned for Caliptra 2.0.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="recognizing-caliptra-1x-integrators">Recognizing Caliptra 1.x Integrators&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>We are proud to recognize the following companies for their successful integration of Caliptra 1.x into their products. Each integrator has demonstrated a strong commitment to security, transparency, and innovation. Click on the company names to read their detailed blog posts about their integration of Caliptra:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Catch us at DAC 59 in San Francisco starting July 11</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/206/news/catch-us-at-dac-59-in-san-francisco-starting-july-11/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/206/news/catch-us-at-dac-59-in-san-francisco-starting-july-11/</guid><description>&lt;p>Come learn about open source hardware and CHIPS Alliance at next week’s 59th Design Automation Conference in San Francisco. We will be at kiosk 2344 in the RISC-V pavilion. You can also here out talk at 12:30 Monday in the Open Source Central Theatre (booth 2338). We are also in a DAC Pavilion Panel: Is Democratization of Chip Design Already Happening? at 2:30 on Monday. Look forward to an exciting day in SF!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How Google is Applying Machine Learning to Macro Placement</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/206/news/how-google-is-applying-machine-learning-to-macro-placement/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/206/news/how-google-is-applying-machine-learning-to-macro-placement/</guid><description>&lt;p>CHIPS Alliance’s latest Deep Dive Cafe featured an outstanding talk by a Google physical design engineer, Young-Joon Lee, who has a PhD from Georgia Tech, and has been working on machine learning physical design projects for the past two years.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The chip placement problem is a notoriously challenging design problem, and has been explored in the electronic design automation research and development community for years. For those unfamiliar with the problem, it involves finding the optimal placement of physical cells implementing the logical function on a chip image to minimize performance, power, and area of the silicon, which in the end affects the cost of the product. The effort by Google to apply machine learning to the placement problem started as part of the Google Brain effort, which in part focuses on running algorithms at scale on large amounts of data.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Improving the OpenLane ASIC Build Flow with Open Source SystemVerilog Support</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/206/news/improving-the-openlane-asic-build-flow-with-open-source-systemverilog-support/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/206/news/improving-the-openlane-asic-build-flow-with-open-source-systemverilog-support/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>This post was originally published at &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/blog/2021/10/openlane-asic-build-flow-with-systemverliog-support/">Antmicro&lt;/a>.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Open source toolchains are key to building collaborative ecosystems, welcoming to new approaches, opportunistic/focused innovations and niche use cases. The ASIC design domain, especially in the view of the rising tensions around manufacturing and supply chains, are in dire need of a software-driven innovation based on an open source approach. The fledgling open source hardware ecosystem has been energized by the success of RISC-V and is now being vastly expanded to cover the entire ASIC design flow by &lt;a href="https://chipsalliance.org/">CHIPS Alliance&lt;/a>, and Antmicro has been playing a leadership role in both of these organizations as well as offering commercial engineering and support services to assist with early adoption of open source approaches in hardware.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Recap of the Fall 2021 CHIPS Alliance Workshop</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/206/news/recap-of-the-fall-2021-chips-alliance-workshop-rob-mains-chips-alliance/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/206/news/recap-of-the-fall-2021-chips-alliance-workshop-rob-mains-chips-alliance/</guid><description>&lt;p>We recently held our fall 2021 CHIPS Alliance workshop with nearly 160 attendees present for informative seminars covering a range of topics including porting Android to RISC-V, open source ASIC design and FPGA tooling, and OmniXtend. In case you missed the talks, a replay is available &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=auXZdPwYs10">on the CHIPS Alliance YouTube channel&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>During the seminar, we had eight exciting technical presentations, including:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="porting-android-chips_alliance-slides-v1.2-Han-Mao.pdf">Porting Android to RISC-V&lt;/a> – Guoyin Chen and Han Mao, Alibaba&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="Practical-Adoption-of-Open-Source-System-Verilog-Tools-CHIPS-Fall-Workshop-Michael-Gielda.pdf">Practical Adoption of Open Source SystemVerilog Tools&lt;/a> – Michael Gielda, Antmicro&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="ChiselTalk_ChipsAlliance_2021_October-Jack-Koenig.pdf">Chisel and FIRRTL for Next-Generation SoC Designs&lt;/a> – Jack Koenig, SiFive&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="OpenFASOC_-Open-Source-Fully-Autonomous-SoC-Synthesis-using-Customizable-Cell-Based-Synthesizable-Analog-Circuits-CHIPS-Alliance-Mehdi-Saligane.pdf">OpenFASOC: Automated Open Source Analog and Mixed-Signals IC Generation&lt;/a> – Mehdi Saligane, University of Michigan (UMICH)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="FPGA-Tooling-Interoperability-with-the-FPGA-Interchange-Format-Maciej-Kurc.pdf">FPGA Tooling Interoperability with the FPGA Interchange Format&lt;/a> – Maciej Kurc, Antmicro&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="OXLPC_ChipsAlliance-Jaco-Hofmann.pdf">OmniXtend: Scalability and LPC&lt;/a> – Jaco Hofmann, Western Digital Corporation&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="Open-Source-NVME-IP-with-AI-Acceleration-Karol-Gugala.pdf">Open Source NVME IP with AI Acceleration&lt;/a> – Anand Kulkarni, Western Digital Corporation and Karol Gugala, Antmicro&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="2021-10-CHIPS_Alliance-Sachin-Sapatnekar.pdf">Automating Analog Layout using ALIGN&lt;/a> – Sachin Sapatnekar, University of Minnesota (UMN)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Each of these talks provided informative, technical details of key aspects of the work underway by members of CHIPS Alliance who are working in an open, collaborative fashion. Of particular interest are the following topic areas:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Listen to CHIPS Alliance’s Rob Mains on EE Journal’s FishFry Podcast</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/206/news/listen-to-chips-alliances-rob-mains-on-ee-journals-fishfry-podcast/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/206/news/listen-to-chips-alliances-rob-mains-on-ee-journals-fishfry-podcast/</guid><description>&lt;p>CHIPS Alliance’s general manager Rob Mains joined Amelia Dalton at EE Journal’s FishFry podcast for a lively discussion about how we’re working to make chip design more accessible. Rob discussed CHIPS Alliance’s work with RISC-V International to develop a new &lt;a href="https://chipsalliance.org/announcement/2021/03/24/risc-v-international-omnixtend-working-group/">unified memory standard&lt;/a>, along with our work to accelerate the design of open source chipsets with the &lt;a href="https://chipsalliance.org/announcement/2020/07/16/aib-2-0-draft-specification/">AIB 2.0 specification&lt;/a>. The conversation also touched on our efforts to provide better support for SystemVerilog using open source tools and to create a dynamic stratified scheduler implementation in Verilator.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Automatic SystemVerilog Linting in GitHub Actions with Verible</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/206/news/automatic-systemverilog-linting-in-github-actions-with-verible/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/206/news/automatic-systemverilog-linting-in-github-actions-with-verible/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>This post was originally published at &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/blog/2021/08/verible-integration-with-github-actions/">Antmicro&lt;/a>.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>With the recent advances in open source &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/blog/2021/07/open-source-systemverilog-tools-in-asic-design/">ASIC development tools&lt;/a> such as Verible, it has become easier to automate tasks and boost developer productivity. The Verible linter is a static code analysis tool that has been helping us and our collaborators to spot and fix stylistic errors and bugs in SystemVerilog code.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="cicd-for-smaller-backlog-and-better-test-reliability">CI/CD for smaller backlog and better test reliability&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>As part of our work within the newly established CHIPS Alliance SystemVerilog subgroup, Antmicro has made further steps to facilitate SystemVerilog workflows with Verible, by providing an easy to use &lt;a href="https://github.com/chipsalliance/verible-linter-action">Verible Linter GitHub Action&lt;/a>. Combined with another open source tool called &lt;a href="https://github.com/reviewdog/reviewdog">Reviewdog&lt;/a>, the action allows you to easily perform automatic code style checks and code review.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Antmicro’s ARVSOM RISC-V Module Announced</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/206/news/antmicros-arvsom-risc-v-module-announced/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/206/news/antmicros-arvsom-risc-v-module-announced/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>This post was originally published at &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/blog/2021/04/arv-som-announcement/">Antmicro&lt;/a>.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We are excited to announce the ARVSOM – Antmicro’s &lt;a href="https://github.com/antmicro/arvsom">fully open source&lt;/a>, RISC-V-based system-on-module featuring the StarFive 71×0 SoC. Using the RISC-V architecture, which Antmicro has been heavily involved in since the early days as a Founding Member of RISC-V International, the SoM is going to enable unprecedented openness, reusability and functionality across different verticals.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We are excited to announce the ARVSOM – Antmicro’s &lt;a href="https://github.com/antmicro/arvsom">fully open source&lt;/a>, RISC-V-based system-on-module featuring the StarFive 71×0 SoC. Using the RISC-V architecture, which Antmicro has been heavily involved in since the early days as a Founding Member of RISC-V International, the SoM is going to enable unprecedented openness, reusability and functionality across different verticals.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Dynamic Scheduling in Verilator – Milestone Towards Open Source UVM</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/206/news/dynamic-scheduling-in-verilator/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/206/news/dynamic-scheduling-in-verilator/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>This post was originally published at &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/blog/2021/05/dynamic-scheduling-in-verilator/">Antmicro&lt;/a>.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>UVM is a verification methodology traditionally used in chip design which has historically been missing from the open source landscape of verification-focused tooling. While new, open source approaches to verification have emerged that include the excellent Python-based Cocotb (that &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/blog/2019/12/testing-usb-cores-with-python-and-cocotb/">we also use&lt;/a> &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/blog/2019/06/verilog-with-cocotb-and-verilator/">and support&lt;/a>) maintained by &lt;a href="https://www.fossi-foundation.org/">FOSSi Foundation&lt;/a>, not everyone can easily adopt it, especially in long-running projects and existing codebases that use a different verification approach. Leading the efforts towards comprehensive UVM / SystemVerilog support in open source tools, we have been gradually completing milestones, getting closer to what will essentially be a modular, collaboration-driven chips design methodology/workflow. Some examples of our activity in this space include &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/blog/2020/12/ibex-support-in-verilator-yosys-via-uhdm-surelog/">enabling open source synthesis and simulation of the Ibex CPU&lt;/a> in &lt;a href="https://github.com/antmicro/verilator/tree/uhdm-verilator">Verilator&lt;/a>/&lt;a href="https://github.com/antmicro/yosys/tree/uhdm-yosys">Yosys&lt;/a> via UHDM/Surelog, and the most recent joint project with Western Digital in which we have developed &lt;a href="https://github.com/antmicro/verilator-dynamic-scheduler-examples">dynamic scheduling in Verilator&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>GitHub Actions Self-hosted Runners, Build Event Server and Google Cloud</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/206/news/github-actions-self-hosted-runners-build-event-server-and-google-cloud/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/206/news/github-actions-self-hosted-runners-build-event-server-and-google-cloud/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>This post was originally published at &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/blog/2021/03/github-actions-self-hosted-runners/">Antmicro&lt;/a>.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Continuous Integration and smart lifecycle management are key for high-tech product development, which is often a complex and multi-faceted process that requires automation to be efficient and failure-proof. At Antmicro, we’ve been creating various open source cloud and hybrid cloud solutions for our customers, helping them to encapsulate the complexity of their software stack. Lots of those projects cross the hardware/software boundary and involve a mix of open source and proprietary code, which means that fine-grained control of the CI setups are needed to make them work.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Goings-on in the FuseSoC Project and Other Open Source Silicon Related News</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/206/news/goings-on-in-the-fusesoc-project-and-other-open-source-silicon-related-news/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/206/news/goings-on-in-the-fusesoc-project-and-other-open-source-silicon-related-news/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>This post was originally published by &lt;a href="https://olofkindgren.blogspot.com/2021/02/fossi-fever-2020.html">Olof Kindgren&lt;/a>&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="fossi-fever-2020">FOSSi Fever 2020&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="fuckload.png" alt="">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2020 was a year with a lot of bad news and so it feels slightly strange to cheerfully write about a very specific topic in the light of this. But there will always be good and bad things happening in the world. So let’s keep fighting the bad things and for now take look at what happened last year within the amazing world of open source silicon. I will start by mentioning the most significant, but by no means the only, milestones for the FOSSi movement as a whole and then take a more personal look at the work where I have been directly involved.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>CHIPS Alliance Welcomes Antmicro and VeriSilicon to the Platinum Membership Level</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/206/news/chips-alliance-welcomes-antmicro-and-verisilicon-to-the-platinum-membership-level/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/206/news/chips-alliance-welcomes-antmicro-and-verisilicon-to-the-platinum-membership-level/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>CHIPS Alliance continues to grow with more than 25 companies collaborating on open source hardware and software technologies&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>SAN FRANCISCO, Feb. 11, 2021&lt;/strong> – CHIPS Alliance, the leading consortium advancing common and open hardware for interfaces, processors and systems, today welcomed Antmicro and VeriSilicon to the company’s Platinum membership level. Antmicro, one of the initial members of the CHIPS Alliance, has upgraded to the Platinum membership level to reflect its deepening involvement in the organization. VeriSilicon is new to the CHIPS Alliance, although the company is heavily involved in open source activities.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>High-Throughput Open Source PCIe on Xilinx VU19P-Based ASIC Prototyping Platform</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/206/news/high-throughput-open-source-pcie/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/206/news/high-throughput-open-source-pcie/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>This post was originally published at &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/blog/2021/02/high-throughput-open-source-pcie-on-xilinx-vu19/">Antmicro&lt;/a>.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In our daily work at Antmicro we use FPGAs primarily for their flexibility and parallel data processing capabilities that make them remarkably effective in advanced vision and audio processing systems involving high-speed interfaces such as PCI Express, USB, Ethernet, HDMI, SDI etc. that we develop and integrate as open source, portable building blocks. Many of our customers, however, use FPGAs also in a different context, namely for designing ASICs, which is a highly specialized market that typically involves large FPGAs, proprietary flows and IP. In one such project, we were working with one of the largest FPGAs in production today, the 9-million LUT Xilinx VU19. Being a design with considerable complexity, it needed a high-throughput link between the FPGA and the host PC that could be thoroughly benchmarked, analyzed and optimized for the use case.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Enabling Open Source Ibex Synthesis and Simulation in Verilator/Yosys via UHDM/Surelog</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/206/news/ibex-synthesis-and-simulation/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/206/news/ibex-synthesis-and-simulation/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>This post was originally published at &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/blog/2020/12/ibex-support-in-verilator-yosys-via-uhdm-surelog/">Antmicro&lt;/a>.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Throughout 2020 we were hard at work developing proper, portable SystemVerilog support for multiple open-source FPGA and ASIC design tools used by us and our customers, most notably &lt;a href="https://github.com/YosysHQ/yosys">Yosys&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://github.com/verilator/verilator">Verilator&lt;/a>. We strongly believe that the support is a necessary step in building a collaborative ecosystem and scalable and reproducible CIs, especially publicly accessible ones that are common in multi-organization projects such as &lt;a href="https://opentitan.org/">OpenTitan&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://chipsalliance.org/">CHIPS Alliance&lt;/a>. Leading the efforts towards achieving this goal, we’ve been developing a fully open source SystemVerilog parsing flow for Yosys and Verilator using UHDM and Surelog, achieving an important milestone: being able to fully parse, synthesize and simulate OpenTitan’s Ibex core directly from the SystemVerilog source.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>CHIPS Alliance Welcomes Mentor as its Newest Member</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/206/news/chips-alliance-welcomes-mentor-as-its-newest-member/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/206/news/chips-alliance-welcomes-mentor-as-its-newest-member/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>Mentor to present at the virtual CHIPS Alliance Workshop on Sept. 17&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>SAN FRANCISCO, Aug. 18, 2020&lt;/strong> – CHIPS Alliance, the leading consortium advancing common and open hardware for interfaces, processors and systems, today announced that Mentor, a Siemens business, has joined as its newest member. The CHIPS Alliance has a roster of more than 20 members collaborating to accelerate the creation and deployment of open system-on-chips (SoCs), peripherals and software tools for a wide range of applications.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>CHIPS SweRV Cores and the Open Tools Ecosystem</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/206/news/chips-swerv-cores-and-the-open-tools-ecosystem/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/206/news/chips-swerv-cores-and-the-open-tools-ecosystem/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>This post was originally published at &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/blog/2020/07/swerv-cores-tools-ecosystem/">Antmicro&lt;/a>.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Antmicro’s open source work spans all parts of the computing stack, from software and AI, to PCBs, FPGAs and, most recently, custom silicon. We connect those areas with an overarching vision of open source tooling and methodology, and a software-driven approach that allows us to move fast and build future-centric solutions. Our partners and customers, many of whom work with us also in the context of organizations such as &lt;a href="https://chipsalliance.org/">CHIPS Alliance&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://riscv.org/">RISC-V&lt;/a>, share our approach to developing open systems. We were recently very happy to be invited to give a talk at the &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ODU1b9amCG8&amp;amp;feature=emb_title">“Production grade, open RISC-V SweRV Core Solutions in CHIPS Alliance”&lt;/a> meetup organized by Western Digital where we presented our systems approach on the example of the open source tools ecosystem that targets their SweRV cores and which we are helping to develop.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>A Look Back at the CHIPS Alliance’s Incredible Growth</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/206/news/chips-alliances-incredible-growth/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/206/news/chips-alliances-incredible-growth/</guid><description>&lt;p>It’s been just over a year since the CHIPS Alliance was founded with the mission of making open source hardware development more accessible to companies, universities and individuals. We’re working to bring the dynamics of the hugely successful open source software development model into ASIC design, building on the groundwork set by the RISC-V community. Progress over the past year is detailed in our &lt;a href="https://chipsalliance.org/chips-alliance-2020-annual-report/">Annual Report&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>CHIPS Alliance is focused on expanding on this open hardware vision by:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>CHIPS Alliance’s Newly Enhanced SweRV Cores Available to All for Free</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/206/news/newly-enhanced-swerv-cores/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/206/news/newly-enhanced-swerv-cores/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>CHIPS Alliance to host online event to help community innovating with SweRV Core EH2 and EL2 Solutions&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>SAN FRANCISCO, May 14, 2020&lt;/strong> – CHIPS Alliance, the leading consortium advancing common and open hardware for interfaces, processors and systems, today announced new enhancements to the SweRV Core™ EH2 and SweRV Core EL2, &lt;a href="https://www.westerndigital.com/company/newsroom/press-releases/2019/2019-12-10-western-digital-brings-memory-closer-to-compute-with-new-risc-v-innovations">developed&lt;/a> for the open-source community by Western Digital. Since the introduction of the cores earlier this year, the CHIPS Alliance has worked with its community to exhaustedly validate the cores through a transparent and rigorous process, as well as incorporate a variety of new updates.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>CHIPS Alliance announces technical milestones, three new workgroups including Chisel and the 3rd Chisel Community Conference</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/206/news/chips-alliance-announces-technical-milestones-three-new-workgroups-including-chisel-and-the-3rd-chisel-community-conference/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/206/news/chips-alliance-announces-technical-milestones-three-new-workgroups-including-chisel-and-the-3rd-chisel-community-conference/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>SAN FRANCISCO, Nov. 7, 2019&lt;/strong> — CHIPS Alliance, the leading consortium advancing common, open hardware for interfaces, processors and systems, today announced the creation of Interconnects, Rocket and Chisel workgroups. In addition, a November verification workshop in Munich and a Chisel conference in January will be held giving engineers an opportunity to learn about open source development efforts in CHIPS Alliance. Lastly, the CHIPS Alliance toolchain and cores workgroups have made contributions to open source development tools.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>CHIPS Alliance growth continues with new members and design workshop this November</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/206/news/chips-alliance-growth-continues-with-new-members-and-design-workshop-this-november/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/206/news/chips-alliance-growth-continues-with-new-members-and-design-workshop-this-november/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>SAN FRANCISCO, Oct. 15, 2019 /PRNewswire/&lt;/strong> — CHIPS Alliance, the leading consortium advancing common, open hardware for interfaces, processors and systems, today announced Codasip GmbH and Munich University of Applied Science have joined the CHIPS Alliance. In addition, on November 14–15, CHIPS Alliance will be joining the university for &lt;a href="https://c212.net/c/link/?t=0&amp;amp;l=en&amp;amp;o=2611936-1&amp;amp;h=3241488071&amp;amp;u=https%3A%2F%2Fchipsalliance.org%2Fworkshops-meetings%2F&amp;amp;a=workshop+on+open+source+design+verification">a workshop on open source design verification&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>CHIPS Alliance is a project hosted by the Linux Foundation to foster a collaborative environment to accelerate the creation and deployment of open SoCs, peripherals and software tools for use in mobile, computing, consumer electronics, and Internet of Things (IoT) applications. The CHIPS Alliance project develops high-quality open source Register Transfer Level (RTL) code relevant to the design of open source CPUs, RISC-V-based SoCs, and complex peripherals for Field Programmable Gate Arrays (FPGAs) and custom silicon.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>CHIPS Alliance featured in All About Circuits</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/206/news/chips-alliance-featured-in-all-about-circuits/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/206/news/chips-alliance-featured-in-all-about-circuits/</guid><description>&lt;p>All About Circuits recently featured an interview with Ted Marena, Yunsup Lee, Amir Salek, and Zvonimir Bandic, discussing the formation of the CHIPS Alliance, its relationship to the RISC-V Foundation, the CHIPS Alliance’s open development model, and initial open source contributions.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.allaboutcircuits.com/news/linux-chips-alliance-open-source-hardware-collaboration/">Read the article&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>CHIPS Alliance Builds Momentum and Community with Newest Members Imperas Software and Metrics</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/206/news/chips-alliance-builds-momentum-and-community-with-newest-members-imperas-software-and-metrics/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/206/news/chips-alliance-builds-momentum-and-community-with-newest-members-imperas-software-and-metrics/</guid><description>&lt;p>Imperas and Metrics joining CHIPS Alliance to help drive the verification of RISC-V Open ISA implementations&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>SAN FRANCISCO – June 18, 2019&lt;/strong> – CHIPS Alliance, the leading consortium advancing common, open hardware for interfaces, processors and systems, today announced Imperas and Metrics are joining the organization and the Verification Working Group. Imperas is an independent provider of processor simulation technology and tools for virtual platforms and
analysis tools for multicore SoC software development. Metrics leads the cloud-based solutions for SoC designers with hardware simulation for both design management flexibility and on-demand capacity. The CHIPS Alliance welcomes Imperas and Metrics among its current members Antmicro, Esperanto Technologies, Google, SiFive, Western Digital.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>CHIPS Alliance to Reveal Project Details, Strategy and Roadmap at Inaugural Workshop Hosted at Google</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/206/news/chips-alliance-to-reveal-project-details-strategy-and-roadmap-at-inaugural-workshop-hosted-at-google/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/206/news/chips-alliance-to-reveal-project-details-strategy-and-roadmap-at-inaugural-workshop-hosted-at-google/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>SAN FRANCISCO – May 7, 2019&lt;/strong> – CHIPS Alliance, the leading consortium advancing common, open hardware for interfaces, processors and systems, today announced it is holding its inaugural workshop on June 19, 2019 at Google at 111 W. Java Drive, Sunnyvale, Calif.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Project details, strategy and roadmaps will be presented by member companies, and attendees will have an opportunity to propose Register Transfer Level (RTL) projects and development flow ideas. The workshop will focus on open source hardware, software tools, RTL development, design verification tools and related topics. The agenda and registration details are available at &lt;a href="https://events.linuxfoundation.org/events/chips-alliance-workshop-2019">https://events.linuxfoundation.org/events/chips-alliance-workshop-2019&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Linux Foundation to Host CHIPS Alliance Project to Propel Industry Innovation Through Open Source CPU Chip and SoC Design</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/206/news/linux-foundation-to-host-chips-alliance-project-to-propel-industry-innovation-through-open-source-cpu-chip-and-soc-design/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/206/news/linux-foundation-to-host-chips-alliance-project-to-propel-industry-innovation-through-open-source-cpu-chip-and-soc-design/</guid><description>&lt;p>New Linux Foundation Project to Foster Flexible, Next-Generation Chip Design for Diverse Data-Centric Applications and Workloads&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>SAN FRANCISCO – March 11, 2019&lt;/strong> – &lt;a href="http://linuxfoundation.org/">The Linux Foundation&lt;/a>, the nonprofit organization enabling mass innovation through open source, today announced its intent to form the CHIPS Alliance project to host and curate high-quality open source code relevant to the design of silicon devices. CHIPS Alliance will foster a collaborative environment that will enable accelerated creation and deployment of more efficient and flexible chip designs for use in mobile, computing, consumer electronics, and Internet of Things (IoT) applications.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>