<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Aib on CHIPS Alliance</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/202/tags/aib/</link><description>Recent content in Aib on CHIPS Alliance</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://chipsalliance.org/preview/202/tags/aib/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Listen to CHIPS Alliance’s Rob Mains on EE Journal’s FishFry Podcast</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/202/news/listen-to-chips-alliances-rob-mains-on-ee-journals-fishfry-podcast/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/202/news/listen-to-chips-alliances-rob-mains-on-ee-journals-fishfry-podcast/</guid><description>&lt;p>CHIPS Alliance’s general manager Rob Mains joined Amelia Dalton at EE Journal’s FishFry podcast for a lively discussion about how we’re working to make chip design more accessible. Rob discussed CHIPS Alliance’s work with RISC-V International to develop a new &lt;a href="https://chipsalliance.org/announcement/2021/03/24/risc-v-international-omnixtend-working-group/">unified memory standard&lt;/a>, along with our work to accelerate the design of open source chipsets with the &lt;a href="https://chipsalliance.org/announcement/2020/07/16/aib-2-0-draft-specification/">AIB 2.0 specification&lt;/a>. The conversation also touched on our efforts to provide better support for SystemVerilog using open source tools and to create a dynamic stratified scheduler implementation in Verilator.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>A Look Back at the CHIPS Alliance’s Incredible Growth</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/202/news/chips-alliances-incredible-growth/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/202/news/chips-alliances-incredible-growth/</guid><description>&lt;p>It’s been just over a year since the CHIPS Alliance was founded with the mission of making open source hardware development more accessible to companies, universities and individuals. We’re working to bring the dynamics of the hugely successful open source software development model into ASIC design, building on the groundwork set by the RISC-V community. Progress over the past year is detailed in our &lt;a href="https://chipsalliance.org/chips-alliance-2020-annual-report/">Annual Report&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>CHIPS Alliance is focused on expanding on this open hardware vision by:&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>