<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Developer Spotlight on CHIPS Alliance</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/204/tags/developer-spotlight/</link><description>Recent content in Developer Spotlight on CHIPS Alliance</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://chipsalliance.org/preview/204/tags/developer-spotlight/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Developer Spotlight- Building Trust, Tools, and the Future of Open Silicon</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/204/news/rob-mains-spotlight/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/204/news/rob-mains-spotlight/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>In this Developer Spotlight, Rob Mains, Executive Director of CHIPS Alliance, reflects on the lessons that shaped his career, the realities of open source silicon, and what it will take to build a sustainable, production-ready open hardware ecosystem.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>From IBM to Oracle, Rob Mains has spent decades working across the full stack of silicon development. This experience has helped shape a leadership philosophy grounded in trust, respect and collaboration. At CHIPS Alliance, this perspective supports a neutral collaboration model that allows companies to jointly develop foundational technologies without blurring competitive boundaries.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Inside the Evolution of Chisel- Jack Koenig on Open Source Silicon Design at SiFive</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/204/news/spotlight-jack-koenig/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/204/news/spotlight-jack-koenig/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>From reluctant programmer to compiler maintainer, a decade-long journey shaping open source digital design tools.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Jack Koenig is a Senior Staff Engineer at SiFive and one of the longest-standing maintainers of the Chisel and FIRRTL projects.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Over the past decade, his contributions have helped shape the foundation of open source hardware description in Scala, bridging the worlds of compiler theory, HDL design, and functional programming.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In this developer spotlight, we explore Jack&amp;rsquo;s journey into open source silicon, his technical contributions, and what lies ahead for Chisel and its ecosystem.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Structuring Open Silicon - A TAC Perspective with Aaron Cunningham</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/204/news/structuring-open-silicon/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/204/news/structuring-open-silicon/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="how-a-globally-distributed-program-manager-is-helping-define-the-next-phase-of-open-source-silicon-collaboration">How a globally distributed program manager is helping define the next phase of open source silicon collaboration.&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Introduction&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Aaron Cunningham serves as Chair of the CHIPS Alliance Technical Advisory Council (TAC) and is a Technical Program Manager at Google focused on tooling, architecture, and hardware optimization. From managing infrastructure in Singapore to advocating for cross-project clarity at the Linux Foundation, Aaron brings a uniquely strategic lens to the complexities of scaling open source silicon.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>