<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>roadmap on CHIPS Alliance</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/197/tags/roadmap/</link><description>Recent content in roadmap on CHIPS Alliance</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://chipsalliance.org/preview/197/tags/roadmap/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Caliptra - Support for VeeR EL2 with User Mode and Physical Memory Protection in Tock embedded OS</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/197/news/caliptra-support-for-veer/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/197/news/caliptra-support-for-veer/</guid><description>The Caliptra Root of Trust project, a collaboration between AMD, Google, Microsoft and NVIDIA within the CHIPS Alliance, is steadily heading towards its 2.0 release – an effort Antmicro is actively contributing to. They’ve recently described their implementation of User mode in the RISC-V VeeR EL2 core along with extended Physical Memory Protection, and related to this work, they’ve introduced support for VeeR EL2 with User Mode and PMP to the Tock embedded OS.</description></item><item><title>Caliptra @ OCP Global Summit 2024</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/197/news/caliptra-ocp-global-summit-2024/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/197/news/caliptra-ocp-global-summit-2024/</guid><description>Introduction As we continue to advance the field of hardware security, we are thrilled to celebrate the successful integration of Caliptra 1.x by our esteemed partners. Their commitment to enhancing security through the adoption of our open-source Root of Trust (RoT) is a testament to the collaborative spirit of the Open Compute Project (OCP). In this post, we also look ahead to the exciting developments planned for Caliptra 2.0.
Recognizing Caliptra 1.</description></item><item><title>CHIPS Alliance to Reveal Project Details, Strategy and Roadmap at Inaugural Workshop Hosted at Google</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/197/news/chips-alliance-to-reveal-project-details-strategy-and-roadmap-at-inaugural-workshop-hosted-at-google/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/197/news/chips-alliance-to-reveal-project-details-strategy-and-roadmap-at-inaugural-workshop-hosted-at-google/</guid><description>SAN FRANCISCO – May 7, 2019 – CHIPS Alliance, the leading consortium advancing common, open hardware for interfaces, processors and systems, today announced it is holding its inaugural workshop on June 19, 2019 at Google at 111 W. Java Drive, Sunnyvale, Calif.
Project details, strategy and roadmaps will be presented by member companies, and attendees will have an opportunity to propose Register Transfer Level (RTL) projects and development flow ideas. The workshop will focus on open source hardware, software tools, RTL development, design verification tools and related topics.</description></item></channel></rss>