<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Verilator on CHIPS Alliance</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/207/tags/verilator/</link><description>Recent content in Verilator on CHIPS Alliance</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://chipsalliance.org/preview/207/tags/verilator/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Support for upstream UVM 2017 in Verilator</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/207/news/uvm-verilator/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/207/news/uvm-verilator/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.accellera.org/community/uvm">Universal Verification Methodology (UVM)&lt;/a> is one of the most popular verification methods in digital design, focusing on standardization and reusability of verification IP and environments. For the last few years, Antmicro has been gradually completing milestones toward full UVM support in the open source &lt;a href="https://github.com/verilator">Verilator RTL simulator&lt;/a>, from &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/blog/2021/05/dynamic-scheduling-in-verilator/">dynamic scheduling&lt;/a> (later enhanced with &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/blog/2021/12/coroutines-for-dynamic-scheduling-in-verilator/">coroutines&lt;/a>) through a &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/blog/2023/10/running-simple-uvm-testbenches-in-verilator/">proof-of-concept UVM testbench running in Verilator&lt;/a> to &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/blog/2024/03/introducing-constrained-randomization-in-verilator/">constrained randomization&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>With this article, CHIPS Alliance is happy to announce that Verilator can now elaborate upstream UVM 2017-1.0 - &lt;a href="https://github.com/chipsalliance/uvm-verilator/pull/9">no patches or workarounds&lt;/a> required. This important milestone was spearheaded by Antmicro&amp;rsquo;s efforts within &lt;a href="https://www.chipsalliance.org/">CHIPS Alliance&lt;/a> and complemented by the work of Wilson Snyder, the maintainer of Verilator, as well as the broader open source community.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Constrained randomization in Verilator</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/207/news/constrained-randomization-verilator/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/207/news/constrained-randomization-verilator/</guid><description>&lt;p>Digital design verification often utilizes the so-called constrained randomization functionality offered by SystemVerilog, where in order to efficiently test designs with random but still correct data, a digital logic designer can put constraints in place. This allows verification tests to run shorter by focusing the validation of the design’s behavior on input that the designer considers useful and interesting.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A few months ago Antmicro &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/blog/2024/03/introducing-constrained-randomization-in-verilator/">introduced constrained randomization to Verilator&lt;/a> - another significant milestone on the way towards full open source support for SystemVerilog and industry-prevalent &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/blog/2023/10/running-simple-uvm-testbenches-in-verilator/">UVM testbenches&lt;/a>. This work has been highly anticipated by many industrial users and is allowing Antmicro to slowly but steadily adopt Verilator for UVM-style verification in their state of the art silicon development work like CHIPS Alliance’s &lt;a href="https://github.com/chipsalliance/Caliptra">Caliptra Root of Trust&lt;/a> project.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Initial assertion control support in Verilator</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/207/news/initial-assertion-control-support-in-verilator/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/207/news/initial-assertion-control-support-in-verilator/</guid><description>&lt;p>Antmicro is continuously working on improving productivity of ASIC design and verification workflows using open source tools as leaders of the &lt;a href="https://www.chipsalliance.org/">CHIPS Alliance&lt;/a> Tools Workgroup, as well as for customer and R&amp;amp;D projects. Extending &lt;a href="https://github.com/verilator">Verilator&lt;/a> with new verification features is a prominent example of such efforts, with the latest notable improvements including &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/blog/2023/10/running-simple-uvm-testbenches-in-verilator/">initial support for UVM testbenches&lt;/a>, the &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/blog/2024/01/analyze-verilator-processes-and-asts/">astsee tool for Verilator process and AST analysis&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/blog/2024/03/introducing-constrained-randomization-in-verilator/">constrained randomization&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In this article, Antmicro introduces initial support for global assertion control (&lt;a href="https://github.com/verilator/verilator/pull/5010">already part of mainline Verilator&lt;/a>), building on existing support for assertions available in the simulator. These changes simplify verification testing by letting developers enable or disable assertions as required by particular simulation stages or testing scenarios. Antmicro delves into the benefits of this implementation, examines several use cases where assertion control can prove useful and provide considerations for the path towards full support.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Analyze Verilator processes and ASTs with the astsee suite</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/207/news/analyze-verilator-processes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/207/news/analyze-verilator-processes/</guid><description>&lt;p>Among other things, Antmicro’s work towards improving the vertical integration potential of customers designing ASIC solutions often sees them enhance one of the flagship open source projects in this space, Verilator which complements - and in fact is &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/blog/2023/09/dpi-support-in-renode-for-hdl-co-simulation-with-verilator-and-questa/">often used alongside&lt;/a> - Antmicro’s own functional simulation framework, &lt;a href="https://about.renode.io">Renode&lt;/a>. Besides contributing bug fixes and other quality-of-life improvements into Verilator, Antmicro also develops new functionalities that &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/blog/2023/10/running-simple-uvm-testbenches-in-verilator/">expand its use cases towards e.g. UVM verification&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/blog/2023/09/accelerating-model-generation-in-verilator/">continuously improve overall performance&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Initial Open Source Support for UVM Testbenches in Verilator</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/207/news/initial-open-source-support-for-uvm-testbenches-in-verilator/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/207/news/initial-open-source-support-for-uvm-testbenches-in-verilator/</guid><description>&lt;p>Leading the efforts of the Tools Workgroup in CHIPS Alliance, across a variety of customer projects, as well as its own R&amp;amp;D, Antmicro is actively looking for and capturing the productivity enhancements that can be achieved in ASIC design using open source. Developing and using open source-enhanced workflows is one thing, but in order for the general shift towards open source to happen, open source support for tooling and methodologies that are already prevalent across the chipmaking industry is necessary.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Verilator Model Generation Performance Improvements and Initial Multithreaded Verilation Support</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/207/news/verilator-model-generation-performance-improvements-and-initial-multithreaded-verilation-support/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/207/news/verilator-model-generation-performance-improvements-and-initial-multithreaded-verilation-support/</guid><description>&lt;p>Verilator can boast the status of one of the most widely used free and open source digital design tools for ASIC and FPGA development. To stay on top of the ever-increasing complexity of ASIC and FPGA devices, as users and contributors, Antmicro, a CHIPS Alliance member and part of the &lt;a href="https://lists.chipsalliance.org/g/tools-wg">Tools Workgroup&lt;/a>, has been actively working on improving the tool and its ecosystem, &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/blog/2023/01/cpu-rtl-co-simulation-in-renode/">including adding co-simulation capabilities with Renode&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/blog/2023/01/open-source-systemverilog-uvm-support-in-verilator/">adding support for SystemVerilog UVM testbenches to Verilator&lt;/a>, or &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/blog/2022/11/scaling-verilator-for-very-large-designs/">improving scalability for very large designs&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Progress in open source SystemVerilog / UVM support in Verilator</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/207/news/progress-in-open-source-systemverilog-uvm-support-in-verilator/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/207/news/progress-in-open-source-systemverilog-uvm-support-in-verilator/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://github.com/verilator/verilator">Verilator&lt;/a> is a shining example of a widely-accepted open source tool which provides state-of-the-art results in the ASIC design space. It is commonly used for simulation and testing, but originally, due to the lack of capability to run event-driven simulations, Verilator wasn’t even considered capable of handling UVM (Universal Verification Methodology) testbenches implemented in SystemVerilog which require scheduling and other features notably absent from the tool. For some time now, Antmicro, together with Western Digital, Google and others in the &lt;a href="https://chipsalliance.org/">CHIPS Alliance&lt;/a>, has been working on enabling fully open source support for SystemVerilog UVM testbenches in Verilator. This has already resulted in significant breakthroughs we have described in this blog, such as implementing &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/blog/2021/12/coroutines-for-dynamic-scheduling-in-verilator/">event-driven simulation capabilities&lt;/a> in Verilator which has &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/jevinskie/status/1602834358561566720">enabled new and exciting use cases&lt;/a>. Since then, on the road to proper UVM testbench support, Antmicro has been working on adding various SystemVerilog constructs and UVM-specific elements into Verilator, which bring us much closer to the goal - the current status and next goals will be described in more detail in this blog note.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Towards UVM: Using Coroutines for Low-overhead Dynamic Scheduling in Verilator</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/207/news/towards-uvm-using-coroutines/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/207/news/towards-uvm-using-coroutines/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>This post was originally published at &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/blog/2021/12/coroutines-for-dynamic-scheduling-in-verilator/">Antmicro&lt;/a>.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Verilator is a popular open source SystemVerilog simulator and one of the key tools in the ASIC and FPGA ecosystem, which Antmicro is actively using and developing, e.g. by &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/blog/2021/09/co-simulation-for-zynq-with-renode-and-verilator/">enabling co-simulation with Renode&lt;/a> or &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/blog/2019/06/verilog-with-cocotb-and-verilator/">Cocotb integration&lt;/a>. It’s also one of the fastest available HDL simulators, including proprietary alternatives. It achieves that speed by generating highly optimized C++ code from a given hardware design. Verilator does a lot of work at compile-time to make the generated (‘verilated’) code extremely fast, such as ordering statements in an optimal way.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Listen to CHIPS Alliance’s Rob Mains on EE Journal’s FishFry Podcast</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/207/news/listen-to-chips-alliances-rob-mains-on-ee-journals-fishfry-podcast/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/207/news/listen-to-chips-alliances-rob-mains-on-ee-journals-fishfry-podcast/</guid><description>&lt;p>CHIPS Alliance’s general manager Rob Mains joined Amelia Dalton at EE Journal’s FishFry podcast for a lively discussion about how we’re working to make chip design more accessible. Rob discussed CHIPS Alliance’s work with RISC-V International to develop a new &lt;a href="https://chipsalliance.org/announcement/2021/03/24/risc-v-international-omnixtend-working-group/">unified memory standard&lt;/a>, along with our work to accelerate the design of open source chipsets with the &lt;a href="https://chipsalliance.org/announcement/2020/07/16/aib-2-0-draft-specification/">AIB 2.0 specification&lt;/a>. The conversation also touched on our efforts to provide better support for SystemVerilog using open source tools and to create a dynamic stratified scheduler implementation in Verilator.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Advanced Co-simulation with Renode and Verilator: PolarFire SoC and FastVDMA</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/207/news/renode-and-verilator-polarfire-soc-and-fastvdma/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/207/news/renode-and-verilator-polarfire-soc-and-fastvdma/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>This post was originally published at &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/blog/2021/06/advanced-co-simulation-with-renode-and-verilator/">Antmicro&lt;/a>.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/blog/2019/09/renode-verilator-hdl-co-simulation/">Co-simulating HDL has been possible in Renode since the 1.7.1 release&lt;/a>, but the functionality – critical for hardware/software co-development as well as FPGA use cases – is constantly evolving based on the needs of our customers like Google and Microchip as well as our work in open source groups including &lt;a href="https://chipsalliance.org/">CHIPS Alliance&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://riscv.org/">RISC-V International&lt;/a>. To quickly recap, by co-simulation we mean a scenario where a part of the system is simulated in Renode but some specific peripheral or subsystem is simulated directly from HDL, e.g. Verilog. To achieve this, Renode integrates with Verilator, a fast and popular open source HDL simulator, which we are helping our customers adopt as well as expanding its capabilities to cover new use cases. Peripherals simulated directly from HDL are typically called Verilated peripherals.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Progress on Building Open Source Infrastructure for System Verilog</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/207/news/open-source-infrastructure-for-system-verilog/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/207/news/open-source-infrastructure-for-system-verilog/</guid><description>&lt;p>SystemVerilog is a rich hardware design description and verification language that is seeing increased usage in industry. In the second Deep Dive Cafe Talk by CHIPS Alliance on July 20, Henner Zeller, who is an software developer with Google, provided an excellent in depth technical talk on building out an open source tooling ecosystem around SystemVerilog to provide a common framework that can be used by both functional simulation applications as well as logic synthesis. In case you missed the live presentation, you can watch it &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/xLxNHBzmGiI">here&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>What You Need to Know About Verilator Open Source Tooling</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/207/news/what-you-need-to-know-about-verilator-open-source-tooling/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/207/news/what-you-need-to-know-about-verilator-open-source-tooling/</guid><description>&lt;p>Verilator is a high performance, open source functional simulator that has gained tremendous popularity in its usage and adoption in the verification of chip design. The ASIC development community has widely embraced Verilator as an effective, often even superior alternative to proprietary solutions, and it is now the standard approach in RISC-V CPU design as the community has worked to provide Verilator simulation capabilities out of the box. CHIPS Alliance and RISC-V leaders Antmicro and Western Digital have been collaborating to make Verilator even more useful for ASIC design purposes, working towards supporting industry-standard verification methods in a completely open source flow.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Dynamic Scheduling in Verilator – Milestone Towards Open Source UVM</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/207/news/dynamic-scheduling-in-verilator/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/207/news/dynamic-scheduling-in-verilator/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>This post was originally published at &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/blog/2021/05/dynamic-scheduling-in-verilator/">Antmicro&lt;/a>.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>UVM is a verification methodology traditionally used in chip design which has historically been missing from the open source landscape of verification-focused tooling. While new, open source approaches to verification have emerged that include the excellent Python-based Cocotb (that &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/blog/2019/12/testing-usb-cores-with-python-and-cocotb/">we also use&lt;/a> &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/blog/2019/06/verilog-with-cocotb-and-verilator/">and support&lt;/a>) maintained by &lt;a href="https://www.fossi-foundation.org/">FOSSi Foundation&lt;/a>, not everyone can easily adopt it, especially in long-running projects and existing codebases that use a different verification approach. Leading the efforts towards comprehensive UVM / SystemVerilog support in open source tools, we have been gradually completing milestones, getting closer to what will essentially be a modular, collaboration-driven chips design methodology/workflow. Some examples of our activity in this space include &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/blog/2020/12/ibex-support-in-verilator-yosys-via-uhdm-surelog/">enabling open source synthesis and simulation of the Ibex CPU&lt;/a> in &lt;a href="https://github.com/antmicro/verilator/tree/uhdm-verilator">Verilator&lt;/a>/&lt;a href="https://github.com/antmicro/yosys/tree/uhdm-yosys">Yosys&lt;/a> via UHDM/Surelog, and the most recent joint project with Western Digital in which we have developed &lt;a href="https://github.com/antmicro/verilator-dynamic-scheduler-examples">dynamic scheduling in Verilator&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Goings-on in the FuseSoC Project and Other Open Source Silicon Related News</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/207/news/goings-on-in-the-fusesoc-project-and-other-open-source-silicon-related-news/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/207/news/goings-on-in-the-fusesoc-project-and-other-open-source-silicon-related-news/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>This post was originally published by &lt;a href="https://olofkindgren.blogspot.com/2021/02/fossi-fever-2020.html">Olof Kindgren&lt;/a>&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="fossi-fever-2020">FOSSi Fever 2020&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="fuckload.png" alt="">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2020 was a year with a lot of bad news and so it feels slightly strange to cheerfully write about a very specific topic in the light of this. But there will always be good and bad things happening in the world. So let’s keep fighting the bad things and for now take look at what happened last year within the amazing world of open source silicon. I will start by mentioning the most significant, but by no means the only, milestones for the FOSSi movement as a whole and then take a more personal look at the work where I have been directly involved.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Enabling Open Source Ibex Synthesis and Simulation in Verilator/Yosys via UHDM/Surelog</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/207/news/ibex-synthesis-and-simulation/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/207/news/ibex-synthesis-and-simulation/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>This post was originally published at &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/blog/2020/12/ibex-support-in-verilator-yosys-via-uhdm-surelog/">Antmicro&lt;/a>.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Throughout 2020 we were hard at work developing proper, portable SystemVerilog support for multiple open-source FPGA and ASIC design tools used by us and our customers, most notably &lt;a href="https://github.com/YosysHQ/yosys">Yosys&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://github.com/verilator/verilator">Verilator&lt;/a>. We strongly believe that the support is a necessary step in building a collaborative ecosystem and scalable and reproducible CIs, especially publicly accessible ones that are common in multi-organization projects such as &lt;a href="https://opentitan.org/">OpenTitan&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://chipsalliance.org/">CHIPS Alliance&lt;/a>. Leading the efforts towards achieving this goal, we’ve been developing a fully open source SystemVerilog parsing flow for Yosys and Verilator using UHDM and Surelog, achieving an important milestone: being able to fully parse, synthesize and simulate OpenTitan’s Ibex core directly from the SystemVerilog source.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>CHIPS SweRV Cores and the Open Tools Ecosystem</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/207/news/chips-swerv-cores-and-the-open-tools-ecosystem/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/207/news/chips-swerv-cores-and-the-open-tools-ecosystem/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>This post was originally published at &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/blog/2020/07/swerv-cores-tools-ecosystem/">Antmicro&lt;/a>.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Antmicro’s open source work spans all parts of the computing stack, from software and AI, to PCBs, FPGAs and, most recently, custom silicon. We connect those areas with an overarching vision of open source tooling and methodology, and a software-driven approach that allows us to move fast and build future-centric solutions. Our partners and customers, many of whom work with us also in the context of organizations such as &lt;a href="https://chipsalliance.org/">CHIPS Alliance&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://riscv.org/">RISC-V&lt;/a>, share our approach to developing open systems. We were recently very happy to be invited to give a talk at the &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ODU1b9amCG8&amp;amp;feature=emb_title">“Production grade, open RISC-V SweRV Core Solutions in CHIPS Alliance”&lt;/a> meetup organized by Western Digital where we presented our systems approach on the example of the open source tools ecosystem that targets their SweRV cores and which we are helping to develop.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>CHIPS Alliance announces technical milestones, three new workgroups including Chisel and the 3rd Chisel Community Conference</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/207/news/chips-alliance-announces-technical-milestones-three-new-workgroups-including-chisel-and-the-3rd-chisel-community-conference/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/207/news/chips-alliance-announces-technical-milestones-three-new-workgroups-including-chisel-and-the-3rd-chisel-community-conference/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>SAN FRANCISCO, Nov. 7, 2019&lt;/strong> — CHIPS Alliance, the leading consortium advancing common, open hardware for interfaces, processors and systems, today announced the creation of Interconnects, Rocket and Chisel workgroups. In addition, a November verification workshop in Munich and a Chisel conference in January will be held giving engineers an opportunity to learn about open source development efforts in CHIPS Alliance. Lastly, the CHIPS Alliance toolchain and cores workgroups have made contributions to open source development tools.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>CHIPS Alliance to Reveal Project Details, Strategy and Roadmap at Inaugural Workshop Hosted at Google</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/207/news/chips-alliance-to-reveal-project-details-strategy-and-roadmap-at-inaugural-workshop-hosted-at-google/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/207/news/chips-alliance-to-reveal-project-details-strategy-and-roadmap-at-inaugural-workshop-hosted-at-google/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>SAN FRANCISCO – May 7, 2019&lt;/strong> – CHIPS Alliance, the leading consortium advancing common, open hardware for interfaces, processors and systems, today announced it is holding its inaugural workshop on June 19, 2019 at Google at 111 W. Java Drive, Sunnyvale, Calif.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Project details, strategy and roadmaps will be presented by member companies, and attendees will have an opportunity to propose Register Transfer Level (RTL) projects and development flow ideas. The workshop will focus on open source hardware, software tools, RTL development, design verification tools and related topics. The agenda and registration details are available at &lt;a href="https://events.linuxfoundation.org/events/chips-alliance-workshop-2019">https://events.linuxfoundation.org/events/chips-alliance-workshop-2019&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>