<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>systemverilog on CHIPS Alliance</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/191/tags/systemverilog/</link><description>Recent content in systemverilog on CHIPS Alliance</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://chipsalliance.org/preview/191/tags/systemverilog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Initial assertion control support in Verilator</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/191/news/initial-assertion-control-support-in-verilator/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/191/news/initial-assertion-control-support-in-verilator/</guid><description>Antmicro is continuously working on improving productivity of ASIC design and verification workflows using open source tools as leaders of the CHIPS Alliance Tools Workgroup, as well as for customer and R&amp;amp;D projects. Extending Verilator with new verification features is a prominent example of such efforts, with the latest notable improvements including initial support for UVM testbenches, the astsee tool for Verilator process and AST analysis and constrained randomization.
In this article, Antmicro introduces initial support for global assertion control (already part of mainline Verilator), building on existing support for assertions available in the simulator.</description></item><item><title>Initial Open Source Support for UVM Testbenches in Verilator</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/191/news/initial-open-source-support-for-uvm-testbenches-in-verilator/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/191/news/initial-open-source-support-for-uvm-testbenches-in-verilator/</guid><description>Leading the efforts of the Tools Workgroup in CHIPS Alliance, across a variety of customer projects, as well as its own R&amp;amp;D, Antmicro is actively looking for and capturing the productivity enhancements that can be achieved in ASIC design using open source. Developing and using open source-enhanced workflows is one thing, but in order for the general shift towards open source to happen, open source support for tooling and methodologies that are already prevalent across the chipmaking industry is necessary.</description></item><item><title>Progress in open source SystemVerilog / UVM support in Verilator</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/191/news/progress-in-open-source-systemverilog-uvm-support-in-verilator/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/191/news/progress-in-open-source-systemverilog-uvm-support-in-verilator/</guid><description>Verilator is a shining example of a widely-accepted open source tool which provides state-of-the-art results in the ASIC design space. It is commonly used for simulation and testing, but originally, due to the lack of capability to run event-driven simulations, Verilator wasn’t even considered capable of handling UVM (Universal Verification Methodology) testbenches implemented in SystemVerilog which require scheduling and other features notably absent from the tool. For some time now, Antmicro, together with Western Digital, Google and others in the CHIPS Alliance, has been working on enabling fully open source support for SystemVerilog UVM testbenches in Verilator.</description></item><item><title>Joint Analog Workgroup / MOS-AK Panel Session</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/191/news/joint-analog-workgroup-mos-ak-panel-session/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/191/news/joint-analog-workgroup-mos-ak-panel-session/</guid><description>Please join us for a special joint panel webinar session for the CHIPS Alliance Analog Workgroup and MOS-AK Foundation.
This panel will feature speakers with 20 minute talks on the following topic areas:
@Mehdi Saligane : Introduction to the open source EDA tool flow for IC design (with reference to [1]) @Makris Nikolaos : EKV3 in NGSPICE using ADMSXL @Keiter, Eric R : Xyce and its support for commercial (hSpice/spectre) libs/syntax @Tim Edwards : his work on the SkyWater 130 nm compatibility with ngspice @Kevin Cameron : update on the P1800 (SystemVerilog) AMS standardization efforts (public doc [2]) There will be time for Q &amp;amp; A after each talk and conversation after the presentation completion.</description></item><item><title>Listen to CHIPS Alliance’s Rob Mains on EE Journal’s FishFry Podcast</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/191/news/listen-to-chips-alliances-rob-mains-on-ee-journals-fishfry-podcast/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/191/news/listen-to-chips-alliances-rob-mains-on-ee-journals-fishfry-podcast/</guid><description>CHIPS Alliance’s general manager Rob Mains joined Amelia Dalton at EE Journal’s FishFry podcast for a lively discussion about how we’re working to make chip design more accessible. Rob discussed CHIPS Alliance’s work with RISC-V International to develop a new unified memory standard, along with our work to accelerate the design of open source chipsets with the AIB 2.0 specification. The conversation also touched on our efforts to provide better support for SystemVerilog using open source tools and to create a dynamic stratified scheduler implementation in Verilator.</description></item><item><title>Open Source SystemVerilog Tools in ASIC Design</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/191/news/open-source-systemverilog-tools-in-asic-design/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/191/news/open-source-systemverilog-tools-in-asic-design/</guid><description>This post was originally published at Antmicro.
Open source hardware is undeniably undergoing a renaissance whose origin can be traced to the establishment of RISC-V Foundation (later redubbed RISC-V International). The open ISA and ecosystem, in which Antmicro participated since the beginning as a Founding member, has sparked many open source CPU implementations but also new tooling, methodologies and trends which allow for more collaborative and software driven design.
Many of those broader open hardware activities have been finding a home in CHIPS Alliance, an open source organization we participate in as a Platinum member alongside Google, Intel, Western Digital, SiFive and others, whose goals explicitly encompass:</description></item><item><title>Progress on Building Open Source Infrastructure for System Verilog</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/191/news/open-source-infrastructure-for-system-verilog/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/191/news/open-source-infrastructure-for-system-verilog/</guid><description>SystemVerilog is a rich hardware design description and verification language that is seeing increased usage in industry. In the second Deep Dive Cafe Talk by CHIPS Alliance on July 20, Henner Zeller, who is an software developer with Google, provided an excellent in depth technical talk on building out an open source tooling ecosystem around SystemVerilog to provide a common framework that can be used by both functional simulation applications as well as logic synthesis.</description></item><item><title>What You Need to Know About Verilator Open Source Tooling</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/191/news/what-you-need-to-know-about-verilator-open-source-tooling/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/191/news/what-you-need-to-know-about-verilator-open-source-tooling/</guid><description>Verilator is a high performance, open source functional simulator that has gained tremendous popularity in its usage and adoption in the verification of chip design. The ASIC development community has widely embraced Verilator as an effective, often even superior alternative to proprietary solutions, and it is now the standard approach in RISC-V CPU design as the community has worked to provide Verilator simulation capabilities out of the box. CHIPS Alliance and RISC-V leaders Antmicro and Western Digital have been collaborating to make Verilator even more useful for ASIC design purposes, working towards supporting industry-standard verification methods in a completely open source flow.</description></item><item><title>Intel joins CHIPS Alliance to promote Advanced Interface Bus (AIB) as an open standard</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/191/news/intel-joins-chips-alliance-to-promote-advanced-interface-bus-aib-as-an-open-standard/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/191/news/intel-joins-chips-alliance-to-promote-advanced-interface-bus-aib-as-an-open-standard/</guid><description>Open development for SOCs gets major boost with new collaboration
SAN FRANCISCO, Jan. 22, 2020 /PRNewswire/ — CHIPS Alliance, the leading consortium advancing common and open hardware for interfaces, processors and systems, today announced industry leading chipmaker Intel as it’s newest member. Intel is contributing the Advanced Interface Bus (AIB) to CHIPS Alliance to foster broad adoption.
CHIPS Alliance is hosted by the Linux Foundation to foster a collaborative environment to accelerate the creation and deployment of open SoCs, peripherals and software tools for use in mobile, computing, consumer electronics and Internet of Things (IoT) applications.</description></item></channel></rss>