<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Caliptra on CHIPS Alliance</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/tags/caliptra/</link><description>Recent content in Caliptra on CHIPS Alliance</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://chipsalliance.org/tags/caliptra/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>CHIPS Alliance 2025- A Year of Breakthroughs in Open Silicon and the Road Ahead</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/news/2025-recap/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/news/2025-recap/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>Author: Rob Mains, Executive Director of CHIPS Alliance&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>CHIPS Alliance is a six-year-old organization that is part of the Linux Foundation, whose mission is to foster collaborative, open source development in the silicon hardware design ecosystem. CHIPS champions all aspects of hardware development including:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Chip design architecture&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Electronic design automation for design entry, design verification, and physical implementation&lt;/li>
&lt;li>FPGA tools&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Repository of chip designs and verification design benches&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Firmware&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Artificial intelligence and chip design&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>CHIPS Alliance showcases innovation at OCP Global Summit</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/news/ocp-2025-recap/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/news/ocp-2025-recap/</guid><description>&lt;p>The &lt;a href="https://www.opencompute.org/blog/2025-ocp-global-summit-by-the-numbers">OCP Global Summit&lt;/a>, hosted in San Jose, CA on October 15-17, brought together leaders in open hardware, hyperscale infrastructure, silicon, and data center innovation to collaborate on the future of open computing. Around 10,835 attendees were onsite at the event, which featured keynote presentations, technical sessions and interactive demos showcasing advancements in chip design, AI infrastructure, sustainability and open source hardware standards.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>CHIPS Alliance had a strong presence at the OCP Global Summit, demonstrating how open source silicon development is advancing innovation across data centers, AI and custom silicon. CHIPS was prominently mentioned in a number of keynote sessions on Tuesday as well as Thursday’s detailed technical sessions as part of the overall &lt;a href="https://www.chipsalliance.org/news/caliptra2-1/">Caliptra&lt;/a> effort. These sessions helped drive attendance to the CHIPS Alliance booth, which was shared with the OpenPower Foundation, on the exhibition floor. Rob Mains, Executive Director of CHIPS Alliance, chatted with interested attendees about a wide range of topics including interoperability, open standards, and the importance of community-driven silicon innovation.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>CHIPS Alliance’s Caliptra Launches 2.1 RTL Release</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/news/caliptra2-1/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/news/caliptra2-1/</guid><description>&lt;p>As the Caliptra partners and CHIPS Alliance members Microsoft, Google, NVIDIA and AMD continue to push the boundaries of open hardware security, we’re excited to announce the &lt;strong>Caliptra 2.1 RTL release&lt;/strong> — another important step in building a more secure and transparent silicon ecosystem. This update builds on Caliptra 2.0, delivering refined features, improved verification, and smoother integration for adopters across the industry.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The growing momentum behind Caliptra highlights the power of collaboration between the &lt;a href="https://www.opencompute.org/">Open Compute Project (OCP)&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://www.chipsalliance.org/">CHIPS Alliance&lt;/a> communities. Our shared commitment to innovation is helping shape a future where trusted hardware security is accessible, verifiable, and built on open standards.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>CHIPS Alliance at the 2025 OCP Global Summit</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/news/ocp-october2025/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/news/ocp-october2025/</guid><description>&lt;p>CHIPS Alliance will be onsite at &lt;a href="https://www.opencompute.org/summit/global-summit">OCP Global Summit 2025&lt;/a>, which takes place on Monday, October 13-Thursday, October 16 at the San Jose Convention Center! We’re excited about this year’s program, which features several talks about &lt;a href="https://www.chipsalliance.org/news/chips-alliance-welcomes-the-caliptra-open-source-root-of-trust-project/">Caliptra&lt;/a>, the open source Root-of-Trust (RoT) project highlighting its roadmap, security enhancements, cryptographic core, and integration into real-world cloud and platform environments.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Check out the sessions on Thursday, October 16 and them to your calendar here:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Generating interactive coverage dashboards for VeeR and Caliptra with Coverview</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/news/coverage-dashboards-for-veer-and-caliptra/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/news/coverage-dashboards-for-veer-and-caliptra/</guid><description>&lt;p>Code coverage is a useful metric to keep track of while developing test suites, providing engineering teams with an actionable overview of how broad their testing goes. This is true both for executable code and digital design, but the different nature of RTL and software execution requires developers to look at different types of coverage information. On top of tracking executed code lines and visited branches, RTL coverage will also need to include information e.g. about specific bit field toggles of all the signals in the design. The thorough testing of a sufficient number of combinations of those signals can be the “make or break” for an RTL design.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Constrained randomization in Verilator</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/news/constrained-randomization-verilator/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/news/constrained-randomization-verilator/</guid><description>&lt;p>Digital design verification often utilizes the so-called constrained randomization functionality offered by SystemVerilog, where in order to efficiently test designs with random but still correct data, a digital logic designer can put constraints in place. This allows verification tests to run shorter by focusing the validation of the design’s behavior on input that the designer considers useful and interesting.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A few months ago Antmicro &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/blog/2024/03/introducing-constrained-randomization-in-verilator/">introduced constrained randomization to Verilator&lt;/a> - another significant milestone on the way towards full open source support for SystemVerilog and industry-prevalent &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/blog/2023/10/running-simple-uvm-testbenches-in-verilator/">UVM testbenches&lt;/a>. This work has been highly anticipated by many industrial users and is allowing Antmicro to slowly but steadily adopt Verilator for UVM-style verification in their state of the art silicon development work like CHIPS Alliance’s &lt;a href="https://github.com/chipsalliance/Caliptra">Caliptra Root of Trust&lt;/a> project.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Caliptra - Support for VeeR EL2 with User Mode and Physical Memory Protection in Tock embedded OS</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/news/caliptra-support-for-veer/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/news/caliptra-support-for-veer/</guid><description>&lt;p>The &lt;a href="https://chipsalliance.github.io/Caliptra/">Caliptra&lt;/a> Root of Trust project, a collaboration between AMD, Google, Microsoft and NVIDIA within the &lt;a href="https://www.chipsalliance.org/">CHIPS Alliance&lt;/a>, is steadily heading towards its &lt;a href="https://www.chipsalliance.org/news/caliptra-ocp-global-summit-2024/">2.0 release&lt;/a> – an effort Antmicro is &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=hXjUoCGlXyM">actively contributing to&lt;/a>. They’ve recently described their &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/blog/2024/09/user-mode-in-veer-el2-core-for-caliptra-2-0/">implementation of User mode&lt;/a> in the RISC-V VeeR EL2 core along with extended Physical Memory Protection, and related to this work, they’ve introduced support for VeeR EL2 with User Mode and PMP to the &lt;a href="https://github.com/tock/tock">Tock&lt;/a> embedded OS. The main goal of this implementation was to test the mode switching feature of the VeeR EL2 core with PMP enabled.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Caliptra @ OCP Global Summit 2024</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/news/caliptra-ocp-global-summit-2024/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/news/caliptra-ocp-global-summit-2024/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">Introduction&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>As we continue to advance the field of hardware security, we are thrilled to celebrate the successful integration of Caliptra 1.x by our esteemed partners. Their commitment to enhancing security through the adoption of our open-source Root of Trust (RoT) is a testament to the collaborative spirit of the Open Compute Project (OCP). In this post, we also look ahead to the exciting developments planned for Caliptra 2.0.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="recognizing-caliptra-1x-integrators">Recognizing Caliptra 1.x Integrators&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>We are proud to recognize the following companies for their successful integration of Caliptra 1.x into their products. Each integrator has demonstrated a strong commitment to security, transparency, and innovation. Click on the company names to read their detailed blog posts about their integration of Caliptra:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Adding Physical Memory Protection to the VeeR EL2 RISC-V Core</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/news/adding-physical-memory-protection-to-the-veer-el2-risc-v-core/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/news/adding-physical-memory-protection-to-the-veer-el2-risc-v-core/</guid><description>&lt;p>Antmicro’s work with CHIPS Alliance’s &lt;a href="https://github.com/chipsalliance/Caliptra">Caliptra Root of Trust&lt;/a> project, led by Google, AMD, NVIDIA, and Microsoft focuses around providing &lt;a href="https://opensource.googleblog.com/2023/11/open-source-and-ci-driven-rtl-testing-and-verification-caliptra-risc-v-veer-core.html">automated testing and verification infrastructure&lt;/a> including code quality checks, code indexing, coverage and functional testing pipelines, as well as maintaining and enhancing the RISC-V VeeR EL2 core which sits in the middle of the Caliptra design. As providers of commercial engineering services around open source tools and silicon blocks, working on Caliptra gives Antmicro both a solid starting point for assisting customers with practical RoT implementations as well as a template for CI-driven ASIC development.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Open source and CI-driven RTL testing and verification for Caliptra’s RISC-V VeeR core</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/news/open-source-rtl-ci-testing-and-verification-for-caliptra-veer/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/news/open-source-rtl-ci-testing-and-verification-for-caliptra-veer/</guid><description>&lt;p>As part of &lt;a href="https://www.chipsalliance.org/">CHIPS Alliance’s&lt;/a> mission to enable a software-driven approach to silicon, working with Google and other CHIPS members, Antmicro has been developing and improving a growing number of open source tools to enable effective, CI-driven silicon development.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Fully reproducible and scalable workflows based on open source tooling are especially beneficial for efforts spanning across multiple industrial and academic actors such as Caliptra, a Root of Trust project driven by Google, AMD, NVIDIA and Microsoft which &lt;a href="https://chipsalliance.org/announcement/2022/12/13/chips-alliance-welcomes-the-caliptra-open-source-root-of-trust-project/">recently joined CHIPS&lt;/a> in order to host the ongoing development and provide the necessary structure, working environment and support for the reference implementation of the standard, originally hosted by &lt;a href="https://www.opencompute.org/documents/caliptra-silicon-rot-services-09012022-pdf">Open Compute Project&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>CHIPS Alliance Welcomes the Caliptra Open Source Root of Trust Project</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/news/chips-alliance-welcomes-the-caliptra-open-source-root-of-trust-project/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/news/chips-alliance-welcomes-the-caliptra-open-source-root-of-trust-project/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>SAN FRANCISCO, December 13, 2022&lt;/strong> – CHIPS Alliance, a Linux Foundation project and leading consortium advancing common and open hardware for interfaces, processors and systems, announced that &lt;a href="https://www.opencompute.org/blog/cloud-security-integrating-trust-into-every-chip">Caliptra&lt;/a>, the open source root of trust project founded by technology leaders AMD, Google, Microsoft and NVIDIA, has joined CHIPS Alliance to enable an open, collaborative community-driven approach to hardware security.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Caliptra is a new specification for an open source silicon root of trust (RoT) designed to meet the enhanced security requirements of modern edge and confidential computing workloads. CHIPS Alliance will oversee the open source implementation of register-transfer level (RTL) code for Caliptra that can be synthesized into current SoC designs, along with the verification suite and firmware. As part of this architecture, the open source RISC-V core hosted by the CHIPS Alliance and now relaunched as VeeR, is embedded within the Caliptra Root of Trust macro. VeeR is a true open source RISC-V core family with full RTL and verification bench all under Apache 2.0 license ready for anyone to use.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>