<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Rowhammer on CHIPS Alliance</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/207/tags/rowhammer/</link><description>Recent content in Rowhammer on CHIPS Alliance</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://chipsalliance.org/preview/207/tags/rowhammer/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>New revision of Data Center RDIMM DDR5 Tester</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/207/news/new-revision-of-data-center-rdimm-ddr5-tester/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/207/news/new-revision-of-data-center-rdimm-ddr5-tester/</guid><description>&lt;p>A few years back, Antmicro introduced the first DDR5 capable platform to the open source &lt;a href="https://github.com/antmicro/rowhammer-tester">FPGA-based Rowhammer research framework&lt;/a> developed in cooperation with Google - the &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/blog/2022/08/extending-the-open-source-rowhammer-testing-framework-to-ddr5/">Data Center RDIMM DDR5 Tester&lt;/a>. The follow-on &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/blog/2024/02/versatile-so-dimm-lpddr5-rowhammer-testing-platform/">SO-DIMM (LP)DDR5 Tester&lt;/a> later extended the framework’s coverage to both SO-DIMM DDR5 modules and LPDDR5.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In this article, Antmicro introduces and provides an overview of a &lt;a href="https://github.com/antmicro/rdimm-ddr5-tester">new revision of the RDIMM DDR5 Tester&lt;/a> employing a more recent &lt;a href="https://designer.antmicro.com/hardware/devices/amd-xilinx-xcau25p-2ffvb676i">AMD Artix UltraScale+ XCAU25P&lt;/a> FPGA as compared to Kintex-7 series used in the previous revision. Artix UltraScale+ is a next-gen series of AMD (Xilinx) FPGAs with higher density of logic cells, higher I/O bandwidth, as well as more High Performance (HP) I/Os with a broader operating voltage range - all of which translate to concrete benefits for the platform, described below.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Versatile SO-DIMM (LP)DDR5 Rowhammer testing platform</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/207/news/versatile-rowhammer-testing-platform/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/207/news/versatile-rowhammer-testing-platform/</guid><description>&lt;p>Ten years after the &lt;a href="https://users.ece.cmu.edu/~yoonguk/papers/kim-isca14.pdf">first disclosure of the initial Rowhammer security exploit&lt;/a>, new DRAM vulnerabilities continue to be discovered, and developing new and efficient mitigation techniques requires a deep understanding of the problem considering the complexity of modern DRAM. To safeguard its Data Center and edge device use cases, Google has been using Antmicro’s advanced R&amp;amp;D capabilities to develop an &lt;a href="https://github.com/antmicro/rowhammer-tester">open source FPGA-based memory testing suite&lt;/a> and family of open hardware platforms, expanding beyond the capabilities of pure-software vulnerability testing and mitigation approaches. The targeted DDR variants have so far included &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/blog/2021/04/lpddr4-test-platform/">LPDDR4&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/blog/2021/12/open-source-data-center-rowhammer-tester/">DDR4&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/blog/2022/08/extending-the-open-source-rowhammer-testing-framework-to-ddr5/">DDR5 RDIMM&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Open Source FPGA Platform for Rowhammer Security Testing in the Data Center</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/207/news/open-source-fpga-platform-for-rowhammer-security-testing-in-the-data-center/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/207/news/open-source-fpga-platform-for-rowhammer-security-testing-in-the-data-center/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>This post was originally published at &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/blog/2021/12/open-source-data-center-rowhammer-tester/">Antmicro&lt;/a>.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Our work together with Google and the world’s research community on detecting and mitigating the Rowhammer problem in DRAM memories has been proving that the challenge is far from being solved and a lot of systems are still vulnerable.
&lt;a href="https://opensource.googleblog.com/2021/11/Open%20source%20DDR%20controller%20framework%20for%20mitigating%20Rowhammer.html">The DDR Rowhammer testing framework&lt;/a> that we developed together with an open hardware &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/blog/2021/04/lpddr4-test-platform/">LPDDR4 DRAM tester board&lt;/a> has been used to detect new attack methods such as &lt;a href="https://security.googleblog.com/2021/05/introducing-half-double-new-hammering.html">Half-Double&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://thehackernews.com/2021/11/new-blacksmith-exploit-bypasses-current.html">Blacksmith&lt;/a> and all data seems to suggest this more such methods will be discovered with time.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Open Source DDR Controller Framework for Mitigating Rowhammer</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/207/news/open-source-ddr-controller-framework-for-mitigating-rowhammer/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/207/news/open-source-ddr-controller-framework-for-mitigating-rowhammer/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>This post was originally published at &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/blog/2021/08/open-source-ddr-test-framework-for-rowhammer/">Antmicro&lt;/a>.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Row_hammer">Rowhammer&lt;/a> is a hardware vulnerability that affects DRAM memory chips and can be exploited to modify memory contents, potentially providing root access to the system. It occurs because Dynamic RAM consists of multiple memory cells packed tightly together and specific access patterns can cause unwanted effects that propagate to nearby memory cells and cause bit-flips in cells which have not been accessed by the attacker.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Modular, Open-source FPGA-based LPDDR4 Test Platform</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/207/news/modular-open-source-fpga-based-lpddr4-test-platform/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/207/news/modular-open-source-fpga-based-lpddr4-test-platform/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>This post was originally published at &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/blog/2021/04/lpddr4-test-platform/">Antmicro&lt;/a>.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The flexibility of FPGAs makes them an excellent choice not only for parallel processing applications but also for research and experimentation in a range of technological areas.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We often provide our customers with flexible R&amp;amp;D platforms that can be easily adapted to changing requirements and new use cases as a result of our practice of using open source hardware, software, FPGA IP and tooling.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>