<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Chisel on CHIPS Alliance</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/tags/chisel/</link><description>Recent content in Chisel on CHIPS Alliance</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://chipsalliance.org/tags/chisel/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>CHIPS Alliance 2025- A Year of Breakthroughs in Open Silicon and the Road Ahead</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/news/2025-recap/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/news/2025-recap/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>Author: Rob Mains, Executive Director of CHIPS Alliance&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>CHIPS Alliance is a six-year-old organization that is part of the Linux Foundation, whose mission is to foster collaborative, open source development in the silicon hardware design ecosystem. CHIPS champions all aspects of hardware development including:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Chip design architecture&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Electronic design automation for design entry, design verification, and physical implementation&lt;/li>
&lt;li>FPGA tools&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Repository of chip designs and verification design benches&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Firmware&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Artificial intelligence and chip design&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>CHIPS Alliance announces technical milestones, three new workgroups including Chisel and the 3rd Chisel Community Conference</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/news/chips-alliance-announces-technical-milestones-three-new-workgroups-including-chisel-and-the-3rd-chisel-community-conference/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/news/chips-alliance-announces-technical-milestones-three-new-workgroups-including-chisel-and-the-3rd-chisel-community-conference/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>SAN FRANCISCO, Nov. 7, 2019&lt;/strong> — CHIPS Alliance, the leading consortium advancing common, open hardware for interfaces, processors and systems, today announced the creation of Interconnects, Rocket and Chisel workgroups. In addition, a November verification workshop in Munich and a Chisel conference in January will be held giving engineers an opportunity to learn about open source development efforts in CHIPS Alliance. Lastly, the CHIPS Alliance toolchain and cores workgroups have made contributions to open source development tools.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>CHIPS Alliance to Reveal Project Details, Strategy and Roadmap at Inaugural Workshop Hosted at Google</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/news/chips-alliance-to-reveal-project-details-strategy-and-roadmap-at-inaugural-workshop-hosted-at-google/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/news/chips-alliance-to-reveal-project-details-strategy-and-roadmap-at-inaugural-workshop-hosted-at-google/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>SAN FRANCISCO – May 7, 2019&lt;/strong> – CHIPS Alliance, the leading consortium advancing common, open hardware for interfaces, processors and systems, today announced it is holding its inaugural workshop on June 19, 2019 at Google at 111 W. Java Drive, Sunnyvale, Calif.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Project details, strategy and roadmaps will be presented by member companies, and attendees will have an opportunity to propose Register Transfer Level (RTL) projects and development flow ideas. The workshop will focus on open source hardware, software tools, RTL development, design verification tools and related topics. The agenda and registration details are available at &lt;a href="https://events.linuxfoundation.org/events/chips-alliance-workshop-2019">https://events.linuxfoundation.org/events/chips-alliance-workshop-2019&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Linux Foundation to Host CHIPS Alliance Project to Propel Industry Innovation Through Open Source CPU Chip and SoC Design</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/news/linux-foundation-to-host-chips-alliance-project-to-propel-industry-innovation-through-open-source-cpu-chip-and-soc-design/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/news/linux-foundation-to-host-chips-alliance-project-to-propel-industry-innovation-through-open-source-cpu-chip-and-soc-design/</guid><description>&lt;p>New Linux Foundation Project to Foster Flexible, Next-Generation Chip Design for Diverse Data-Centric Applications and Workloads&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>SAN FRANCISCO – March 11, 2019&lt;/strong> – &lt;a href="http://linuxfoundation.org/">The Linux Foundation&lt;/a>, the nonprofit organization enabling mass innovation through open source, today announced its intent to form the CHIPS Alliance project to host and curate high-quality open source code relevant to the design of silicon devices. CHIPS Alliance will foster a collaborative environment that will enable accelerated creation and deployment of more efficient and flexible chip designs for use in mobile, computing, consumer electronics, and Internet of Things (IoT) applications.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>