<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Abouts on CHIPS Alliance</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/62/about/</link><description>Recent content in Abouts on CHIPS Alliance</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://chipsalliance.org/preview/62/about/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Contact</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/62/about/contact/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/62/about/contact/</guid><description>hbspt.forms.create({ region: "na1", portalId: "8112310", formId: "94557cae-71ce-4536-a54f-8eff19aab9f9", sfdcCampaignId: "7012M000001FetwQAC" }); Mailing Address CHIPS Alliance
1 Letterman Drive, Building D, Suite D4700
San Francisco, CA 94129</description></item><item><title>Frequently Asked Questions</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/62/about/faq/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/62/about/faq/</guid><description>1 What is CHIPS Alliance?
CHIPS Alliance, a member of the Linux Foundation, is championing open source based collaboration in the chip design community. This includes architectures, specifications, reference implementations, PDKs and EDA tooling. CHIPS Alliance hosts different workgroups to bring community members together to focus on topics of shared interest. 2 Why do we need open source hardware, chips, FPGAs, etc.?
Open source ingredients for hardware design are enabling and accelerating the global collaborative ecosystem.</description></item><item><title>Governance</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/62/about/governance/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/62/about/governance/</guid><description>In addition to the top-level structure of The CHIPS Alliance, each hosted open source project has its own process, structure, and community. While the Technical Steering Community (TSC) sets high-level technical policy, projects have a great deal of flexibility in day-to-day operations.
Rob Mains - General Manager The General Manager works with the Governing Board, our members, and our projects to ensure the CHIPS Alliance is a healthy, sustainable, and neutral home for open source technical collaborations.</description></item><item><title>Members</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/62/about/members/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/62/about/members/</guid><description>When an organization joins the CHIPS Alliance, they are making a tangible commitment to the success and sustainability of open source projects which help to achieve these goals. The CHIPS Alliance recognizes the critical supporting role of these organizations, and thanks them for their ongoing support of our project communities.
CHIPS Alliance Members Become a Member Platinum Members Gold Members Silver Members Auditor Members Associate Members</description></item><item><title>Who We Are</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/62/about/who-we-are/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/62/about/who-we-are/</guid><description>The CHIPS Alliance leverages common hardware development efforts by developing IP blocks that can be broadly used, such as RISC-V cores and neural network accelerator cores. We recognize that verification contributions benefit all who participate in the project, and prioritize joint resources for design verification.
The scope of the Project includes hardware and software design and development under an open source (Apache v2) license:
Verified IP blocks (compute cores, accelerators etc) Verified SoC designs (based on RISC-V and other open source cores) Open source software development tools for ASIC development High value IP including analog peripherals, mixed signal blocks and compute acceleration Exploration of new design flows such as Python-based design verification.</description></item></channel></rss>