<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Project-Update on CHIPS Alliance</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/202/tags/project-update/</link><description>Recent content in Project-Update on CHIPS Alliance</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 22 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://chipsalliance.org/preview/202/tags/project-update/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Generating interactive coverage dashboards for VeeR and Caliptra with Coverview</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/202/news/coverage-dashboards-for-veer-and-caliptra/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/202/news/coverage-dashboards-for-veer-and-caliptra/</guid><description>&lt;p>Code coverage is a useful metric to keep track of while developing test suites, providing engineering teams with an actionable overview of how broad their testing goes. This is true both for executable code and digital design, but the different nature of RTL and software execution requires developers to look at different types of coverage information. On top of tracking executed code lines and visited branches, RTL coverage will also need to include information e.g. about specific bit field toggles of all the signals in the design. The thorough testing of a sufficient number of combinations of those signals can be the “make or break” for an RTL design.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>New revision of Data Center RDIMM DDR5 Tester</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/202/news/new-revision-of-data-center-rdimm-ddr5-tester/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/202/news/new-revision-of-data-center-rdimm-ddr5-tester/</guid><description>&lt;p>A few years back, Antmicro introduced the first DDR5 capable platform to the open source &lt;a href="https://github.com/antmicro/rowhammer-tester">FPGA-based Rowhammer research framework&lt;/a> developed in cooperation with Google - the &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/blog/2022/08/extending-the-open-source-rowhammer-testing-framework-to-ddr5/">Data Center RDIMM DDR5 Tester&lt;/a>. The follow-on &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/blog/2024/02/versatile-so-dimm-lpddr5-rowhammer-testing-platform/">SO-DIMM (LP)DDR5 Tester&lt;/a> later extended the framework’s coverage to both SO-DIMM DDR5 modules and LPDDR5.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In this article, Antmicro introduces and provides an overview of a &lt;a href="https://github.com/antmicro/rdimm-ddr5-tester">new revision of the RDIMM DDR5 Tester&lt;/a> employing a more recent &lt;a href="https://designer.antmicro.com/hardware/devices/amd-xilinx-xcau25p-2ffvb676i">AMD Artix UltraScale+ XCAU25P&lt;/a> FPGA as compared to Kintex-7 series used in the previous revision. Artix UltraScale+ is a next-gen series of AMD (Xilinx) FPGAs with higher density of logic cells, higher I/O bandwidth, as well as more High Performance (HP) I/Os with a broader operating voltage range - all of which translate to concrete benefits for the platform, described below.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Constrained randomization in Verilator</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/202/news/constrained-randomization-verilator/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/202/news/constrained-randomization-verilator/</guid><description>&lt;p>Digital design verification often utilizes the so-called constrained randomization functionality offered by SystemVerilog, where in order to efficiently test designs with random but still correct data, a digital logic designer can put constraints in place. This allows verification tests to run shorter by focusing the validation of the design’s behavior on input that the designer considers useful and interesting.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A few months ago Antmicro &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/blog/2024/03/introducing-constrained-randomization-in-verilator/">introduced constrained randomization to Verilator&lt;/a> - another significant milestone on the way towards full open source support for SystemVerilog and industry-prevalent &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/blog/2023/10/running-simple-uvm-testbenches-in-verilator/">UVM testbenches&lt;/a>. This work has been highly anticipated by many industrial users and is allowing Antmicro to slowly but steadily adopt Verilator for UVM-style verification in their state of the art silicon development work like CHIPS Alliance’s &lt;a href="https://github.com/chipsalliance/Caliptra">Caliptra Root of Trust&lt;/a> project.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Topwrap – open source toolkit for modular, parameterizable digital logic design</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/202/news/topwrap/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/202/news/topwrap/</guid><description>&lt;p>ASIC and FPGA designs consist of distinct blocks of logic bound together by a top-level design. Taking advantage of this modularity and enabling automation and reuse of blocks across designs requires tools for automated processing and generation of top level files, letting you easily parametrize and aggregate the blocks in various configurations.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To this end, Antmicro created &lt;a href="https://github.com/antmicro/topwrap">Topwrap&lt;/a>, an open source toolkit for connecting individual HDL modules into full designs of varying complexity. The toolkit is designed to take advantage of the ever-growing library of open source digital logic blocks that they also &lt;a href="https://github.com/chipsalliance/i3c-core">heavily contribute to&lt;/a> and, thanks to its structuredness, offers a user-friendly graphical interface sitting on top of a well-formed CLI. This in turn lets you mix-and-match high-level GUI-driven design with more fine-grained CLI-level adjustments and present designs in the form of a diagram thanks to the integration with Antmicro’s &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/blog/2024/02/add-web-based-guis-with-pipeline-manager/">Pipeline Manager&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Initial assertion control support in Verilator</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/202/news/initial-assertion-control-support-in-verilator/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/202/news/initial-assertion-control-support-in-verilator/</guid><description>&lt;p>Antmicro is continuously working on improving productivity of ASIC design and verification workflows using open source tools as leaders of the &lt;a href="https://www.chipsalliance.org/">CHIPS Alliance&lt;/a> Tools Workgroup, as well as for customer and R&amp;amp;D projects. Extending &lt;a href="https://github.com/verilator">Verilator&lt;/a> with new verification features is a prominent example of such efforts, with the latest notable improvements including &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/blog/2023/10/running-simple-uvm-testbenches-in-verilator/">initial support for UVM testbenches&lt;/a>, the &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/blog/2024/01/analyze-verilator-processes-and-asts/">astsee tool for Verilator process and AST analysis&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/blog/2024/03/introducing-constrained-randomization-in-verilator/">constrained randomization&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In this article, Antmicro introduces initial support for global assertion control (&lt;a href="https://github.com/verilator/verilator/pull/5010">already part of mainline Verilator&lt;/a>), building on existing support for assertions available in the simulator. These changes simplify verification testing by letting developers enable or disable assertions as required by particular simulation stages or testing scenarios. Antmicro delves into the benefits of this implementation, examines several use cases where assertion control can prove useful and provide considerations for the path towards full support.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Speeding Up OpenROAD For Fast Design Feedback</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/202/news/speeding-up-openroad-for-fast-design-feedback/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/202/news/speeding-up-openroad-for-fast-design-feedback/</guid><description>&lt;p>The &lt;a href="https://theopenroadproject.org/">OpenROAD&lt;/a> project provides an open source ASIC toolchain that reduces the entry barriers to the field of hardware development and allows fast-turnaround feedback about designs, helping to increase the productivity of silicon teams. As such, it’s a great supporting tool, increasingly used in state-of-the-art industrial projects alongside other open source tools like Verilator.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Antmicro has been helping early adopters of OpenROAD-based flows in projects such as &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/blog/2021/12/sw-driven-asics-with-skywater-shuttle/">SkyWater Shuttle&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/blog/2023/03/adapting-opentitan-for-fpga-prototyping-and-tooling-development/">OpenTitan&lt;/a> or more recently, Google’s &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/blog/2023/09/accelerating-digital-block-design-with-googles-xls/">XLS&lt;/a>. As a result, there is an increasing amount of interest in improving the performance of OpenROAD to yield faster turnaround times, especially for large and complex designs.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Adding Physical Memory Protection to the VeeR EL2 RISC-V Core</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/202/news/adding-physical-memory-protection-to-the-veer-el2-risc-v-core/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/202/news/adding-physical-memory-protection-to-the-veer-el2-risc-v-core/</guid><description>&lt;p>Antmicro’s work with CHIPS Alliance’s &lt;a href="https://github.com/chipsalliance/Caliptra">Caliptra Root of Trust&lt;/a> project, led by Google, AMD, NVIDIA, and Microsoft focuses around providing &lt;a href="https://opensource.googleblog.com/2023/11/open-source-and-ci-driven-rtl-testing-and-verification-caliptra-risc-v-veer-core.html">automated testing and verification infrastructure&lt;/a> including code quality checks, code indexing, coverage and functional testing pipelines, as well as maintaining and enhancing the RISC-V VeeR EL2 core which sits in the middle of the Caliptra design. As providers of commercial engineering services around open source tools and silicon blocks, working on Caliptra gives Antmicro both a solid starting point for assisting customers with practical RoT implementations as well as a template for CI-driven ASIC development.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Versatile SO-DIMM (LP)DDR5 Rowhammer testing platform</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/202/news/versatile-rowhammer-testing-platform/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/202/news/versatile-rowhammer-testing-platform/</guid><description>&lt;p>Ten years after the &lt;a href="https://users.ece.cmu.edu/~yoonguk/papers/kim-isca14.pdf">first disclosure of the initial Rowhammer security exploit&lt;/a>, new DRAM vulnerabilities continue to be discovered, and developing new and efficient mitigation techniques requires a deep understanding of the problem considering the complexity of modern DRAM. To safeguard its Data Center and edge device use cases, Google has been using Antmicro’s advanced R&amp;amp;D capabilities to develop an &lt;a href="https://github.com/antmicro/rowhammer-tester">open source FPGA-based memory testing suite&lt;/a> and family of open hardware platforms, expanding beyond the capabilities of pure-software vulnerability testing and mitigation approaches. The targeted DDR variants have so far included &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/blog/2021/04/lpddr4-test-platform/">LPDDR4&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/blog/2021/12/open-source-data-center-rowhammer-tester/">DDR4&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/blog/2022/08/extending-the-open-source-rowhammer-testing-framework-to-ddr5/">DDR5 RDIMM&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Initial Open Source Support for UVM Testbenches in Verilator</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/202/news/initial-open-source-support-for-uvm-testbenches-in-verilator/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/202/news/initial-open-source-support-for-uvm-testbenches-in-verilator/</guid><description>&lt;p>Leading the efforts of the Tools Workgroup in CHIPS Alliance, across a variety of customer projects, as well as its own R&amp;amp;D, Antmicro is actively looking for and capturing the productivity enhancements that can be achieved in ASIC design using open source. Developing and using open source-enhanced workflows is one thing, but in order for the general shift towards open source to happen, open source support for tooling and methodologies that are already prevalent across the chipmaking industry is necessary.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Verilator Model Generation Performance Improvements and Initial Multithreaded Verilation Support</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/202/news/verilator-model-generation-performance-improvements-and-initial-multithreaded-verilation-support/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/202/news/verilator-model-generation-performance-improvements-and-initial-multithreaded-verilation-support/</guid><description>&lt;p>Verilator can boast the status of one of the most widely used free and open source digital design tools for ASIC and FPGA development. To stay on top of the ever-increasing complexity of ASIC and FPGA devices, as users and contributors, Antmicro, a CHIPS Alliance member and part of the &lt;a href="https://lists.chipsalliance.org/g/tools-wg">Tools Workgroup&lt;/a>, has been actively working on improving the tool and its ecosystem, &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/blog/2023/01/cpu-rtl-co-simulation-in-renode/">including adding co-simulation capabilities with Renode&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/blog/2023/01/open-source-systemverilog-uvm-support-in-verilator/">adding support for SystemVerilog UVM testbenches to Verilator&lt;/a>, or &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/blog/2022/11/scaling-verilator-for-very-large-designs/">improving scalability for very large designs&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Progress in open source SystemVerilog / UVM support in Verilator</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/202/news/progress-in-open-source-systemverilog-uvm-support-in-verilator/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/202/news/progress-in-open-source-systemverilog-uvm-support-in-verilator/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://github.com/verilator/verilator">Verilator&lt;/a> is a shining example of a widely-accepted open source tool which provides state-of-the-art results in the ASIC design space. It is commonly used for simulation and testing, but originally, due to the lack of capability to run event-driven simulations, Verilator wasn’t even considered capable of handling UVM (Universal Verification Methodology) testbenches implemented in SystemVerilog which require scheduling and other features notably absent from the tool. For some time now, Antmicro, together with Western Digital, Google and others in the &lt;a href="https://chipsalliance.org/">CHIPS Alliance&lt;/a>, has been working on enabling fully open source support for SystemVerilog UVM testbenches in Verilator. This has already resulted in significant breakthroughs we have described in this blog, such as implementing &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/blog/2021/12/coroutines-for-dynamic-scheduling-in-verilator/">event-driven simulation capabilities&lt;/a> in Verilator which has &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/jevinskie/status/1602834358561566720">enabled new and exciting use cases&lt;/a>. Since then, on the road to proper UVM testbench support, Antmicro has been working on adding various SystemVerilog constructs and UVM-specific elements into Verilator, which bring us much closer to the goal - the current status and next goals will be described in more detail in this blog note.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Open source and CI-driven RTL testing and verification for Caliptra’s RISC-V VeeR core</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/202/news/open-source-rtl-ci-testing-and-verification-for-caliptra-veer/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/202/news/open-source-rtl-ci-testing-and-verification-for-caliptra-veer/</guid><description>&lt;p>As part of &lt;a href="https://www.chipsalliance.org/">CHIPS Alliance’s&lt;/a> mission to enable a software-driven approach to silicon, working with Google and other CHIPS members, Antmicro has been developing and improving a growing number of open source tools to enable effective, CI-driven silicon development.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Fully reproducible and scalable workflows based on open source tooling are especially beneficial for efforts spanning across multiple industrial and academic actors such as Caliptra, a Root of Trust project driven by Google, AMD, NVIDIA and Microsoft which &lt;a href="https://chipsalliance.org/announcement/2022/12/13/chips-alliance-welcomes-the-caliptra-open-source-root-of-trust-project/">recently joined CHIPS&lt;/a> in order to host the ongoing development and provide the necessary structure, working environment and support for the reference implementation of the standard, originally hosted by &lt;a href="https://www.opencompute.org/documents/caliptra-silicon-rot-services-09012022-pdf">Open Compute Project&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Integrating the Language Server Protocol in Verible</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/202/news/integrating-language-server-protocol-in-verible/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/202/news/integrating-language-server-protocol-in-verible/</guid><description>&lt;p>A more collaborative, open and software driven ASIC design methodology pioneered by the &lt;a href="https://chipsalliance.org">CHIPS Alliance&lt;/a> requires an open source tooling stack to enable sharing of workflows, artifacts and fostering a free exchange of insights and improvements.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>While internally often using new design methodologies and languages such as Migen, Chisel or XLS, Antmicro is conscious of the fact that a lot of the world’s ASIC development involves SystemVerilog and UVM, and so we are working on bridging traditional and new ASIC development methodologies as described in a &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/blog/2023/01/open-source-systemverilog-uvm-support-in-verilator/">recent blog note&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>F4PGA open source flow gets a new Python-based build system and CLI tool</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/202/news/f4pga-open-source-flow-gets-a-new-python-based-build-system-and-cli-tool/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/202/news/f4pga-open-source-flow-gets-a-new-python-based-build-system-and-cli-tool/</guid><description>&lt;p>One of the most recent projects developed within the workgroup is the &lt;a href="https://github.com/chipsalliance/f4pga">unified f4pga CLI tool&lt;/a>. In the broader context of our &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/blog/2021/09/fpga-interchange-format/">continuous efforts to make the FPGA space more unified and flexible&lt;/a>, creating the f4pga CLI tool was a logical next step – it allowed us to wrap the underlying tools into a single CLI, making the F4PGA toolchain a more complete flow. The currently supported architectures are AMD’s (former Xilinx) 7 Series, Lattice’s iCE40 and QuickLogic’s EOS S3. &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/blog/2022/09/f4pga-new-build-system-and-cli-tool">Details are here&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Skywater</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/202/news/skywater/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/202/news/skywater/</guid><description>&lt;p>It’s great to learn that Google &lt;a href="https://www.skywatertechnology.com/skywater-receives-funding-from-dod-partners-with-google-to-facilitate-open-source-design-for-its-new-90-nm-technology-offering/">announced&lt;/a> the expansion of its partnership with &lt;a href="https://www.skywatertechnology.com/">SkyWater Technology&lt;/a>. They are working together to release an open source process design kit (PDK) for SKY90-FD, SkyWater’s commercial 90nm fully depleted silicon on insulator (FDSOI) CMOS process technology. SKY90-FD is based on MIT Lincoln Laboratory’s 90 nm commercial FDSOI technology, and enables designers to create complex integrated circuits for a diverse range of applications.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You can read more @ &lt;a href="https://opensource.googleblog.com/2022/07/SkyWater-and-Google-expand-open-source-program-to-new-90nm-technology.html">https://opensource.googleblog.com/2022/07/SkyWater-and-Google-expand-open-source-program-to-new-90nm-technology.html&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Antmicro DDR5 Rowhammer Testing Framework</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/202/news/1212/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/202/news/1212/</guid><description>&lt;p>CHIPS Alliance is excited by the Antmicro announcement of the extensible, open, Rowhammer testing framework for DDR5. Read a detailed description of their work here: &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/blog/2022/08/extending-the-open-source-rowhammer-testing-framework-to-ddr5/">https://antmicro.com/blog/2022/08/extending-the-open-source-rowhammer-testing-framework-to-ddr5/&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Here are some graphics of the work:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="DDR5-diagram.svg" alt="DDR5 diagram">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="DDR5-photo.png" alt="DDR5 device">&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Enhanced System Verilog Support for Yosys via Antmicro plug-in</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/202/news/enhanced-system-verilog-support-for-yosys-via-antmicro-plug-in/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/202/news/enhanced-system-verilog-support-for-yosys-via-antmicro-plug-in/</guid><description>&lt;p>CHIPS Alliance is pleased to see the announcement by Antmicro for its development and contribution to the open source hardware community to provide a easy to use plug-in for any version of Yosys to allow import of System Verilog based designs. This development is made possible by the underlying utilization of the Unified Hardware Data Model (UHDM), a key open source data representation upon which EDA applications can be built. Details can be seen here from Antmicro: &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/blog/2022/02/simplifying-open-source-sv-synthesis-with-the-yosys-uhdm-plugin/">https://antmicro.com/blog/2022/02/simplifying-open-source-sv-synthesis-with-the-yosys-uhdm-plugin/&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Towards UVM: Using Coroutines for Low-overhead Dynamic Scheduling in Verilator</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/202/news/towards-uvm-using-coroutines/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/202/news/towards-uvm-using-coroutines/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>This post was originally published at &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/blog/2021/12/coroutines-for-dynamic-scheduling-in-verilator/">Antmicro&lt;/a>.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Verilator is a popular open source SystemVerilog simulator and one of the key tools in the ASIC and FPGA ecosystem, which Antmicro is actively using and developing, e.g. by &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/blog/2021/09/co-simulation-for-zynq-with-renode-and-verilator/">enabling co-simulation with Renode&lt;/a> or &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/blog/2019/06/verilog-with-cocotb-and-verilator/">Cocotb integration&lt;/a>. It’s also one of the fastest available HDL simulators, including proprietary alternatives. It achieves that speed by generating highly optimized C++ code from a given hardware design. Verilator does a lot of work at compile-time to make the generated (‘verilated’) code extremely fast, such as ordering statements in an optimal way.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Open Source FPGA Platform for Rowhammer Security Testing in the Data Center</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/202/news/open-source-fpga-platform-for-rowhammer-security-testing-in-the-data-center/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/202/news/open-source-fpga-platform-for-rowhammer-security-testing-in-the-data-center/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>This post was originally published at &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/blog/2021/12/open-source-data-center-rowhammer-tester/">Antmicro&lt;/a>.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Our work together with Google and the world’s research community on detecting and mitigating the Rowhammer problem in DRAM memories has been proving that the challenge is far from being solved and a lot of systems are still vulnerable.
&lt;a href="https://opensource.googleblog.com/2021/11/Open%20source%20DDR%20controller%20framework%20for%20mitigating%20Rowhammer.html">The DDR Rowhammer testing framework&lt;/a> that we developed together with an open hardware &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/blog/2021/04/lpddr4-test-platform/">LPDDR4 DRAM tester board&lt;/a> has been used to detect new attack methods such as &lt;a href="https://security.googleblog.com/2021/05/introducing-half-double-new-hammering.html">Half-Double&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://thehackernews.com/2021/11/new-blacksmith-exploit-bypasses-current.html">Blacksmith&lt;/a> and all data seems to suggest this more such methods will be discovered with time.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Open Source Debayerization Blocks in FPGA</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/202/news/open-source-debayerization-blocks-in-fpga/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/202/news/open-source-debayerization-blocks-in-fpga/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>This post was originally published at &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/blog/2021/10/debayerization-blocks-in-fpga/">Antmicro&lt;/a>.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/platforms/custom-camera-platforms/">modern digital camera systems&lt;/a>, the captured image undergoes a complex process involving various image signal processing (ISP) techniques to reproduce the observed scene as accurately as possible while preserving bandwidth. On the most basic level, most CCD and CMOS image sensors use the Bayer pattern filter, where 50% of the pixels are green, 25% are red and 25% are blue (corresponding to the increased sensitivity of the human eye to the green color). &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Demosaicing">Demosaicing&lt;/a>, also known as debayering, is an important part of any ISP pipeline whereby an algorithm reconstructs the missing RGB components/channels of each pixel by performing interpolation of the values collected for individual pixels.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Improving the OpenLane ASIC Build Flow with Open Source SystemVerilog Support</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/202/news/improving-the-openlane-asic-build-flow-with-open-source-systemverilog-support/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/202/news/improving-the-openlane-asic-build-flow-with-open-source-systemverilog-support/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>This post was originally published at &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/blog/2021/10/openlane-asic-build-flow-with-systemverliog-support/">Antmicro&lt;/a>.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Open source toolchains are key to building collaborative ecosystems, welcoming to new approaches, opportunistic/focused innovations and niche use cases. The ASIC design domain, especially in the view of the rising tensions around manufacturing and supply chains, are in dire need of a software-driven innovation based on an open source approach. The fledgling open source hardware ecosystem has been energized by the success of RISC-V and is now being vastly expanded to cover the entire ASIC design flow by &lt;a href="https://chipsalliance.org/">CHIPS Alliance&lt;/a>, and Antmicro has been playing a leadership role in both of these organizations as well as offering commercial engineering and support services to assist with early adoption of open source approaches in hardware.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Open Source DDR Controller Framework for Mitigating Rowhammer</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/202/news/open-source-ddr-controller-framework-for-mitigating-rowhammer/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/202/news/open-source-ddr-controller-framework-for-mitigating-rowhammer/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>This post was originally published at &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/blog/2021/08/open-source-ddr-test-framework-for-rowhammer/">Antmicro&lt;/a>.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Row_hammer">Rowhammer&lt;/a> is a hardware vulnerability that affects DRAM memory chips and can be exploited to modify memory contents, potentially providing root access to the system. It occurs because Dynamic RAM consists of multiple memory cells packed tightly together and specific access patterns can cause unwanted effects that propagate to nearby memory cells and cause bit-flips in cells which have not been accessed by the attacker.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>SymbiFlow FPGA Interchange Format to Enable Interoperable FPGA Tooling</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/202/news/symbiflow-fpga-interchange-format-to-enable-interoperable-fpga-tooling/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/202/news/symbiflow-fpga-interchange-format-to-enable-interoperable-fpga-tooling/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>This post was originally published at &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/blog/2021/09/symbiflow-fpga-interchange-format/">Antmicro&lt;/a>.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/technologies/fpga/">Field Programmable Gate Arrays (FPGAs)&lt;/a> have been around for several decades, but historically development of toolchains targeting specific platforms was done in separate ecosystems and driven by the vendors themselves. Only in recent years, the development of vendor-neutral open source toolchains has revealed the need of having an abstraction layer to describe and define an FPGA architecture through a standard format.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>FPGA toolchains are not trivial as they comprise several elements which themselves can be quite complex: roughly speaking, you can divide the process of “compiling” FPGA-targeted code in a Hardware Description Language (HDL) into three stages: synthesis, place and route, bitstream generation. A standard format could provide a common description of the various architectures and serve as a bridge between the multitude of open source and closed proprietary tools that deal with the entire process or parts thereof, including the open source Yosys for synthesis and VtR and nextpnr for place and route, to relevant vendor tooling from Xilinx, Intel, Lattice, QuickLogic, etc.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Open Source SystemVerilog Tools in ASIC Design</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/202/news/open-source-systemverilog-tools-in-asic-design/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/202/news/open-source-systemverilog-tools-in-asic-design/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>This post was originally published at &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/blog/2021/07/open-source-systemverilog-tools-in-asic-design/">Antmicro&lt;/a>.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Open source hardware is undeniably undergoing a renaissance whose origin can be traced to the establishment of RISC-V Foundation (later redubbed RISC-V International). The open ISA and ecosystem, in which Antmicro participated since the beginning as a Founding member, has sparked many open source CPU implementations but also new tooling, methodologies and trends which allow for more collaborative and software driven design.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Many of those broader open hardware activities have been finding a home in &lt;a href="https://chipsalliance.org/">CHIPS Alliance&lt;/a>, an open source organization we participate in as a Platinum member alongside Google, Intel, Western Digital, SiFive and others, whose goals explicitly encompass:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Advanced Co-simulation with Renode and Verilator: PolarFire SoC and FastVDMA</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/202/news/renode-and-verilator-polarfire-soc-and-fastvdma/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/202/news/renode-and-verilator-polarfire-soc-and-fastvdma/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>This post was originally published at &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/blog/2021/06/advanced-co-simulation-with-renode-and-verilator/">Antmicro&lt;/a>.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/blog/2019/09/renode-verilator-hdl-co-simulation/">Co-simulating HDL has been possible in Renode since the 1.7.1 release&lt;/a>, but the functionality – critical for hardware/software co-development as well as FPGA use cases – is constantly evolving based on the needs of our customers like Google and Microchip as well as our work in open source groups including &lt;a href="https://chipsalliance.org/">CHIPS Alliance&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://riscv.org/">RISC-V International&lt;/a>. To quickly recap, by co-simulation we mean a scenario where a part of the system is simulated in Renode but some specific peripheral or subsystem is simulated directly from HDL, e.g. Verilog. To achieve this, Renode integrates with Verilator, a fast and popular open source HDL simulator, which we are helping our customers adopt as well as expanding its capabilities to cover new use cases. Peripherals simulated directly from HDL are typically called Verilated peripherals.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Progress on Building Open Source Infrastructure for System Verilog</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/202/news/open-source-infrastructure-for-system-verilog/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/202/news/open-source-infrastructure-for-system-verilog/</guid><description>&lt;p>SystemVerilog is a rich hardware design description and verification language that is seeing increased usage in industry. In the second Deep Dive Cafe Talk by CHIPS Alliance on July 20, Henner Zeller, who is an software developer with Google, provided an excellent in depth technical talk on building out an open source tooling ecosystem around SystemVerilog to provide a common framework that can be used by both functional simulation applications as well as logic synthesis. In case you missed the live presentation, you can watch it &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/xLxNHBzmGiI">here&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Dynamic Scheduling in Verilator – Milestone Towards Open Source UVM</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/202/news/dynamic-scheduling-in-verilator/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/202/news/dynamic-scheduling-in-verilator/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>This post was originally published at &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/blog/2021/05/dynamic-scheduling-in-verilator/">Antmicro&lt;/a>.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>UVM is a verification methodology traditionally used in chip design which has historically been missing from the open source landscape of verification-focused tooling. While new, open source approaches to verification have emerged that include the excellent Python-based Cocotb (that &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/blog/2019/12/testing-usb-cores-with-python-and-cocotb/">we also use&lt;/a> &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/blog/2019/06/verilog-with-cocotb-and-verilator/">and support&lt;/a>) maintained by &lt;a href="https://www.fossi-foundation.org/">FOSSi Foundation&lt;/a>, not everyone can easily adopt it, especially in long-running projects and existing codebases that use a different verification approach. Leading the efforts towards comprehensive UVM / SystemVerilog support in open source tools, we have been gradually completing milestones, getting closer to what will essentially be a modular, collaboration-driven chips design methodology/workflow. Some examples of our activity in this space include &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/blog/2020/12/ibex-support-in-verilator-yosys-via-uhdm-surelog/">enabling open source synthesis and simulation of the Ibex CPU&lt;/a> in &lt;a href="https://github.com/antmicro/verilator/tree/uhdm-verilator">Verilator&lt;/a>/&lt;a href="https://github.com/antmicro/yosys/tree/uhdm-yosys">Yosys&lt;/a> via UHDM/Surelog, and the most recent joint project with Western Digital in which we have developed &lt;a href="https://github.com/antmicro/verilator-dynamic-scheduler-examples">dynamic scheduling in Verilator&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Modular, Open-source FPGA-based LPDDR4 Test Platform</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/202/news/modular-open-source-fpga-based-lpddr4-test-platform/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/202/news/modular-open-source-fpga-based-lpddr4-test-platform/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>This post was originally published at &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/blog/2021/04/lpddr4-test-platform/">Antmicro&lt;/a>.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The flexibility of FPGAs makes them an excellent choice not only for parallel processing applications but also for research and experimentation in a range of technological areas.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We often provide our customers with flexible R&amp;amp;D platforms that can be easily adapted to changing requirements and new use cases as a result of our practice of using open source hardware, software, FPGA IP and tooling.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Goings-on in the FuseSoC Project and Other Open Source Silicon Related News</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/202/news/goings-on-in-the-fusesoc-project-and-other-open-source-silicon-related-news/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/202/news/goings-on-in-the-fusesoc-project-and-other-open-source-silicon-related-news/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>This post was originally published by &lt;a href="https://olofkindgren.blogspot.com/2021/02/fossi-fever-2020.html">Olof Kindgren&lt;/a>&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="fossi-fever-2020">FOSSi Fever 2020&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="fuckload.png" alt="">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2020 was a year with a lot of bad news and so it feels slightly strange to cheerfully write about a very specific topic in the light of this. But there will always be good and bad things happening in the world. So let’s keep fighting the bad things and for now take look at what happened last year within the amazing world of open source silicon. I will start by mentioning the most significant, but by no means the only, milestones for the FOSSi movement as a whole and then take a more personal look at the work where I have been directly involved.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>High-Throughput Open Source PCIe on Xilinx VU19P-Based ASIC Prototyping Platform</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/202/news/high-throughput-open-source-pcie/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/202/news/high-throughput-open-source-pcie/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>This post was originally published at &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/blog/2021/02/high-throughput-open-source-pcie-on-xilinx-vu19/">Antmicro&lt;/a>.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In our daily work at Antmicro we use FPGAs primarily for their flexibility and parallel data processing capabilities that make them remarkably effective in advanced vision and audio processing systems involving high-speed interfaces such as PCI Express, USB, Ethernet, HDMI, SDI etc. that we develop and integrate as open source, portable building blocks. Many of our customers, however, use FPGAs also in a different context, namely for designing ASICs, which is a highly specialized market that typically involves large FPGAs, proprietary flows and IP. In one such project, we were working with one of the largest FPGAs in production today, the 9-million LUT Xilinx VU19. Being a design with considerable complexity, it needed a high-throughput link between the FPGA and the host PC that could be thoroughly benchmarked, analyzed and optimized for the use case.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Enabling Open Source Ibex Synthesis and Simulation in Verilator/Yosys via UHDM/Surelog</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/202/news/ibex-synthesis-and-simulation/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/202/news/ibex-synthesis-and-simulation/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>This post was originally published at &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/blog/2020/12/ibex-support-in-verilator-yosys-via-uhdm-surelog/">Antmicro&lt;/a>.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Throughout 2020 we were hard at work developing proper, portable SystemVerilog support for multiple open-source FPGA and ASIC design tools used by us and our customers, most notably &lt;a href="https://github.com/YosysHQ/yosys">Yosys&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://github.com/verilator/verilator">Verilator&lt;/a>. We strongly believe that the support is a necessary step in building a collaborative ecosystem and scalable and reproducible CIs, especially publicly accessible ones that are common in multi-organization projects such as &lt;a href="https://opentitan.org/">OpenTitan&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://chipsalliance.org/">CHIPS Alliance&lt;/a>. Leading the efforts towards achieving this goal, we’ve been developing a fully open source SystemVerilog parsing flow for Yosys and Verilator using UHDM and Surelog, achieving an important milestone: being able to fully parse, synthesize and simulate OpenTitan’s Ibex core directly from the SystemVerilog source.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>CHIPS SweRV Cores and the Open Tools Ecosystem</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/202/news/chips-swerv-cores-and-the-open-tools-ecosystem/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/202/news/chips-swerv-cores-and-the-open-tools-ecosystem/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>This post was originally published at &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/blog/2020/07/swerv-cores-tools-ecosystem/">Antmicro&lt;/a>.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Antmicro’s open source work spans all parts of the computing stack, from software and AI, to PCBs, FPGAs and, most recently, custom silicon. We connect those areas with an overarching vision of open source tooling and methodology, and a software-driven approach that allows us to move fast and build future-centric solutions. Our partners and customers, many of whom work with us also in the context of organizations such as &lt;a href="https://chipsalliance.org/">CHIPS Alliance&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://riscv.org/">RISC-V&lt;/a>, share our approach to developing open systems. We were recently very happy to be invited to give a talk at the &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ODU1b9amCG8&amp;amp;feature=emb_title">“Production grade, open RISC-V SweRV Core Solutions in CHIPS Alliance”&lt;/a> meetup organized by Western Digital where we presented our systems approach on the example of the open source tools ecosystem that targets their SweRV cores and which we are helping to develop.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Open Source Process Design Kit from Google, SkyWater Technologies and Partners Released</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/202/news/open-source-process-design-kit-from-google-skywater-technologies-and-partners-released/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/202/news/open-source-process-design-kit-from-google-skywater-technologies-and-partners-released/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>This post was originally published at &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/blog/2020/06/skywater-open-source-pdk/">Antmicro&lt;/a>.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The ASIC design and manufacturing flow has for a long time been dominated by proprietary tools and processes. The growing complexity of chip-building has been reinforcing the claim that “hardware is too hard to be open source”, as the cost and time needed to build an ASIC have kept small, more agile, software-oriented teams and individuals away from the hardware domain. Thus, ASICs have not been able to benefit from the enthusiasm and collaboration which have been fuelling software development for decades now. Thanks to the continued effort of many entities which Antmicro is very proud to be among, this is now changing quickly.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Intel joins CHIPS Alliance to promote Advanced Interface Bus (AIB) as an open standard</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/202/news/intel-joins-chips-alliance-to-promote-advanced-interface-bus-aib-as-an-open-standard/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/202/news/intel-joins-chips-alliance-to-promote-advanced-interface-bus-aib-as-an-open-standard/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>Open development for SOCs gets major boost with new collaboration&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>SAN FRANCISCO, Jan. 22, 2020 /PRNewswire/&lt;/strong> — CHIPS Alliance, the leading consortium advancing common and open hardware for interfaces, processors and systems, today announced industry leading chipmaker Intel as it’s newest member. Intel is contributing the Advanced Interface Bus (AIB) to CHIPS Alliance to foster broad adoption.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>CHIPS Alliance is hosted by the Linux Foundation to foster a collaborative environment to accelerate the creation and deployment of open SoCs, peripherals and software tools for use in mobile, computing, consumer electronics and Internet of Things (IoT) applications. The CHIPS Alliance project develops high-quality open source Register Transfer Level (RTL) code and software development tools relevant to the design of open source CPUs, SoCs, and complex peripherals for Field Programmable Gate Arrays (FPGAs) and custom silicon.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Open Source USB test suite</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/202/news/open-source-usb-test-suite/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/202/news/open-source-usb-test-suite/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>Note&lt;/strong>: the open source test suite will be demonstrated at the CHIPS Alliance booth at the &lt;a href="https://tmt.knect365.com/risc-v-summit/">RISC-V Summit 2019&lt;/a> – join us Dec 10-12 in the San Jose Convention Center!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>USB is often a daunting topic for developers, and implementing support for it from scratch is a time consuming task. When the expected result is more complicated than a USB-to-serial bridge, the solution would be to either use a hardware transceiver or, especially for older USB standards, use an open source core to implement one directly in the FPGA fabric. But which core to use?&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>