<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>openroad on CHIPS Alliance</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/188/tags/openroad/</link><description>Recent content in openroad on CHIPS Alliance</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://chipsalliance.org/preview/188/tags/openroad/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Speeding Up OpenROAD For Fast Design Feedback</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/188/news/speeding-up-openroad-for-fast-design-feedback/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/188/news/speeding-up-openroad-for-fast-design-feedback/</guid><description>The OpenROAD project provides an open source ASIC toolchain that reduces the entry barriers to the field of hardware development and allows fast-turnaround feedback about designs, helping to increase the productivity of silicon teams. As such, it’s a great supporting tool, increasingly used in state-of-the-art industrial projects alongside other open source tools like Verilator.
Antmicro has been helping early adopters of OpenROAD-based flows in projects such as SkyWater Shuttle, OpenTitan or more recently, Google’s XLS.</description></item><item><title>Improving the OpenLane ASIC Build Flow with Open Source SystemVerilog Support</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/188/news/improving-the-openlane-asic-build-flow-with-open-source-systemverilog-support/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/188/news/improving-the-openlane-asic-build-flow-with-open-source-systemverilog-support/</guid><description>This post was originally published at Antmicro.
Open source toolchains are key to building collaborative ecosystems, welcoming to new approaches, opportunistic/focused innovations and niche use cases. The ASIC design domain, especially in the view of the rising tensions around manufacturing and supply chains, are in dire need of a software-driven innovation based on an open source approach. The fledgling open source hardware ecosystem has been energized by the success of RISC-V and is now being vastly expanded to cover the entire ASIC design flow by CHIPS Alliance, and Antmicro has been playing a leadership role in both of these organizations as well as offering commercial engineering and support services to assist with early adoption of open source approaches in hardware.</description></item><item><title>Efabless Launches chipIgnite with SkyWater to Bring Chip Creation to the Masses</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/188/news/efabless-launches-chipignite/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/188/news/efabless-launches-chipignite/</guid><description>Program includes a pre-designed carrier chip and automated open source design flow from Efabless SkyWater’s open source SKY130 process is the first node to be used to fabricate chips for the program Initiative removes access barriers by significantly reducing cost and the need for deep semiconductor experience to design chips Efabless, a community chip creation platform, today announced the launch of its new chipIgnite program to bring chip design and fabrication to the masses and a collaboration with SkyWater Technology for the first node supported in the program.</description></item><item><title>New MPW-TWO Program Will Provide Fabrication For Fully Open Source Projects</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/188/news/new-mpw-two-program/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/188/news/new-mpw-two-program/</guid><description>CHIPS Alliance is excited to announce that the hardware development community can submit their open source design projects to Efabless.com for space on their forthcoming shuttle. This opportunity comes after the success of having 40 submissions for the MPW-ONE shuttle; 60% of those designs were submitted by first-time ASIC designers. MPW-TWO is the second Open MPW Shuttle providing fabrication for fully open-source projects using the SkyWater Open Source PDK announced by Google and SkyWater.</description></item><item><title>GitHub Actions Self-hosted Runners, Build Event Server and Google Cloud</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/188/news/github-actions-self-hosted-runners-build-event-server-and-google-cloud/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/188/news/github-actions-self-hosted-runners-build-event-server-and-google-cloud/</guid><description>This post was originally published at Antmicro.
Continuous Integration and smart lifecycle management are key for high-tech product development, which is often a complex and multi-faceted process that requires automation to be efficient and failure-proof. At Antmicro, we’ve been creating various open source cloud and hybrid cloud solutions for our customers, helping them to encapsulate the complexity of their software stack. Lots of those projects cross the hardware/software boundary and involve a mix of open source and proprietary code, which means that fine-grained control of the CI setups are needed to make them work.</description></item><item><title>Goings-on in the FuseSoC Project and Other Open Source Silicon Related News</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/188/news/goings-on-in-the-fusesoc-project-and-other-open-source-silicon-related-news/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/188/news/goings-on-in-the-fusesoc-project-and-other-open-source-silicon-related-news/</guid><description>This post was originally published by Olof Kindgren
FOSSi Fever 2020 2020 was a year with a lot of bad news and so it feels slightly strange to cheerfully write about a very specific topic in the light of this. But there will always be good and bad things happening in the world. So let’s keep fighting the bad things and for now take look at what happened last year within the amazing world of open source silicon.</description></item><item><title>Efabless Joins CHIPS Alliance to Accelerate the Growth of the Open Source Chip Ecosystem</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/188/news/efabless-joins-chips-alliance-to-accelerate-the-growth-of-the-open-source-chip-ecosystem/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/188/news/efabless-joins-chips-alliance-to-accelerate-the-growth-of-the-open-source-chip-ecosystem/</guid><description>Efabless to give a talk on the OpenROAD project at the CHIPS Alliance Workshop on Sept. 17
SAN FRANCISCO, Sept. 15, 2020 – CHIPS Alliance, the leading consortium advancing common and open hardware for interfaces, processors and systems, today welcomed Efabless, a crowdsourcing design platform for custom silicon, as its latest member. Efabless is already an active participant in several open source initiatives that the CHIPS Alliance is involved in, including the OpenROAD project and the Open Source Shuttle Program.</description></item></channel></rss>