<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Opemtitan on CHIPS Alliance</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/204/tags/opemtitan/</link><description>Recent content in Opemtitan on CHIPS Alliance</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://chipsalliance.org/preview/204/tags/opemtitan/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Initial assertion control support in Verilator</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/204/news/initial-assertion-control-support-in-verilator/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/204/news/initial-assertion-control-support-in-verilator/</guid><description>&lt;p>Antmicro is continuously working on improving productivity of ASIC design and verification workflows using open source tools as leaders of the &lt;a href="https://www.chipsalliance.org/">CHIPS Alliance&lt;/a> Tools Workgroup, as well as for customer and R&amp;amp;D projects. Extending &lt;a href="https://github.com/verilator">Verilator&lt;/a> with new verification features is a prominent example of such efforts, with the latest notable improvements including &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/blog/2023/10/running-simple-uvm-testbenches-in-verilator/">initial support for UVM testbenches&lt;/a>, the &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/blog/2024/01/analyze-verilator-processes-and-asts/">astsee tool for Verilator process and AST analysis&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/blog/2024/03/introducing-constrained-randomization-in-verilator/">constrained randomization&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In this article, Antmicro introduces initial support for global assertion control (&lt;a href="https://github.com/verilator/verilator/pull/5010">already part of mainline Verilator&lt;/a>), building on existing support for assertions available in the simulator. These changes simplify verification testing by letting developers enable or disable assertions as required by particular simulation stages or testing scenarios. Antmicro delves into the benefits of this implementation, examines several use cases where assertion control can prove useful and provide considerations for the path towards full support.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Improving the OpenLane ASIC Build Flow with Open Source SystemVerilog Support</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/204/news/improving-the-openlane-asic-build-flow-with-open-source-systemverilog-support/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/204/news/improving-the-openlane-asic-build-flow-with-open-source-systemverilog-support/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>This post was originally published at &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/blog/2021/10/openlane-asic-build-flow-with-systemverliog-support/">Antmicro&lt;/a>.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Open source toolchains are key to building collaborative ecosystems, welcoming to new approaches, opportunistic/focused innovations and niche use cases. The ASIC design domain, especially in the view of the rising tensions around manufacturing and supply chains, are in dire need of a software-driven innovation based on an open source approach. The fledgling open source hardware ecosystem has been energized by the success of RISC-V and is now being vastly expanded to cover the entire ASIC design flow by &lt;a href="https://chipsalliance.org/">CHIPS Alliance&lt;/a>, and Antmicro has been playing a leadership role in both of these organizations as well as offering commercial engineering and support services to assist with early adoption of open source approaches in hardware.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>