<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Topwrap on CHIPS Alliance</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/203/tags/topwrap/</link><description>Recent content in Topwrap on CHIPS Alliance</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://chipsalliance.org/preview/203/tags/topwrap/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Topwrap – open source toolkit for modular, parameterizable digital logic design</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/203/news/topwrap/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/203/news/topwrap/</guid><description>&lt;p>ASIC and FPGA designs consist of distinct blocks of logic bound together by a top-level design. Taking advantage of this modularity and enabling automation and reuse of blocks across designs requires tools for automated processing and generation of top level files, letting you easily parametrize and aggregate the blocks in various configurations.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To this end, Antmicro created &lt;a href="https://github.com/antmicro/topwrap">Topwrap&lt;/a>, an open source toolkit for connecting individual HDL modules into full designs of varying complexity. The toolkit is designed to take advantage of the ever-growing library of open source digital logic blocks that they also &lt;a href="https://github.com/chipsalliance/i3c-core">heavily contribute to&lt;/a> and, thanks to its structuredness, offers a user-friendly graphical interface sitting on top of a well-formed CLI. This in turn lets you mix-and-match high-level GUI-driven design with more fine-grained CLI-level adjustments and present designs in the form of a diagram thanks to the integration with Antmicro’s &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/blog/2024/02/add-web-based-guis-with-pipeline-manager/">Pipeline Manager&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>