<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Interview on CHIPS Alliance</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/201/tags/interview/</link><description>Recent content in Interview on CHIPS Alliance</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://chipsalliance.org/preview/201/tags/interview/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Listen to CHIPS Alliance’s Rob Mains on EE Journal’s FishFry Podcast</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/201/news/listen-to-chips-alliances-rob-mains-on-ee-journals-fishfry-podcast/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/201/news/listen-to-chips-alliances-rob-mains-on-ee-journals-fishfry-podcast/</guid><description>&lt;p>CHIPS Alliance’s general manager Rob Mains joined Amelia Dalton at EE Journal’s FishFry podcast for a lively discussion about how we’re working to make chip design more accessible. Rob discussed CHIPS Alliance’s work with RISC-V International to develop a new &lt;a href="https://chipsalliance.org/announcement/2021/03/24/risc-v-international-omnixtend-working-group/">unified memory standard&lt;/a>, along with our work to accelerate the design of open source chipsets with the &lt;a href="https://chipsalliance.org/announcement/2020/07/16/aib-2-0-draft-specification/">AIB 2.0 specification&lt;/a>. The conversation also touched on our efforts to provide better support for SystemVerilog using open source tools and to create a dynamic stratified scheduler implementation in Verilator.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Semiconductor Engineering: About The SweRV Core EH2</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/201/news/semiconductor-engineering-swerv-core-eh2/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/201/news/semiconductor-engineering-swerv-core-eh2/</guid><description>&lt;p>In mid-May, CHIPS Alliance announced the open sourcing of the SweRV Core EH2 and SweRV Core EL2 designed by &lt;a href="https://www.westerndigital.com/company/innovations/risc-v">Western Digital&lt;/a>. These cores, as well as the earlier EH1, are now supported by Codasip’s SweRV Core Support Package which provides all of the components necessary to design, implement, test, and write software for a SweRV Core-based system-on-chip. But what is SweRV Core EH2?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The SweRV Core EH1 was the first to be released through CHIPS Alliance and was a core aimed at high-end embedded applications including Western Digital’s flash controllers and SSDs. The core is a dual issue, superscalar, high-performance core with 9 pipeline stages. The EH2 is an exciting further development aimed at delivering even more performance for IoT, artificial intelligence and data-intensive embedded applications.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>CHIPS Alliance featured in All About Circuits</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/201/news/chips-alliance-featured-in-all-about-circuits/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/201/news/chips-alliance-featured-in-all-about-circuits/</guid><description>&lt;p>All About Circuits recently featured an interview with Ted Marena, Yunsup Lee, Amir Salek, and Zvonimir Bandic, discussing the formation of the CHIPS Alliance, its relationship to the RISC-V Foundation, the CHIPS Alliance’s open development model, and initial open source contributions.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.allaboutcircuits.com/news/linux-chips-alliance-open-source-hardware-collaboration/">Read the article&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Podcast – Embedded Computing Design – Five Minutes With… Zvonimir Bandic, Chairman, Chips Alliance</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/201/news/podcast-embedded-computing-design-five-minutes-with-zvonimir-bandic-chairman-chips-alliance/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/201/news/podcast-embedded-computing-design-five-minutes-with-zvonimir-bandic-chairman-chips-alliance/</guid><description>&lt;p>Zvonimir Bandic wears lots of hats. He is the Senior Director of Hardware Platforms for &lt;a href="https://www.westerndigital.com/">Western Digital&lt;/a>; he’s a Member of the Board of Directors for the &lt;a href="https://riscv.org/">RISC-V Foundation&lt;/a>, and he’s the Chairman of the &lt;a href="https://chipsalliance.org/">Chips Alliance&lt;/a>. It’s that latter capacity that we discussed in this week’s Five Minutes With…discussion. The organization focuses on things like open source hardware, software tools, RTL development, and related topics. They will be holding their &lt;a href="https://events.linuxfoundation.org/events/chips-alliance-workshop-2019/">inaugural workshop&lt;/a> in just a few weeks, so it was timely to understand the purpose of the Alliance. And now I do, as will you.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>