<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Tutorial on CHIPS Alliance</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/209/tags/tutorial/</link><description>Recent content in Tutorial on CHIPS Alliance</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://chipsalliance.org/preview/209/tags/tutorial/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Analyze Verilator processes and ASTs with the astsee suite</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/209/news/analyze-verilator-processes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/209/news/analyze-verilator-processes/</guid><description>&lt;p>Among other things, Antmicro’s work towards improving the vertical integration potential of customers designing ASIC solutions often sees them enhance one of the flagship open source projects in this space, Verilator which complements - and in fact is &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/blog/2023/09/dpi-support-in-renode-for-hdl-co-simulation-with-verilator-and-questa/">often used alongside&lt;/a> - Antmicro’s own functional simulation framework, &lt;a href="https://about.renode.io">Renode&lt;/a>. Besides contributing bug fixes and other quality-of-life improvements into Verilator, Antmicro also develops new functionalities that &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/blog/2023/10/running-simple-uvm-testbenches-in-verilator/">expand its use cases towards e.g. UVM verification&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/blog/2023/09/accelerating-model-generation-in-verilator/">continuously improve overall performance&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>SATA Design Implementation on FPGAs with Open Source Tools</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/209/news/sata-design-implementation-on-fpgas-with-open-source-tools/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/209/news/sata-design-implementation-on-fpgas-with-open-source-tools/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>This post was originally published at &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/blog/2021/12/sata-with-open-source-fpga-tools/">Antmicro&lt;/a>.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Real-world FPGAs designs often require high rate transmission protocols such as PCIe, USB and SATA which rely on high speed transceivers for external communication. These protocols are used to interface with various devices such as graphics cards and storage devices, and many of our clients reach out to us specifically because they need the &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/technologies/fpga/">flexibility, high-throughput and low-latency characteristics of FPGAs&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In particular, for customers that deal with high data volumes (which is very common in video applications), implementing SATA to communicate and transfer data with e.g. an SSD hard drive is a must.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Software-driven ASIC Prototyping Using the Open Source SkyWater Shuttle</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/209/news/software-driven-asic-prototyping-using-the-open-source-skywater-shuttle/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/209/news/software-driven-asic-prototyping-using-the-open-source-skywater-shuttle/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>This post was originally published at &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/blog/2021/12/sw-driven-asics-with-skywater-shuttle/">Antmicro&lt;/a>.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The growing cost and complexity of advanced nodes, supply chain issues and demand for silicon independence mean that the ASIC design process is in need of innovation. Antmicro believes the answer to those challenges is bound to come from the software-driven, open source approach which has shaped the Internet and gave rise to modern cloud computing. Applying the methodologies of software design to ASICs is however notoriously viewed as difficult, given the closed nature of many components needed to build chips – tools, IP and process design kits, or PDKs for short, as well as the slow turnaround of manufacturing.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Automatic SystemVerilog Linting in GitHub Actions with Verible</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/209/news/automatic-systemverilog-linting-in-github-actions-with-verible/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/209/news/automatic-systemverilog-linting-in-github-actions-with-verible/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>This post was originally published at &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/blog/2021/08/verible-integration-with-github-actions/">Antmicro&lt;/a>.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>With the recent advances in open source &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/blog/2021/07/open-source-systemverilog-tools-in-asic-design/">ASIC development tools&lt;/a> such as Verible, it has become easier to automate tasks and boost developer productivity. The Verible linter is a static code analysis tool that has been helping us and our collaborators to spot and fix stylistic errors and bugs in SystemVerilog code.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="cicd-for-smaller-backlog-and-better-test-reliability">CI/CD for smaller backlog and better test reliability&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>As part of our work within the newly established CHIPS Alliance SystemVerilog subgroup, Antmicro has made further steps to facilitate SystemVerilog workflows with Verible, by providing an easy to use &lt;a href="https://github.com/chipsalliance/verible-linter-action">Verible Linter GitHub Action&lt;/a>. Combined with another open source tool called &lt;a href="https://github.com/reviewdog/reviewdog">Reviewdog&lt;/a>, the action allows you to easily perform automatic code style checks and code review.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Open Source Custom GitHub Actions Runners with Google Cloud and Terraform</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/209/news/open-source-custom-github-actions-runners-with-google-cloud-and-terraform/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/209/news/open-source-custom-github-actions-runners-with-google-cloud-and-terraform/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>This post was originally published at &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/blog/2021/08/open-source-github-actions-runners-with-gcp-and-terraform/">Antmicro&lt;/a>.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In order to fulfill our internal and our customers’ needs, we have developed and successfully deployed an &lt;a href="https://github.com/antmicro/runner">open source custom GitHub Actions runner&lt;/a> that allows us to mix the GitHub default and your custom hardware and software. The runner software itself operates within a Google Cloud Platform project, spawns &lt;a href="https://cloud.google.com/compute/docs/instances">Compute Engine instances&lt;/a> and orchestrates the build, providing a number of interesting advantages that were needed in our ASIC and FPGA-related work. As is typical for us, we have released all the necessary components as open source – read on to learn how the solution works, the benefits it offers and how to build and deploy this software in your organization (which we can also help with as part of our commercial support and engineering services).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>What You Need to Know About Verilator Open Source Tooling</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/209/news/what-you-need-to-know-about-verilator-open-source-tooling/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/209/news/what-you-need-to-know-about-verilator-open-source-tooling/</guid><description>&lt;p>Verilator is a high performance, open source functional simulator that has gained tremendous popularity in its usage and adoption in the verification of chip design. The ASIC development community has widely embraced Verilator as an effective, often even superior alternative to proprietary solutions, and it is now the standard approach in RISC-V CPU design as the community has worked to provide Verilator simulation capabilities out of the box. CHIPS Alliance and RISC-V leaders Antmicro and Western Digital have been collaborating to make Verilator even more useful for ASIC design purposes, working towards supporting industry-standard verification methods in a completely open source flow.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>GitHub Actions Self-hosted Runners, Build Event Server and Google Cloud</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/209/news/github-actions-self-hosted-runners-build-event-server-and-google-cloud/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/209/news/github-actions-self-hosted-runners-build-event-server-and-google-cloud/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>This post was originally published at &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/blog/2021/03/github-actions-self-hosted-runners/">Antmicro&lt;/a>.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Continuous Integration and smart lifecycle management are key for high-tech product development, which is often a complex and multi-faceted process that requires automation to be efficient and failure-proof. At Antmicro, we’ve been creating various open source cloud and hybrid cloud solutions for our customers, helping them to encapsulate the complexity of their software stack. Lots of those projects cross the hardware/software boundary and involve a mix of open source and proprietary code, which means that fine-grained control of the CI setups are needed to make them work.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>SystemVerilog Linting and Formatting with FuseSoC – Verible Integration</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/209/news/systemverilog-linting-and-formatting-with-fusesoc-verible-integration/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/209/news/systemverilog-linting-and-formatting-with-fusesoc-verible-integration/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>This post was originally published at &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/blog/2020/04/systemverilog-linter-and-formatter-in-fusesoc/">Antmicro&lt;/a>.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Although new ASIC design methodologies and tools such as Chisel are on the rise, most ASIC projects still use SystemVerilog, the support of which in open source tools has traditionally lagged behind. This is unfortunate, as using proprietary alternatives with the CI systems of open source projects is neither scalable due to licensing costs and restrictions nor simple due to the need for license management and obfuscation.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>