<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Uvm on CHIPS Alliance</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/201/tags/uvm/</link><description>Recent content in Uvm on CHIPS Alliance</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://chipsalliance.org/preview/201/tags/uvm/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Initial assertion control support in Verilator</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/201/news/initial-assertion-control-support-in-verilator/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/201/news/initial-assertion-control-support-in-verilator/</guid><description>&lt;p>Antmicro is continuously working on improving productivity of ASIC design and verification workflows using open source tools as leaders of the &lt;a href="https://www.chipsalliance.org/">CHIPS Alliance&lt;/a> Tools Workgroup, as well as for customer and R&amp;amp;D projects. Extending &lt;a href="https://github.com/verilator">Verilator&lt;/a> with new verification features is a prominent example of such efforts, with the latest notable improvements including &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/blog/2023/10/running-simple-uvm-testbenches-in-verilator/">initial support for UVM testbenches&lt;/a>, the &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/blog/2024/01/analyze-verilator-processes-and-asts/">astsee tool for Verilator process and AST analysis&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/blog/2024/03/introducing-constrained-randomization-in-verilator/">constrained randomization&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In this article, Antmicro introduces initial support for global assertion control (&lt;a href="https://github.com/verilator/verilator/pull/5010">already part of mainline Verilator&lt;/a>), building on existing support for assertions available in the simulator. These changes simplify verification testing by letting developers enable or disable assertions as required by particular simulation stages or testing scenarios. Antmicro delves into the benefits of this implementation, examines several use cases where assertion control can prove useful and provide considerations for the path towards full support.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Initial Open Source Support for UVM Testbenches in Verilator</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/201/news/initial-open-source-support-for-uvm-testbenches-in-verilator/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/201/news/initial-open-source-support-for-uvm-testbenches-in-verilator/</guid><description>&lt;p>Leading the efforts of the Tools Workgroup in CHIPS Alliance, across a variety of customer projects, as well as its own R&amp;amp;D, Antmicro is actively looking for and capturing the productivity enhancements that can be achieved in ASIC design using open source. Developing and using open source-enhanced workflows is one thing, but in order for the general shift towards open source to happen, open source support for tooling and methodologies that are already prevalent across the chipmaking industry is necessary.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Progress in open source SystemVerilog / UVM support in Verilator</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/201/news/progress-in-open-source-systemverilog-uvm-support-in-verilator/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/201/news/progress-in-open-source-systemverilog-uvm-support-in-verilator/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://github.com/verilator/verilator">Verilator&lt;/a> is a shining example of a widely-accepted open source tool which provides state-of-the-art results in the ASIC design space. It is commonly used for simulation and testing, but originally, due to the lack of capability to run event-driven simulations, Verilator wasn’t even considered capable of handling UVM (Universal Verification Methodology) testbenches implemented in SystemVerilog which require scheduling and other features notably absent from the tool. For some time now, Antmicro, together with Western Digital, Google and others in the &lt;a href="https://chipsalliance.org/">CHIPS Alliance&lt;/a>, has been working on enabling fully open source support for SystemVerilog UVM testbenches in Verilator. This has already resulted in significant breakthroughs we have described in this blog, such as implementing &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/blog/2021/12/coroutines-for-dynamic-scheduling-in-verilator/">event-driven simulation capabilities&lt;/a> in Verilator which has &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/jevinskie/status/1602834358561566720">enabled new and exciting use cases&lt;/a>. Since then, on the road to proper UVM testbench support, Antmicro has been working on adding various SystemVerilog constructs and UVM-specific elements into Verilator, which bring us much closer to the goal - the current status and next goals will be described in more detail in this blog note.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Towards UVM: Using Coroutines for Low-overhead Dynamic Scheduling in Verilator</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/201/news/towards-uvm-using-coroutines/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/201/news/towards-uvm-using-coroutines/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>This post was originally published at &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/blog/2021/12/coroutines-for-dynamic-scheduling-in-verilator/">Antmicro&lt;/a>.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Verilator is a popular open source SystemVerilog simulator and one of the key tools in the ASIC and FPGA ecosystem, which Antmicro is actively using and developing, e.g. by &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/blog/2021/09/co-simulation-for-zynq-with-renode-and-verilator/">enabling co-simulation with Renode&lt;/a> or &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/blog/2019/06/verilog-with-cocotb-and-verilator/">Cocotb integration&lt;/a>. It’s also one of the fastest available HDL simulators, including proprietary alternatives. It achieves that speed by generating highly optimized C++ code from a given hardware design. Verilator does a lot of work at compile-time to make the generated (‘verilated’) code extremely fast, such as ordering statements in an optimal way.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>What You Need to Know About Verilator Open Source Tooling</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/201/news/what-you-need-to-know-about-verilator-open-source-tooling/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/201/news/what-you-need-to-know-about-verilator-open-source-tooling/</guid><description>&lt;p>Verilator is a high performance, open source functional simulator that has gained tremendous popularity in its usage and adoption in the verification of chip design. The ASIC development community has widely embraced Verilator as an effective, often even superior alternative to proprietary solutions, and it is now the standard approach in RISC-V CPU design as the community has worked to provide Verilator simulation capabilities out of the box. CHIPS Alliance and RISC-V leaders Antmicro and Western Digital have been collaborating to make Verilator even more useful for ASIC design purposes, working towards supporting industry-standard verification methods in a completely open source flow.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>