<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>swerv on CHIPS Alliance</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/199/tags/swerv/</link><description>Recent content in swerv on CHIPS Alliance</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://chipsalliance.org/preview/199/tags/swerv/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Improving the OpenLane ASIC Build Flow with Open Source SystemVerilog Support</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/199/news/improving-the-openlane-asic-build-flow-with-open-source-systemverilog-support/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/199/news/improving-the-openlane-asic-build-flow-with-open-source-systemverilog-support/</guid><description>This post was originally published at Antmicro.
Open source toolchains are key to building collaborative ecosystems, welcoming to new approaches, opportunistic/focused innovations and niche use cases. The ASIC design domain, especially in the view of the rising tensions around manufacturing and supply chains, are in dire need of a software-driven innovation based on an open source approach. The fledgling open source hardware ecosystem has been energized by the success of RISC-V and is now being vastly expanded to cover the entire ASIC design flow by CHIPS Alliance, and Antmicro has been playing a leadership role in both of these organizations as well as offering commercial engineering and support services to assist with early adoption of open source approaches in hardware.</description></item><item><title>CHIPS SweRV Cores and the Open Tools Ecosystem</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/199/news/chips-swerv-cores-and-the-open-tools-ecosystem/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/199/news/chips-swerv-cores-and-the-open-tools-ecosystem/</guid><description>This post was originally published at Antmicro.
Antmicro’s open source work spans all parts of the computing stack, from software and AI, to PCBs, FPGAs and, most recently, custom silicon. We connect those areas with an overarching vision of open source tooling and methodology, and a software-driven approach that allows us to move fast and build future-centric solutions. Our partners and customers, many of whom work with us also in the context of organizations such as CHIPS Alliance and RISC-V, share our approach to developing open systems.</description></item><item><title>Semiconductor Engineering: About The SweRV Core EH2</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/199/news/semiconductor-engineering-swerv-core-eh2/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/199/news/semiconductor-engineering-swerv-core-eh2/</guid><description>In mid-May, CHIPS Alliance announced the open sourcing of the SweRV Core EH2 and SweRV Core EL2 designed by Western Digital. These cores, as well as the earlier EH1, are now supported by Codasip’s SweRV Core Support Package which provides all of the components necessary to design, implement, test, and write software for a SweRV Core-based system-on-chip. But what is SweRV Core EH2?
The SweRV Core EH1 was the first to be released through CHIPS Alliance and was a core aimed at high-end embedded applications including Western Digital’s flash controllers and SSDs.</description></item><item><title>CHIPS Alliance’s Newly Enhanced SweRV Cores Available to All for Free</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/199/news/newly-enhanced-swerv-cores/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/199/news/newly-enhanced-swerv-cores/</guid><description>CHIPS Alliance to host online event to help community innovating with SweRV Core EH2 and EL2 Solutions
SAN FRANCISCO, May 14, 2020 – CHIPS Alliance, the leading consortium advancing common and open hardware for interfaces, processors and systems, today announced new enhancements to the SweRV Core™ EH2 and SweRV Core EL2, developed for the open-source community by Western Digital. Since the introduction of the cores earlier this year, the CHIPS Alliance has worked with its community to exhaustedly validate the cores through a transparent and rigorous process, as well as incorporate a variety of new updates.</description></item><item><title>Linux Foundation to Host CHIPS Alliance Project to Propel Industry Innovation Through Open Source CPU Chip and SoC Design</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/199/news/linux-foundation-to-host-chips-alliance-project-to-propel-industry-innovation-through-open-source-cpu-chip-and-soc-design/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/199/news/linux-foundation-to-host-chips-alliance-project-to-propel-industry-innovation-through-open-source-cpu-chip-and-soc-design/</guid><description>New Linux Foundation Project to Foster Flexible, Next-Generation Chip Design for Diverse Data-Centric Applications and Workloads
SAN FRANCISCO – March 11, 2019 – The Linux Foundation, the nonprofit organization enabling mass innovation through open source, today announced its intent to form the CHIPS Alliance project to host and curate high-quality open source code relevant to the design of silicon devices. CHIPS Alliance will foster a collaborative environment that will enable accelerated creation and deployment of more efficient and flexible chip designs for use in mobile, computing, consumer electronics, and Internet of Things (IoT) applications.</description></item></channel></rss>