<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Events on CHIPS Alliance</title><link>https://chipsalliance.github.io/chips-alliance-website/events/</link><description>Recent content in Events on CHIPS Alliance</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 03 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://chipsalliance.github.io/chips-alliance-website/events/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>RISC-V at embedded world</title><link>https://chipsalliance.github.io/chips-alliance-website/events/event-2/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.github.io/chips-alliance-website/events/event-2/</guid><description>RISC-V is a global standard available under an open, royalty-free license exhibiting at embedded world 2023 to highlight members and the broader RISC-V ecosystem.</description></item><item><title>Zephyr at embedded world</title><link>https://chipsalliance.github.io/chips-alliance-website/events/event-3/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.github.io/chips-alliance-website/events/event-3/</guid><description>Visit The Zephyr® Project and various members at embedded world 2023 as we showcase the best-in-class RTOS for connected resource-constrained devices.</description></item><item><title>CHIPS Alliance Fall Workshop 2022</title><link>https://chipsalliance.github.io/chips-alliance-website/events/chips-biannual-technology-update-2022-2/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.github.io/chips-alliance-website/events/chips-biannual-technology-update-2022-2/</guid><description>Check out the presentations below, and watch the replay here
Porting Android to RISC-V Alibaba – Guoyin Chen and Han Mao, Alibaba (replay) Practical Adoption of Open Source System Verilog Tools – Michael Gielda, Antmicro (replay) Chisel and FIRRTL for Next-Generation SoC Designs– Jack Koenig, SiFive (replay) OpenFASOC: Automated Open Source Analog and Mixed-Signals IC Generation – Mehdi Saligane, University of Michigan (UMICH) (replay) FPGA Tooling Interoperability with the FPGA Interchange Format – Maciej Kurc, Antmicro (replay) OmniXtend: Scalability and LPC – Jaco Hofmann, Western Digital Corporation (replay) Open Source NVME IP with AI Acceleration – Anand Kulkarni, Western Digital Corporation and Karol Gugala, Antmicro (replay) Automating Analog Layout using ALIGN – Sachin Sapatnekar, University of Minnesota (UMN) (replay) Watch the Replay</description></item><item><title>CHIPS Alliance First 2022 Biannual Technology Update</title><link>https://chipsalliance.github.io/chips-alliance-website/events/chips-biannual-technology-update-2022-1/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.github.io/chips-alliance-website/events/chips-biannual-technology-update-2022-1/</guid><description>Check out the presentations below:
Introduction – Rob Mains, CHIPS Alliance Updates of Android on RISC-V – Han Mao, Alibaba Chisel and FIRRTL for Next-Generation SoC Designs– Jack Koenig, SiFive Introducting the F4PGA Workgroup– Michael Gielda, Karol Gugala, Antmicro Chiplet IP Protocol– Dave Kehlet, Intel NVMe Computational Storage Processor for Edge &amp;amp; Datacenter Applications, Anand Kulkarni, Wester Digital Towards Open Source Models of Cryogenic CMOS : Brian Hoskins and Pragya Shrestha, NIST Latest Statistics from Google’s No Cost Shuttle Program : Tim Ansell, Google Watch the Replay</description></item><item><title>Big Event</title><link>https://chipsalliance.github.io/chips-alliance-website/events/event-1/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.github.io/chips-alliance-website/events/event-1/</guid><description>Description about big event.</description></item></channel></rss>