<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>CHIPS Alliance</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/103/</link><description>Recent content on CHIPS Alliance</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 09 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://chipsalliance.org/preview/103/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>CHIPS Technology Update - November 2023</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/103/events/chips-2023-fall-event/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/103/events/chips-2023-fall-event/</guid><description>Check out the presentations below, and watch the replay here
Project Open Se Cura – Kenny Vassigh, Bangfei Pan, Cindy Liu, Kai Yick, Google, Michael Gielda, Antmicro, Brian Murray, Verisilicon (slides) Caliptra Workgroup Update - Andres Lagar-Cavilla, Google (slides) Enabling UVM testbenches in Verilator - Michael Gielda, Karol Gugala, Antmicro (slides) FuseSOC: Package manager and build abstraction tool for FPGA/ASIC development - Olof Kindgren, Qamcom (slides) CHIPYard: An Open Source RISC-V Design Frameowrk - Sagar Karandikar, U.</description></item><item><title>Initial Open Source Support for UVM Testbenches in Verilator</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/103/news/initial-open-source-support-for-uvm-testbenches-in-verilator/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/103/news/initial-open-source-support-for-uvm-testbenches-in-verilator/</guid><description>Leading the efforts of the Tools Workgroup in CHIPS Alliance, across a variety of customer projects, as well as its own R&amp;amp;D, Antmicro is actively looking for and capturing the productivity enhancements that can be achieved in ASIC design using open source. Developing and using open source-enhanced workflows is one thing, but in order for the general shift towards open source to happen, open source support for tooling and methodologies that are already prevalent across the chipmaking industry is necessary.</description></item><item><title>RISC-V Summit North America 2023</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/103/events/riscv_na_2023/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/103/events/riscv_na_2023/</guid><description>Please join us at the RISC-V North American Summit November 7 - 8
Be sure to come visit us at the CHIPS Alliance booth at the event.
Details here:</description></item><item><title>CHIPS Alliance at the Open Compute Project Global Summit</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/103/events/chips_ocp_2023/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/103/events/chips_ocp_2023/</guid><description>Please join us at the Open Compute Project Global Summit to hear about the Caliptra Root of Trust collaborative project.
Be sure to come visit us at booth C37 hosted by the Linux Foundation at the event.
Details here</description></item><item><title>Verilator Model Generation Performance Improvements and Initial Multithreaded Verilation Support</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/103/news/verilator-model-generation-performance-improvements-and-initial-multithreaded-verilation-support/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/103/news/verilator-model-generation-performance-improvements-and-initial-multithreaded-verilation-support/</guid><description>Verilator can boast the status of one of the most widely used free and open source digital design tools for ASIC and FPGA development. To stay on top of the ever-increasing complexity of ASIC and FPGA devices, as users and contributors, Antmicro, a CHIPS Alliance member and part of the Tools Workgroup, has been actively working on improving the tool and its ecosystem, including adding co-simulation capabilities with Renode, adding support for SystemVerilog UVM testbenches to Verilator, or improving scalability for very large designs.</description></item><item><title>Progress in open source SystemVerilog / UVM support in Verilator</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/103/news/progress-in-open-source-systemverilog-uvm-support-in-verilator/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/103/news/progress-in-open-source-systemverilog-uvm-support-in-verilator/</guid><description>Verilator is a shining example of a widely-accepted open source tool which provides state-of-the-art results in the ASIC design space. It is commonly used for simulation and testing, but originally, due to the lack of capability to run event-driven simulations, Verilator wasn’t even considered capable of handling UVM (Universal Verification Methodology) testbenches implemented in SystemVerilog which require scheduling and other features notably absent from the tool. For some time now, Antmicro, together with Western Digital, Google and others in the CHIPS Alliance, has been working on enabling fully open source support for SystemVerilog UVM testbenches in Verilator.</description></item><item><title>CHIPS Alliance Summer Workshop 2023</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/103/events/chips-biannual-technology-update-2022_13_07/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/103/events/chips-biannual-technology-update-2022_13_07/</guid><description>Check out the presentations below, and watch the replay here
Caliptra &amp;amp; VeeR continuous integration ecosystem – Michael Gielda, Antmicro (slides) Caliptra: Validating firmware against multiple hardware models in CI - Kor Nielsen, Google OmniXtend: coherent scaleout over commodity fabrics - Jaco Hoffman, Westen Digital (slides) CHISEL 3 and Beyond - Jack Koenig, SiFive (slides) Single Source library for digital design and virtual prototyping - Mikhail Moiseev, Intel (slides) Building Confidence in Open IC Design using OpenFASOC - Mehdi Saligane, University of Michigan (slides) Watch the Replay</description></item><item><title>Open source and CI-driven RTL testing and verification for Caliptra’s RISC-V VeeR core</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/103/news/open-source-rtl-ci-testing-and-verification-for-caliptra-veer/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/103/news/open-source-rtl-ci-testing-and-verification-for-caliptra-veer/</guid><description>As part of CHIPS Alliance’s mission to enable a software-driven approach to silicon, working with Google and other CHIPS members, Antmicro has been developing and improving a growing number of open source tools to enable effective, CI-driven silicon development.
Fully reproducible and scalable workflows based on open source tooling are especially beneficial for efforts spanning across multiple industrial and academic actors such as Caliptra, a Root of Trust project driven by Google, AMD, NVIDIA and Microsoft which recently joined CHIPS in order to host the ongoing development and provide the necessary structure, working environment and support for the reference implementation of the standard, originally hosted by Open Compute Project.</description></item><item><title>Integrating the Language Server Protocol in Verible</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/103/news/integrating-language-server-protocol-in-verible/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/103/news/integrating-language-server-protocol-in-verible/</guid><description>A more collaborative, open and software driven ASIC design methodology pioneered by the CHIPS Alliance requires an open source tooling stack to enable sharing of workflows, artifacts and fostering a free exchange of insights and improvements.
While internally often using new design methodologies and languages such as Migen, Chisel or XLS, Antmicro is conscious of the fact that a lot of the world’s ASIC development involves SystemVerilog and UVM, and so we are working on bridging traditional and new ASIC development methodologies as described in a recent blog note.</description></item><item><title>CHIPS Alliance Fall Workshop 2022</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/103/events/chips-biannual-technology-update-2022-2/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/103/events/chips-biannual-technology-update-2022-2/</guid><description>Check out the presentations below, and watch the replay here
Caliptra – Bryan Kelly, Microsoft SBOM and HBOM / Zephyr - Kate Stewart, Linux Foundation F4PGA tools in the classroom - Mike Wirthlin, Jeff Goeders, BYU (slides) Datasets for Machine Learning for Chip Design - Aman Arora, UT-Austin (slides) Open source SystemVerilog / UVM support and scaling for large designs in Verilator 5.0 and beyond, Michael Gielda, Antmicro (slides) Lowering barriers to chip design using OpenFASOC, AWG activities and tapeouts, Mehdi Saligane, University of Michigan (slides) Global Foundries Open PDK, Karthik Chandrasekaran, Global Foundries Caravel SOC Learnings, Mohammed Kassem, Efabless, (slides) Intel Compiler for SystemC, Mikhail Moiseev, Intel (slides) Renode co-simulation for Caravel, Peter Gielda, Antmicro (slides) Watch the Replay</description></item><item><title>CHIPS Alliance Welcomes the Caliptra Open Source Root of Trust Project</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/103/news/chips-alliance-welcomes-the-caliptra-open-source-root-of-trust-project/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/103/news/chips-alliance-welcomes-the-caliptra-open-source-root-of-trust-project/</guid><description>SAN FRANCISCO, December 13, 2022 – CHIPS Alliance, a Linux Foundation project and leading consortium advancing common and open hardware for interfaces, processors and systems, announced that Caliptra, the open source root of trust project founded by technology leaders AMD, Google, Microsoft and NVIDIA, has joined CHIPS Alliance to enable an open, collaborative community-driven approach to hardware security.
Caliptra is a new specification for an open source silicon root of trust (RoT) designed to meet the enhanced security requirements of modern edge and confidential computing workloads.</description></item><item><title>Joint Analog Workgroup / MOS-AK Panel Session</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/103/news/joint-analog-workgroup-mos-ak-panel-session/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/103/news/joint-analog-workgroup-mos-ak-panel-session/</guid><description>Please join us for a special joint panel webinar session for the CHIPS Alliance Analog Workgroup and MOS-AK Foundation.
This panel will feature speakers with 20 minute talks on the following topic areas:
@Mehdi Saligane : Introduction to the open source EDA tool flow for IC design (with reference to [1]) @Makris Nikolaos : EKV3 in NGSPICE using ADMSXL @Keiter, Eric R : Xyce and its support for commercial (hSpice/spectre) libs/syntax @Tim Edwards : his work on the SkyWater 130 nm compatibility with ngspice @Kevin Cameron : update on the P1800 (SystemVerilog) AMS standardization efforts (public doc [2]) There will be time for Q &amp;amp; A after each talk and conversation after the presentation completion.</description></item><item><title>CHIPS Alliance Fall 2022 Technology Update December 15</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/103/news/chips-alliance-fall-2022-technology-update-december-15/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/103/news/chips-alliance-fall-2022-technology-update-december-15/</guid><description>Please join us on December 15 at 8:30 am PT either in person at Google or virtually for a CHIPS technology update featuring many exciting speakers. Details and registration are here: https://events.linuxfoundation.org/chips-biannual-technology-update/</description></item><item><title>F4PGA open source flow gets a new Python-based build system and CLI tool</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/103/news/f4pga-open-source-flow-gets-a-new-python-based-build-system-and-cli-tool/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/103/news/f4pga-open-source-flow-gets-a-new-python-based-build-system-and-cli-tool/</guid><description>One of the most recent projects developed within the workgroup is the unified f4pga CLI tool. In the broader context of our continuous efforts to make the FPGA space more unified and flexible, creating the f4pga CLI tool was a logical next step – it allowed us to wrap the underlying tools into a single CLI, making the F4PGA toolchain a more complete flow. The currently supported architectures are AMD’s (former Xilinx) 7 Series, Lattice’s iCE40 and QuickLogic’s EOS S3.</description></item><item><title>Skywater</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/103/news/skywater/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/103/news/skywater/</guid><description>It’s great to learn that Google announced the expansion of its partnership with SkyWater Technology. They are working together to release an open source process design kit (PDK) for SKY90-FD, SkyWater’s commercial 90nm fully depleted silicon on insulator (FDSOI) CMOS process technology. SKY90-FD is based on MIT Lincoln Laboratory’s 90 nm commercial FDSOI technology, and enables designers to create complex integrated circuits for a diverse range of applications.
You can read more @ https://opensource.</description></item><item><title>Antmicro DDR5 Rowhammer Testing Framework</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/103/news/1212/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/103/news/1212/</guid><description>CHIPS Alliance is excited by the Antmicro announcement of the extensible, open, Rowhammer testing framework for DDR5. Read a detailed description of their work here: https://antmicro.com/blog/2022/08/extending-the-open-source-rowhammer-testing-framework-to-ddr5/
Here are some graphics of the work:</description></item><item><title>Catch us at DAC 59 in San Francisco starting July 11</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/103/news/catch-us-at-dac-59-in-san-francisco-starting-july-11/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/103/news/catch-us-at-dac-59-in-san-francisco-starting-july-11/</guid><description>Come learn about open source hardware and CHIPS Alliance at next week’s 59th Design Automation Conference in San Francisco. We will be at kiosk 2344 in the RISC-V pavilion. You can also here out talk at 12:30 Monday in the Open Source Central Theatre (booth 2338). We are also in a DAC Pavilion Panel: Is Democratization of Chip Design Already Happening? at 2:30 on Monday. Look forward to an exciting day in SF!</description></item><item><title>Enhanced System Verilog Support for Yosys via Antmicro plug-in</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/103/news/enhanced-system-verilog-support-for-yosys-via-antmicro-plug-in/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/103/news/enhanced-system-verilog-support-for-yosys-via-antmicro-plug-in/</guid><description>CHIPS Alliance is pleased to see the announcement by Antmicro for its development and contribution to the open source hardware community to provide a easy to use plug-in for any version of Yosys to allow import of System Verilog based designs. This development is made possible by the underlying utilization of the Unified Hardware Data Model (UHDM), a key open source data representation upon which EDA applications can be built. Details can be seen here from Antmicro: https://antmicro.</description></item><item><title>Alibaba Cloud Announced Progress in Porting Android Functions onto RISC-V</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/103/news/alibaba-cloud-announced-progress-in-porting-android-functions-onto-risc-v/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/103/news/alibaba-cloud-announced-progress-in-porting-android-functions-onto-risc-v/</guid><description>The company also tops MLPerf Tiny v0.7 Benchmark with its IOT processor
Hangzhou, China, April 20, 2022 – Alibaba Cloud, the digital technologies and intelligence backbone of Alibaba Group, announced it has made further progress in porting basic Android functions onto the RISC-V instruction-set architecture (ISA). This proves the feasibility of using RISC-V based Android devices in scenarios ranging from multimedia to signal processing, device interconnection, and artificial intelligence.
Last year, the company reported it had successfully ported basic functions like chrome browsing in Android 10.</description></item><item><title>CHIPS Alliance First 2022 Biannual Technology Update</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/103/events/chips-biannual-technology-update-2022-1/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/103/events/chips-biannual-technology-update-2022-1/</guid><description>Watch the Replay
Check out the presentations below:
Introduction – Rob Mains, CHIPS Alliance Updates of Android on RISC-V – Han Mao, Alibaba (slides) Chisel and FIRRTL for Next-Generation SoC Designs– Jack Koenig, SiFive (slides) Introducting the F4PGA Workgroup– Michael Gielda, Karol Gugala, Antmicro (slides) Chiplet IP Protocol– Dave Kehlet, Intel (slides) NVMe Computational Storage Processor for Edge &amp;amp; Datacenter Applications, Anand Kulkarni, Wester Digital (slides) Towards Open Source Models of Cryogenic CMOS : Brian Hoskins and Pragya Shrestha, NIST (slides) Latest Statistics from Google’s No Cost Shuttle Program : Tim Ansell, Google : (slides) Watch the Replay</description></item><item><title>CHIPS Alliance Forms F4PGA Workgroup to Accelerate Adoption of Open Source FPGA Tooling</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/103/news/chips-alliance-forms-f4pga-workgroup-to-accelerate-adoption-of-open-source-fpga-tooling/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/103/news/chips-alliance-forms-f4pga-workgroup-to-accelerate-adoption-of-open-source-fpga-tooling/</guid><description>New workgroup draws support from industry leaders as the open FPGA toolchain matures
SAN FRANCISCO, Feb. 18, 2022 – CHIPS Alliance, the leading consortium advancing common and open source hardware for interfaces, processors and systems, today established the FOSS Flow For FPGA (F4PGA) Workgroup to drive open source tooling, IP and research efforts for FPGAs.
FPGA vendors such as Xilinx (now part of AMD) and QuickLogic, industrial FPGA users and contributors such as Google and Antmicro, as well as universities including Brigham Young University, University of Pennsylvania, Princeton University and University of Toronto, can now officially collaborate under the umbrella of the newly launched F4PGA Workgroup.</description></item><item><title>CHIPS Alliance Announces Xilinx as its Newest Member</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/103/news/xilinx-new-member/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/103/news/xilinx-new-member/</guid><description>Xilinx to continue to drive forward open source FPGA innovation
SAN FRANCISCO, Feb. 3, 2022 – CHIPS Alliance, the leading consortium advancing common and open hardware for interfaces, processors and systems, today announced that Xilinx, Inc. (NASDAQ: XLNX) has joined the CHIPS Alliance organization. Xilinx is a leader in adaptive computing, providing highly-flexible programmable silicon, enabled by a suite of advanced software and tools to drive rapid innovation across a wide span of industries and technologies – from consumer to cars to the cloud.</description></item><item><title>Towards UVM: Using Coroutines for Low-overhead Dynamic Scheduling in Verilator</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/103/news/towards-uvm-using-coroutines/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/103/news/towards-uvm-using-coroutines/</guid><description>This post was originally published at Antmicro.
Verilator is a popular open source SystemVerilog simulator and one of the key tools in the ASIC and FPGA ecosystem, which Antmicro is actively using and developing, e.g. by enabling co-simulation with Renode or Cocotb integration. It’s also one of the fastest available HDL simulators, including proprietary alternatives. It achieves that speed by generating highly optimized C++ code from a given hardware design. Verilator does a lot of work at compile-time to make the generated (‘verilated’) code extremely fast, such as ordering statements in an optimal way.</description></item><item><title>SATA Design Implementation on FPGAs with Open Source Tools</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/103/news/sata-design-implementation-on-fpgas-with-open-source-tools/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/103/news/sata-design-implementation-on-fpgas-with-open-source-tools/</guid><description>This post was originally published at Antmicro.
Real-world FPGAs designs often require high rate transmission protocols such as PCIe, USB and SATA which rely on high speed transceivers for external communication. These protocols are used to interface with various devices such as graphics cards and storage devices, and many of our clients reach out to us specifically because they need the flexibility, high-throughput and low-latency characteristics of FPGAs.
In particular, for customers that deal with high data volumes (which is very common in video applications), implementing SATA to communicate and transfer data with e.</description></item><item><title>Open Source FPGA Platform for Rowhammer Security Testing in the Data Center</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/103/news/open-source-fpga-platform-for-rowhammer-security-testing-in-the-data-center/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/103/news/open-source-fpga-platform-for-rowhammer-security-testing-in-the-data-center/</guid><description>This post was originally published at Antmicro.
Our work together with Google and the world’s research community on detecting and mitigating the Rowhammer problem in DRAM memories has been proving that the challenge is far from being solved and a lot of systems are still vulnerable. The DDR Rowhammer testing framework that we developed together with an open hardware LPDDR4 DRAM tester board has been used to detect new attack methods such as Half-Double and Blacksmith and all data seems to suggest this more such methods will be discovered with time.</description></item><item><title>2021 Annual Report</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/103/news/2021-annual-report/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/103/news/2021-annual-report/</guid><description>CHIPS Alliance was founded in March 2019 to design high-quality, open source hardware register transfer level (RTL) and develop open source hardware and software design tools. By creating an open and collaborative environment, companies and organizations can develop innovative, cost effective hardware designs optimized for the requirements of today’s silicon devices and FPGAs.
CHIPS Alliance was incorporated by four organizations which wanted to make open source silicon a reality. Esperanto, Google, SiFive and Western Digital were the founding members.</description></item><item><title>Software-driven ASIC Prototyping Using the Open Source SkyWater Shuttle</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/103/news/software-driven-asic-prototyping-using-the-open-source-skywater-shuttle/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/103/news/software-driven-asic-prototyping-using-the-open-source-skywater-shuttle/</guid><description>This post was originally published at Antmicro.
The growing cost and complexity of advanced nodes, supply chain issues and demand for silicon independence mean that the ASIC design process is in need of innovation. Antmicro believes the answer to those challenges is bound to come from the software-driven, open source approach which has shaped the Internet and gave rise to modern cloud computing. Applying the methodologies of software design to ASICs is however notoriously viewed as difficult, given the closed nature of many components needed to build chips – tools, IP and process design kits, or PDKs for short, as well as the slow turnaround of manufacturing.</description></item><item><title>Open Source Debayerization Blocks in FPGA</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/103/news/open-source-debayerization-blocks-in-fpga/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/103/news/open-source-debayerization-blocks-in-fpga/</guid><description>This post was originally published at Antmicro.
In modern digital camera systems, the captured image undergoes a complex process involving various image signal processing (ISP) techniques to reproduce the observed scene as accurately as possible while preserving bandwidth. On the most basic level, most CCD and CMOS image sensors use the Bayer pattern filter, where 50% of the pixels are green, 25% are red and 25% are blue (corresponding to the increased sensitivity of the human eye to the green color).</description></item><item><title>How Google is Applying Machine Learning to Macro Placement</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/103/news/how-google-is-applying-machine-learning-to-macro-placement/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/103/news/how-google-is-applying-machine-learning-to-macro-placement/</guid><description>CHIPS Alliance’s latest Deep Dive Cafe featured an outstanding talk by a Google physical design engineer, Young-Joon Lee, who has a PhD from Georgia Tech, and has been working on machine learning physical design projects for the past two years.
The chip placement problem is a notoriously challenging design problem, and has been explored in the electronic design automation research and development community for years. For those unfamiliar with the problem, it involves finding the optimal placement of physical cells implementing the logical function on a chip image to minimize performance, power, and area of the silicon, which in the end affects the cost of the product.</description></item><item><title>Improving the OpenLane ASIC Build Flow with Open Source SystemVerilog Support</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/103/news/improving-the-openlane-asic-build-flow-with-open-source-systemverilog-support/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/103/news/improving-the-openlane-asic-build-flow-with-open-source-systemverilog-support/</guid><description>This post was originally published at Antmicro.
Open source toolchains are key to building collaborative ecosystems, welcoming to new approaches, opportunistic/focused innovations and niche use cases. The ASIC design domain, especially in the view of the rising tensions around manufacturing and supply chains, are in dire need of a software-driven innovation based on an open source approach. The fledgling open source hardware ecosystem has been energized by the success of RISC-V and is now being vastly expanded to cover the entire ASIC design flow by CHIPS Alliance, and Antmicro has been playing a leadership role in both of these organizations as well as offering commercial engineering and support services to assist with early adoption of open source approaches in hardware.</description></item><item><title>Recap of the Fall 2021 CHIPS Alliance Workshop</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/103/news/recap-of-the-fall-2021-chips-alliance-workshop-rob-mains-chips-alliance/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/103/news/recap-of-the-fall-2021-chips-alliance-workshop-rob-mains-chips-alliance/</guid><description>We recently held our fall 2021 CHIPS Alliance workshop with nearly 160 attendees present for informative seminars covering a range of topics including porting Android to RISC-V, open source ASIC design and FPGA tooling, and OmniXtend. In case you missed the talks, a replay is available on the CHIPS Alliance YouTube channel.
During the seminar, we had eight exciting technical presentations, including:
Porting Android to RISC-V – Guoyin Chen and Han Mao, Alibaba Practical Adoption of Open Source SystemVerilog Tools – Michael Gielda, Antmicro Chisel and FIRRTL for Next-Generation SoC Designs – Jack Koenig, SiFive OpenFASOC: Automated Open Source Analog and Mixed-Signals IC Generation – Mehdi Saligane, University of Michigan (UMICH) FPGA Tooling Interoperability with the FPGA Interchange Format – Maciej Kurc, Antmicro OmniXtend: Scalability and LPC – Jaco Hofmann, Western Digital Corporation Open Source NVME IP with AI Acceleration – Anand Kulkarni, Western Digital Corporation and Karol Gugala, Antmicro Automating Analog Layout using ALIGN – Sachin Sapatnekar, University of Minnesota (UMN) Each of these talks provided informative, technical details of key aspects of the work underway by members of CHIPS Alliance who are working in an open, collaborative fashion.</description></item><item><title>CHIPS Alliance Fall Workshop 2021</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/103/events/fall-workshop-2021/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/103/events/fall-workshop-2021/</guid><description>Check out the presentations below, and watch the replay here
Porting Android to RISC-V Alibaba – Guoyin Chen and Han Mao, Alibaba (replay) (slides) Practical Adoption of Open Source System Verilog Tools – Michael Gielda, Antmicro (replay) (slides) Chisel and FIRRTL for Next-Generation SoC Designs– Jack Koenig, SiFive (replay) (slides) OpenFASOC: Automated Open Source Analog and Mixed-Signals IC Generation – Mehdi Saligane, University of Michigan (UMICH) (replay) (slides) FPGA Tooling Interoperability with the FPGA Interchange Format – Maciej Kurc, Antmicro (replay) (slides) OmniXtend: Scalability and LPC – Jaco Hofmann, Western Digital Corporation (replay) (slides) Open Source NVME IP with AI Acceleration – Anand Kulkarni, Western Digital Corporation and Karol Gugala, Antmicro (replay) (slides) Automating Analog Layout using ALIGN – Sachin Sapatnekar, University of Minnesota (UMN) (replay) (slides) Watch the Replay</description></item><item><title>Open Source DDR Controller Framework for Mitigating Rowhammer</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/103/news/open-source-ddr-controller-framework-for-mitigating-rowhammer/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/103/news/open-source-ddr-controller-framework-for-mitigating-rowhammer/</guid><description>This post was originally published at Antmicro.
Rowhammer is a hardware vulnerability that affects DRAM memory chips and can be exploited to modify memory contents, potentially providing root access to the system. It occurs because Dynamic RAM consists of multiple memory cells packed tightly together and specific access patterns can cause unwanted effects that propagate to nearby memory cells and cause bit-flips in cells which have not been accessed by the attacker.</description></item><item><title>Listen to CHIPS Alliance’s Rob Mains on EE Journal’s FishFry Podcast</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/103/news/listen-to-chips-alliances-rob-mains-on-ee-journals-fishfry-podcast/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/103/news/listen-to-chips-alliances-rob-mains-on-ee-journals-fishfry-podcast/</guid><description>CHIPS Alliance’s general manager Rob Mains joined Amelia Dalton at EE Journal’s FishFry podcast for a lively discussion about how we’re working to make chip design more accessible. Rob discussed CHIPS Alliance’s work with RISC-V International to develop a new unified memory standard, along with our work to accelerate the design of open source chipsets with the AIB 2.0 specification. The conversation also touched on our efforts to provide better support for SystemVerilog using open source tools and to create a dynamic stratified scheduler implementation in Verilator.</description></item><item><title>SkyWater Technology Joins CHIPS Alliance to Further Efforts to Make Chip Design and Production More Accessible</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/103/news/skywater-technology-joins-chips-alliance-to-further-efforts-to-make-chip-design-and-production-more-accessible/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/103/news/skywater-technology-joins-chips-alliance-to-further-efforts-to-make-chip-design-and-production-more-accessible/</guid><description>SkyWater furthers collaboration with CHIPS Alliance members on open source shuttle projects
SAN FRANCISCO, Sept. 16, 2021 – CHIPS Alliance, the leading consortium advancing common and open hardware for interfaces, processors and systems, today announced that SkyWater Technology (NASDAQ: SKYT) has become a member of the organization. SkyWater provides custom development, volume manufacturing and advanced packaging services for a wide range of silicon, including solutions based on the free and open RISC-V instruction set architecture (ISA).</description></item><item><title>SymbiFlow FPGA Interchange Format to Enable Interoperable FPGA Tooling</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/103/news/symbiflow-fpga-interchange-format-to-enable-interoperable-fpga-tooling/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/103/news/symbiflow-fpga-interchange-format-to-enable-interoperable-fpga-tooling/</guid><description>This post was originally published at Antmicro.
Field Programmable Gate Arrays (FPGAs) have been around for several decades, but historically development of toolchains targeting specific platforms was done in separate ecosystems and driven by the vendors themselves. Only in recent years, the development of vendor-neutral open source toolchains has revealed the need of having an abstraction layer to describe and define an FPGA architecture through a standard format.
FPGA toolchains are not trivial as they comprise several elements which themselves can be quite complex: roughly speaking, you can divide the process of “compiling” FPGA-targeted code in a Hardware Description Language (HDL) into three stages: synthesis, place and route, bitstream generation.</description></item><item><title>Automatic SystemVerilog Linting in GitHub Actions with Verible</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/103/news/automatic-systemverilog-linting-in-github-actions-with-verible/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/103/news/automatic-systemverilog-linting-in-github-actions-with-verible/</guid><description>This post was originally published at Antmicro.
With the recent advances in open source ASIC development tools such as Verible, it has become easier to automate tasks and boost developer productivity. The Verible linter is a static code analysis tool that has been helping us and our collaborators to spot and fix stylistic errors and bugs in SystemVerilog code.
CI/CD for smaller backlog and better test reliability As part of our work within the newly established CHIPS Alliance SystemVerilog subgroup, Antmicro has made further steps to facilitate SystemVerilog workflows with Verible, by providing an easy to use Verible Linter GitHub Action.</description></item><item><title>Open Source Custom GitHub Actions Runners with Google Cloud and Terraform</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/103/news/open-source-custom-github-actions-runners-with-google-cloud-and-terraform/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/103/news/open-source-custom-github-actions-runners-with-google-cloud-and-terraform/</guid><description>This post was originally published at Antmicro.
In order to fulfill our internal and our customers’ needs, we have developed and successfully deployed an open source custom GitHub Actions runner that allows us to mix the GitHub default and your custom hardware and software. The runner software itself operates within a Google Cloud Platform project, spawns Compute Engine instances and orchestrates the build, providing a number of interesting advantages that were needed in our ASIC and FPGA-related work.</description></item><item><title>Open Source SystemVerilog Tools in ASIC Design</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/103/news/open-source-systemverilog-tools-in-asic-design/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/103/news/open-source-systemverilog-tools-in-asic-design/</guid><description>This post was originally published at Antmicro.
Open source hardware is undeniably undergoing a renaissance whose origin can be traced to the establishment of RISC-V Foundation (later redubbed RISC-V International). The open ISA and ecosystem, in which Antmicro participated since the beginning as a Founding member, has sparked many open source CPU implementations but also new tooling, methodologies and trends which allow for more collaborative and software driven design.
Many of those broader open hardware activities have been finding a home in CHIPS Alliance, an open source organization we participate in as a Platinum member alongside Google, Intel, Western Digital, SiFive and others, whose goals explicitly encompass:</description></item><item><title>Advanced Co-simulation with Renode and Verilator: PolarFire SoC and FastVDMA</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/103/news/renode-and-verilator-polarfire-soc-and-fastvdma/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/103/news/renode-and-verilator-polarfire-soc-and-fastvdma/</guid><description>This post was originally published at Antmicro.
Co-simulating HDL has been possible in Renode since the 1.7.1 release, but the functionality – critical for hardware/software co-development as well as FPGA use cases – is constantly evolving based on the needs of our customers like Google and Microchip as well as our work in open source groups including CHIPS Alliance and RISC-V International. To quickly recap, by co-simulation we mean a scenario where a part of the system is simulated in Renode but some specific peripheral or subsystem is simulated directly from HDL, e.</description></item><item><title>Progress on Building Open Source Infrastructure for System Verilog</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/103/news/open-source-infrastructure-for-system-verilog/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/103/news/open-source-infrastructure-for-system-verilog/</guid><description>SystemVerilog is a rich hardware design description and verification language that is seeing increased usage in industry. In the second Deep Dive Cafe Talk by CHIPS Alliance on July 20, Henner Zeller, who is an software developer with Google, provided an excellent in depth technical talk on building out an open source tooling ecosystem around SystemVerilog to provide a common framework that can be used by both functional simulation applications as well as logic synthesis.</description></item><item><title>What You Need to Know About Verilator Open Source Tooling</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/103/news/what-you-need-to-know-about-verilator-open-source-tooling/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/103/news/what-you-need-to-know-about-verilator-open-source-tooling/</guid><description>Verilator is a high performance, open source functional simulator that has gained tremendous popularity in its usage and adoption in the verification of chip design. The ASIC development community has widely embraced Verilator as an effective, often even superior alternative to proprietary solutions, and it is now the standard approach in RISC-V CPU design as the community has worked to provide Verilator simulation capabilities out of the box. CHIPS Alliance and RISC-V leaders Antmicro and Western Digital have been collaborating to make Verilator even more useful for ASIC design purposes, working towards supporting industry-standard verification methods in a completely open source flow.</description></item><item><title>Efabless Launches chipIgnite with SkyWater to Bring Chip Creation to the Masses</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/103/news/efabless-launches-chipignite/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/103/news/efabless-launches-chipignite/</guid><description>Program includes a pre-designed carrier chip and automated open source design flow from Efabless SkyWater’s open source SKY130 process is the first node to be used to fabricate chips for the program Initiative removes access barriers by significantly reducing cost and the need for deep semiconductor experience to design chips Efabless, a community chip creation platform, today announced the launch of its new chipIgnite program to bring chip design and fabrication to the masses and a collaboration with SkyWater Technology for the first node supported in the program.</description></item><item><title>Antmicro’s ARVSOM RISC-V Module Announced</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/103/news/antmicros-arvsom-risc-v-module-announced/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/103/news/antmicros-arvsom-risc-v-module-announced/</guid><description>This post was originally published at Antmicro.
We are excited to announce the ARVSOM – Antmicro’s fully open source, RISC-V-based system-on-module featuring the StarFive 71×0 SoC. Using the RISC-V architecture, which Antmicro has been heavily involved in since the early days as a Founding Member of RISC-V International, the SoM is going to enable unprecedented openness, reusability and functionality across different verticals.
We are excited to announce the ARVSOM – Antmicro’s fully open source, RISC-V-based system-on-module featuring the StarFive 71×0 SoC.</description></item><item><title>Dynamic Scheduling in Verilator – Milestone Towards Open Source UVM</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/103/news/dynamic-scheduling-in-verilator/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/103/news/dynamic-scheduling-in-verilator/</guid><description>This post was originally published at Antmicro.
UVM is a verification methodology traditionally used in chip design which has historically been missing from the open source landscape of verification-focused tooling. While new, open source approaches to verification have emerged that include the excellent Python-based Cocotb (that we also use and support) maintained by FOSSi Foundation, not everyone can easily adopt it, especially in long-running projects and existing codebases that use a different verification approach.</description></item><item><title>New MPW-TWO Program Will Provide Fabrication For Fully Open Source Projects</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/103/news/new-mpw-two-program/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/103/news/new-mpw-two-program/</guid><description>CHIPS Alliance is excited to announce that the hardware development community can submit their open source design projects to Efabless.com for space on their forthcoming shuttle. This opportunity comes after the success of having 40 submissions for the MPW-ONE shuttle; 60% of those designs were submitted by first-time ASIC designers. MPW-TWO is the second Open MPW Shuttle providing fabrication for fully open-source projects using the SkyWater Open Source PDK announced by Google and SkyWater.</description></item><item><title>Modular, Open-source FPGA-based LPDDR4 Test Platform</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/103/news/modular-open-source-fpga-based-lpddr4-test-platform/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/103/news/modular-open-source-fpga-based-lpddr4-test-platform/</guid><description>This post was originally published at Antmicro.
The flexibility of FPGAs makes them an excellent choice not only for parallel processing applications but also for research and experimentation in a range of technological areas.
We often provide our customers with flexible R&amp;amp;D platforms that can be easily adapted to changing requirements and new use cases as a result of our practice of using open source hardware, software, FPGA IP and tooling.</description></item><item><title>CHIPS Alliance Spring Workshop 2021</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/103/events/spring-workshop-2021/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/103/events/spring-workshop-2021/</guid><description>Check out the presentations below, and watch the replay here
Chipyard - Bora Nikolic, UC Berkeley (slides) RISC-V DV Workgroup Updates Tao Liu / Matt Cockrell, Google (slides) Open Source Flows in ASIC &amp;amp; FPGA Development Michael Gielda, Antmicro Open-Source AIB Chiplet Ecosystem David Kehlet, Intel (slides) OmniXtend Milestone Updates Dejan Vucinic, Western Digital (slides) Chisel advances for next-gen SOC Designs Jack Koenig, SiFive (slides) Codasip SweRV Core Support Package in a Nutshell Zdenek Prikyl, Codasip (slides) An Introduction to the OpenROAD project Andrew Kahng / Tom Spyrou, OpenROAD (slides) Open Source FPGA Tooling Brian Faith, Quicklogic (slides) Fully Open Silicon Down to the Transistor Tim Ansell, Google (slides) Watch the Replay</description></item><item><title>CHIPS Alliance and RISC-V International Invite the RISC-V Community to Participate in Updating a New Unified Memory Architecture Standard</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/103/news/risc-v-international-omnixtend-working-group/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/103/news/risc-v-international-omnixtend-working-group/</guid><description>New joint working group will enhance the OmniXtend Cache Coherency architecture
SAN FRANCISCO, March 24, 2020 – RISC-V International, a non-profit corporation controlled by its members to drive the adoption and implementation of the free and open RISC-V instruction set architecture (ISA), and CHIPS Alliance, the leading consortium advancing common and open hardware for interfaces, processors and systems, today announced a joint collaboration to update the OmniXtend Cache Coherency specification and protocol, along with building out developer tools for OmniXtend.</description></item><item><title>GitHub Actions Self-hosted Runners, Build Event Server and Google Cloud</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/103/news/github-actions-self-hosted-runners-build-event-server-and-google-cloud/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/103/news/github-actions-self-hosted-runners-build-event-server-and-google-cloud/</guid><description>This post was originally published at Antmicro.
Continuous Integration and smart lifecycle management are key for high-tech product development, which is often a complex and multi-faceted process that requires automation to be efficient and failure-proof. At Antmicro, we’ve been creating various open source cloud and hybrid cloud solutions for our customers, helping them to encapsulate the complexity of their software stack. Lots of those projects cross the hardware/software boundary and involve a mix of open source and proprietary code, which means that fine-grained control of the CI setups are needed to make them work.</description></item><item><title>Goings-on in the FuseSoC Project and Other Open Source Silicon Related News</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/103/news/goings-on-in-the-fusesoc-project-and-other-open-source-silicon-related-news/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/103/news/goings-on-in-the-fusesoc-project-and-other-open-source-silicon-related-news/</guid><description>This post was originally published by Olof Kindgren
FOSSi Fever 2020 2020 was a year with a lot of bad news and so it feels slightly strange to cheerfully write about a very specific topic in the light of this. But there will always be good and bad things happening in the world. So let’s keep fighting the bad things and for now take look at what happened last year within the amazing world of open source silicon.</description></item><item><title>CHIPS Alliance Welcomes Antmicro and VeriSilicon to the Platinum Membership Level</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/103/news/chips-alliance-welcomes-antmicro-and-verisilicon-to-the-platinum-membership-level/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/103/news/chips-alliance-welcomes-antmicro-and-verisilicon-to-the-platinum-membership-level/</guid><description>CHIPS Alliance continues to grow with more than 25 companies collaborating on open source hardware and software technologies
SAN FRANCISCO, Feb. 11, 2021 – CHIPS Alliance, the leading consortium advancing common and open hardware for interfaces, processors and systems, today welcomed Antmicro and VeriSilicon to the company’s Platinum membership level. Antmicro, one of the initial members of the CHIPS Alliance, has upgraded to the Platinum membership level to reflect its deepening involvement in the organization.</description></item><item><title>High-Throughput Open Source PCIe on Xilinx VU19P-Based ASIC Prototyping Platform</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/103/news/high-throughput-open-source-pcie/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/103/news/high-throughput-open-source-pcie/</guid><description>This post was originally published at Antmicro.
In our daily work at Antmicro we use FPGAs primarily for their flexibility and parallel data processing capabilities that make them remarkably effective in advanced vision and audio processing systems involving high-speed interfaces such as PCI Express, USB, Ethernet, HDMI, SDI etc. that we develop and integrate as open source, portable building blocks. Many of our customers, however, use FPGAs also in a different context, namely for designing ASICs, which is a highly specialized market that typically involves large FPGAs, proprietary flows and IP.</description></item><item><title>CHIPS Alliance Brings on Rob Mains as New Executive Director</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/103/news/chips-alliance-brings-on-rob-mains-as-new-executive-director/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/103/news/chips-alliance-brings-on-rob-mains-as-new-executive-director/</guid><description>Industry veteran to lead open hardware consortium democratizing silicon innovation
SAN FRANCISCO, Feb. 8, 2021 – CHIPS Alliance, the leading consortium advancing common and open hardware for interfaces, processors and systems, today announced the appointment of Rob Mains as the organization’s new executive director.
Rob has over 35 years of experience in software engineering and development, with 25 years of experience as an EDA software architect focused on microprocessor design and advanced process node technologies.</description></item><item><title>Enabling Open Source Ibex Synthesis and Simulation in Verilator/Yosys via UHDM/Surelog</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/103/news/ibex-synthesis-and-simulation/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/103/news/ibex-synthesis-and-simulation/</guid><description>This post was originally published at Antmicro.
Throughout 2020 we were hard at work developing proper, portable SystemVerilog support for multiple open-source FPGA and ASIC design tools used by us and our customers, most notably Yosys and Verilator. We strongly believe that the support is a necessary step in building a collaborative ecosystem and scalable and reproducible CIs, especially publicly accessible ones that are common in multi-organization projects such as OpenTitan and CHIPS Alliance.</description></item><item><title>2020 Annual Report</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/103/news/2020-annual-report/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/103/news/2020-annual-report/</guid><description>CHIPS Alliance was founded in March 2019 to design high-quality, open source hardware register transfer level (RTL) and develop open source hardware and software design tools. By creating an open and collaborative environment, companies and organizations can develop innovative, cost effective hardware designs optimized for the requirements of today’s silicon devices and FPGAs.
CHIPS Alliance was incorporated by four organizations which wanted to make open source silicon a reality. Esperanto, Google, SiFive and Western Digital were the founding members.</description></item><item><title>Efabless Joins CHIPS Alliance to Accelerate the Growth of the Open Source Chip Ecosystem</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/103/news/efabless-joins-chips-alliance-to-accelerate-the-growth-of-the-open-source-chip-ecosystem/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/103/news/efabless-joins-chips-alliance-to-accelerate-the-growth-of-the-open-source-chip-ecosystem/</guid><description>Efabless to give a talk on the OpenROAD project at the CHIPS Alliance Workshop on Sept. 17
SAN FRANCISCO, Sept. 15, 2020 – CHIPS Alliance, the leading consortium advancing common and open hardware for interfaces, processors and systems, today welcomed Efabless, a crowdsourcing design platform for custom silicon, as its latest member. Efabless is already an active participant in several open source initiatives that the CHIPS Alliance is involved in, including the OpenROAD project and the Open Source Shuttle Program.</description></item><item><title>CHIPS Alliance to Collaborate with RISC-V to Standardize an Open Unified Memory Leveraging OmniXtend</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/103/news/omnixtend/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/103/news/omnixtend/</guid><description>CHIPS Alliance to highlight OmniXtend advances at RISC-V Summit
SAN FRANCISCO, Dec. 8, 2020 – CHIPS Alliance, the leading consortium advancing common and open hardware for interfaces, processors and systems, today announced that the organization will highlight OmniXtend advances in a presentation at the RISC-V Summit, taking place virtually from Dec. 8-10, 2020. The CHIPS Alliance plans to work with RISC-V International to standardize an open unified memory coherency bus leveraging OmniXtend to foster innovation for data-centric applications.</description></item><item><title>The CHIPS Alliance Workshop: 10 Talks From Industry Leaders, All For Free</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/103/news/the-chips-alliance-workshop-overview/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/103/news/the-chips-alliance-workshop-overview/</guid><description>Mark your calendars! The CHIPS Alliance Workshop is coming up on Thursday, Sept. 17 from 11 a.m. to 2 p.m. PT. This free, virtual event will feature talks from industry leaders including Antmicro, Efabless, Google, Intel, Mentor, Metrics, OpenROAD, QuickLogic, SiFive, UC Berkeley and Western Digital.
The CHIPS Alliance Workshop will fit 10 sessions into three hours for a jam-packed event covering a range of interesting topics in the open source community.</description></item><item><title>CHIPS Alliance Welcomes Mentor as its Newest Member</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/103/news/chips-alliance-welcomes-mentor-as-its-newest-member/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/103/news/chips-alliance-welcomes-mentor-as-its-newest-member/</guid><description>Mentor to present at the virtual CHIPS Alliance Workshop on Sept. 17
SAN FRANCISCO, Aug. 18, 2020 – CHIPS Alliance, the leading consortium advancing common and open hardware for interfaces, processors and systems, today announced that Mentor, a Siemens business, has joined as its newest member. The CHIPS Alliance has a roster of more than 20 members collaborating to accelerate the creation and deployment of open system-on-chips (SoCs), peripherals and software tools for a wide range of applications.</description></item><item><title>QuickLogic Joins CHIPS Alliance to Expand Open Source FPGA Efforts</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/103/news/quicklogic-joins-chips-alliance-to-expand-open-source-fpga-efforts/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/103/news/quicklogic-joins-chips-alliance-to-expand-open-source-fpga-efforts/</guid><description>QuickLogic to present at the virtual CHIPS Alliance Workshop on Sept. 17
SAN FRANCISCO, Aug. 11, 2020 – CHIPS Alliance, the leading consortium advancing common and open hardware for interfaces, processors and systems, today announced that QuickLogic Corporation (NASDAQ: QUIK), a developer of ultra-low power multi-core voice-enabled SoCs, embedded FPGA IP, and Endpoint AI solutions, has joined as its newest member.
“Over the past few years the electronics industry has seen a big shift towards open source hardware and software, and we’re proud to be one of the companies at the forefront of that movement,” said Brian Faith, president and CEO at QuickLogic.</description></item><item><title>CHIPS Alliance Announces AIB 2.0 Draft Specification to Accelerate Design of Open Source Chiplets</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/103/news/aib-2-0-draft-specification/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/103/news/aib-2-0-draft-specification/</guid><description>AIB reduces design barriers, costs, and leverages generators to ease development of chiplet-based designs
SAN FRANCISCO, July 16, 2020 – CHIPS Alliance, the leading consortium advancing common and open hardware for interfaces, processors and systems, today announced that it has released the Advanced Interface Bus (AIB) version 2.0 draft specification on GitHub. The AIB standard is an open-source, royalty-free PHY-level standard for connecting multiple semiconductor die within the same package. AIB is ideal for designing SoCs, FPGAs, SerDes chiplets, high-performance ADC/DAC chiplets, optical networking chiplets and more.</description></item><item><title>CHIPS SweRV Cores and the Open Tools Ecosystem</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/103/news/chips-swerv-cores-and-the-open-tools-ecosystem/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/103/news/chips-swerv-cores-and-the-open-tools-ecosystem/</guid><description>This post was originally published at Antmicro.
Antmicro’s open source work spans all parts of the computing stack, from software and AI, to PCBs, FPGAs and, most recently, custom silicon. We connect those areas with an overarching vision of open source tooling and methodology, and a software-driven approach that allows us to move fast and build future-centric solutions. Our partners and customers, many of whom work with us also in the context of organizations such as CHIPS Alliance and RISC-V, share our approach to developing open systems.</description></item><item><title>Open Source Process Design Kit from Google, SkyWater Technologies and Partners Released</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/103/news/open-source-process-design-kit-from-google-skywater-technologies-and-partners-released/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/103/news/open-source-process-design-kit-from-google-skywater-technologies-and-partners-released/</guid><description>This post was originally published at Antmicro.
The ASIC design and manufacturing flow has for a long time been dominated by proprietary tools and processes. The growing complexity of chip-building has been reinforcing the claim that “hardware is too hard to be open source”, as the cost and time needed to build an ASIC have kept small, more agile, software-oriented teams and individuals away from the hardware domain. Thus, ASICs have not been able to benefit from the enthusiasm and collaboration which have been fuelling software development for decades now.</description></item><item><title>Semiconductor Engineering: About The SweRV Core EH2</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/103/news/semiconductor-engineering-swerv-core-eh2/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/103/news/semiconductor-engineering-swerv-core-eh2/</guid><description>In mid-May, CHIPS Alliance announced the open sourcing of the SweRV Core EH2 and SweRV Core EL2 designed by Western Digital. These cores, as well as the earlier EH1, are now supported by Codasip’s SweRV Core Support Package which provides all of the components necessary to design, implement, test, and write software for a SweRV Core-based system-on-chip. But what is SweRV Core EH2?
The SweRV Core EH1 was the first to be released through CHIPS Alliance and was a core aimed at high-end embedded applications including Western Digital’s flash controllers and SSDs.</description></item><item><title>QuickLogic Announces Open Reconfigurable Computing Initiative</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/103/news/quicklogic-announces-open-reconfigurable-computing-initiative/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/103/news/quicklogic-announces-open-reconfigurable-computing-initiative/</guid><description>Originally issued by QuickLogic, the following press release announces the QORC initiative including the world’s first vendor-supported open FPGA toolchain using SymbiFlow, and describes the contribution of CHIPS Alliance members Antmicro and Google.
QuickLogic Open Reconfigurable Computing (QORC) initiative, developed by Antmicro in collaboration with QuickLogic and Google, broadens access to company’s FPGA technology and eFPGA IP for all embedded systems developers First Programmable Logic Company to Embrace Open Source FPGA Development Tools San Jose, CA – June 16, 2020 – QuickLogic Corporation (NASDAQ: QUIK), a developer of ultra-low power multi-core voice-enabled SoCs, embedded FPGA IP, and Endpoint AI solutions, today announced its ground breaking QORC (QuickLogic Open Reconfigurable Computing) initiative, making it the first programmable logic vendor to actively embrace a fully open source suite of development tools for its FPGA devices and eFPGA technology.</description></item><item><title>A Look Back at the CHIPS Alliance’s Incredible Growth</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/103/news/chips-alliances-incredible-growth/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/103/news/chips-alliances-incredible-growth/</guid><description>It’s been just over a year since the CHIPS Alliance was founded with the mission of making open source hardware development more accessible to companies, universities and individuals. We’re working to bring the dynamics of the hugely successful open source software development model into ASIC design, building on the groundwork set by the RISC-V community. Progress over the past year is detailed in our Annual Report.
CHIPS Alliance is focused on expanding on this open hardware vision by:</description></item><item><title>CHIPS Alliance’s Newly Enhanced SweRV Cores Available to All for Free</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/103/news/newly-enhanced-swerv-cores/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/103/news/newly-enhanced-swerv-cores/</guid><description>CHIPS Alliance to host online event to help community innovating with SweRV Core EH2 and EL2 Solutions
SAN FRANCISCO, May 14, 2020 – CHIPS Alliance, the leading consortium advancing common and open hardware for interfaces, processors and systems, today announced new enhancements to the SweRV Core™ EH2 and SweRV Core EL2, developed for the open-source community by Western Digital. Since the introduction of the cores earlier this year, the CHIPS Alliance has worked with its community to exhaustedly validate the cores through a transparent and rigorous process, as well as incorporate a variety of new updates.</description></item><item><title>SystemVerilog Linting and Formatting with FuseSoC – Verible Integration</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/103/news/systemverilog-linting-and-formatting-with-fusesoc-verible-integration/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/103/news/systemverilog-linting-and-formatting-with-fusesoc-verible-integration/</guid><description>This post was originally published at Antmicro.
Although new ASIC design methodologies and tools such as Chisel are on the rise, most ASIC projects still use SystemVerilog, the support of which in open source tools has traditionally lagged behind. This is unfortunate, as using proprietary alternatives with the CI systems of open source projects is neither scalable due to licensing costs and restrictions nor simple due to the need for license management and obfuscation.</description></item><item><title>Intel joins CHIPS Alliance to promote Advanced Interface Bus (AIB) as an open standard</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/103/news/intel-joins-chips-alliance-to-promote-advanced-interface-bus-aib-as-an-open-standard/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/103/news/intel-joins-chips-alliance-to-promote-advanced-interface-bus-aib-as-an-open-standard/</guid><description>Open development for SOCs gets major boost with new collaboration
SAN FRANCISCO, Jan. 22, 2020 /PRNewswire/ — CHIPS Alliance, the leading consortium advancing common and open hardware for interfaces, processors and systems, today announced industry leading chipmaker Intel as it’s newest member. Intel is contributing the Advanced Interface Bus (AIB) to CHIPS Alliance to foster broad adoption.
CHIPS Alliance is hosted by the Linux Foundation to foster a collaborative environment to accelerate the creation and deployment of open SoCs, peripherals and software tools for use in mobile, computing, consumer electronics and Internet of Things (IoT) applications.</description></item><item><title>Open Source USB test suite</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/103/news/open-source-usb-test-suite/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/103/news/open-source-usb-test-suite/</guid><description>Note: the open source test suite will be demonstrated at the CHIPS Alliance booth at the RISC-V Summit 2019 – join us Dec 10-12 in the San Jose Convention Center!
USB is often a daunting topic for developers, and implementing support for it from scratch is a time consuming task. When the expected result is more complicated than a USB-to-serial bridge, the solution would be to either use a hardware transceiver or, especially for older USB standards, use an open source core to implement one directly in the FPGA fabric.</description></item><item><title>CHIPS Alliance announces technical milestones, three new workgroups including Chisel and the 3rd Chisel Community Conference</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/103/news/chips-alliance-announces-technical-milestones-three-new-workgroups-including-chisel-and-the-3rd-chisel-community-conference/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/103/news/chips-alliance-announces-technical-milestones-three-new-workgroups-including-chisel-and-the-3rd-chisel-community-conference/</guid><description>SAN FRANCISCO, Nov. 7, 2019 — CHIPS Alliance, the leading consortium advancing common, open hardware for interfaces, processors and systems, today announced the creation of Interconnects, Rocket and Chisel workgroups. In addition, a November verification workshop in Munich and a Chisel conference in January will be held giving engineers an opportunity to learn about open source development efforts in CHIPS Alliance. Lastly, the CHIPS Alliance toolchain and cores workgroups have made contributions to open source development tools.</description></item><item><title>CHIPS Alliance growth continues with new members and design workshop this November</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/103/news/chips-alliance-growth-continues-with-new-members-and-design-workshop-this-november/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/103/news/chips-alliance-growth-continues-with-new-members-and-design-workshop-this-november/</guid><description>SAN FRANCISCO, Oct. 15, 2019 /PRNewswire/ — CHIPS Alliance, the leading consortium advancing common, open hardware for interfaces, processors and systems, today announced Codasip GmbH and Munich University of Applied Science have joined the CHIPS Alliance. In addition, on November 14–15, CHIPS Alliance will be joining the university for a workshop on open source design verification.
CHIPS Alliance is a project hosted by the Linux Foundation to foster a collaborative environment to accelerate the creation and deployment of open SoCs, peripherals and software tools for use in mobile, computing, consumer electronics, and Internet of Things (IoT) applications.</description></item><item><title>CHIPS Alliance featured in All About Circuits</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/103/news/chips-alliance-featured-in-all-about-circuits/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/103/news/chips-alliance-featured-in-all-about-circuits/</guid><description>All About Circuits recently featured an interview with Ted Marena, Yunsup Lee, Amir Salek, and Zvonimir Bandic, discussing the formation of the CHIPS Alliance, its relationship to the RISC-V Foundation, the CHIPS Alliance’s open development model, and initial open source contributions.
Read the article.</description></item><item><title>CHIPS Alliance Builds Momentum and Community with Newest Members Imperas Software and Metrics</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/103/news/chips-alliance-builds-momentum-and-community-with-newest-members-imperas-software-and-metrics/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/103/news/chips-alliance-builds-momentum-and-community-with-newest-members-imperas-software-and-metrics/</guid><description>Imperas and Metrics joining CHIPS Alliance to help drive the verification of RISC-V Open ISA implementations
SAN FRANCISCO – June 18, 2019 – CHIPS Alliance, the leading consortium advancing common, open hardware for interfaces, processors and systems, today announced Imperas and Metrics are joining the organization and the Verification Working Group. Imperas is an independent provider of processor simulation technology and tools for virtual platforms and analysis tools for multicore SoC software development.</description></item><item><title>Podcast – Embedded Computing Design – Five Minutes With… Zvonimir Bandic, Chairman, Chips Alliance</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/103/news/podcast-embedded-computing-design-five-minutes-with-zvonimir-bandic-chairman-chips-alliance/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/103/news/podcast-embedded-computing-design-five-minutes-with-zvonimir-bandic-chairman-chips-alliance/</guid><description>Zvonimir Bandic wears lots of hats. He is the Senior Director of Hardware Platforms for Western Digital; he’s a Member of the Board of Directors for the RISC-V Foundation, and he’s the Chairman of the Chips Alliance. It’s that latter capacity that we discussed in this week’s Five Minutes With…discussion. The organization focuses on things like open source hardware, software tools, RTL development, and related topics. They will be holding their inaugural workshop in just a few weeks, so it was timely to understand the purpose of the Alliance.</description></item><item><title>CHIPS Alliance to Reveal Project Details, Strategy and Roadmap at Inaugural Workshop Hosted at Google</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/103/news/chips-alliance-to-reveal-project-details-strategy-and-roadmap-at-inaugural-workshop-hosted-at-google/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/103/news/chips-alliance-to-reveal-project-details-strategy-and-roadmap-at-inaugural-workshop-hosted-at-google/</guid><description>SAN FRANCISCO – May 7, 2019 – CHIPS Alliance, the leading consortium advancing common, open hardware for interfaces, processors and systems, today announced it is holding its inaugural workshop on June 19, 2019 at Google at 111 W. Java Drive, Sunnyvale, Calif.
Project details, strategy and roadmaps will be presented by member companies, and attendees will have an opportunity to propose Register Transfer Level (RTL) projects and development flow ideas. The workshop will focus on open source hardware, software tools, RTL development, design verification tools and related topics.</description></item><item><title>Open Hardware Group – CHIPS Alliance – Building Momentum and Community with Newest Member Antmicro</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/103/news/open-hardware-group-chips-alliance-building-momentum-and-community-with-newest-member-antmicro/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/103/news/open-hardware-group-chips-alliance-building-momentum-and-community-with-newest-member-antmicro/</guid><description>Antmicro Joins CHIPS Alliance to develop open source cores, IP blocks and tools for CPUs, RISC-V-based SoCs and peripherals
SAN FRANCISCO – April 18, 2019 – CHIPS Alliance, the leading consortium advancing common, open hardware for interfaces, processors and systems, today announced Antmicro is joining the organization. Antmicro is a software-driven technology company focused on introducing open source into strategic areas of industry, especially edge AI. Announced just last month, the CHIPS Alliance welcomes Antmicro among its initial members Esperanto Technologies, Google, SiFive, and Western Digital.</description></item><item><title>Linux Foundation to Host CHIPS Alliance Project to Propel Industry Innovation Through Open Source CPU Chip and SoC Design</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/103/news/linux-foundation-to-host-chips-alliance-project-to-propel-industry-innovation-through-open-source-cpu-chip-and-soc-design/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/103/news/linux-foundation-to-host-chips-alliance-project-to-propel-industry-innovation-through-open-source-cpu-chip-and-soc-design/</guid><description>New Linux Foundation Project to Foster Flexible, Next-Generation Chip Design for Diverse Data-Centric Applications and Workloads
SAN FRANCISCO – March 11, 2019 – The Linux Foundation, the nonprofit organization enabling mass innovation through open source, today announced its intent to form the CHIPS Alliance project to host and curate high-quality open source code relevant to the design of silicon devices. CHIPS Alliance will foster a collaborative environment that will enable accelerated creation and deployment of more efficient and flexible chip designs for use in mobile, computing, consumer electronics, and Internet of Things (IoT) applications.</description></item><item><title>Analog Workgroup</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/103/workgroups/analog/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/103/workgroups/analog/</guid><description>The Analog workgroup was formed by the CHIPS Alliance TSC to explore collaborations in open source Analog/Mixed-Signal design and verification. It focuses on sharing best practices, ideas, tooling (analog automation), and other challenge areas in the design space. The workgroup is composed of both industry and university members.</description></item><item><title>Caliptra Workgroup</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/103/workgroups/caliptra/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/103/workgroups/caliptra/</guid><description>Microsoft Teams Meeting Link</description></item><item><title>Chisel Workgroup</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/103/workgroups/chisel/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/103/workgroups/chisel/</guid><description>The Chisel Workgroup is formed around the eponymous hardware design language (HDL) that facilitates advanced circuit generation and design reuse for both ASIC and FPGA digital logic designs. Chisel adds hardware construction primitives to the Scala programming language, providing designers with the power of a modern programming language to write complex, parameterizable circuit generators that produce synthesizable Verilog. Chisel is powered by FIRRTL (Flexible Intermediate Representation for RTL), a hardware compiler framework that performs optimizations of Chisel-generated circuits and supports custom user-defined circuit transformations on an Intermediate Representation.</description></item><item><title>Contact</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/103/about/contact/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/103/about/contact/</guid><description>hbspt.forms.create({ region: "na1", portalId: "8112310", formId: "94557cae-71ce-4536-a54f-8eff19aab9f9", sfdcCampaignId: "7012M000001FetwQAC" }); Mailing Address CHIPS Alliance
1 Letterman Drive, Building D, Suite D4700
San Francisco, CA 94129</description></item><item><title>F4PGA Workgroup</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/103/workgroups/f4pga/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/103/workgroups/f4pga/</guid><description>The F4PGA Workgroup was formed to drive open source tooling, IP cores and research for FPGA devices. It includes three major groups whose collaboration is critical to the success of the open source approach in this space: FPGA vendors, industrial users and university members. Its main focus is enabling rapid prototyping and software-driven development of FPGA-oriented systems in areas such as ML and video processing. The workgroup provides an open collaboration platform for its members, aiming at accelerating the speed of innovation in FPGAs and the general availability of the technology.</description></item><item><title>Frequently Asked Questions</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/103/about/faq/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/103/about/faq/</guid><description>1 What is CHIPS Alliance?
CHIPS Alliance, a member of the Linux Foundation, is championing open source based collaboration in the chip design community. This includes architectures, specifications, reference implementations, PDKs and EDA tooling. CHIPS Alliance hosts different workgroups to bring community members together to focus on topics of shared interest. 2 Why do we need open source hardware, chips, FPGAs, etc.?
Open source ingredients for hardware design are enabling and accelerating the global collaborative ecosystem.</description></item><item><title>Getting Started</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/103/getting-started/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/103/getting-started/</guid><description>By creating an open and collaborative environment, the CHIPS Alliance shares resources to lower the cost of development. Companies and individuals can work together to develop open source CPUs, various peripherals, complex IP blocks, tools and workflows.
The CHIPS Alliance is open to all organizations who are interested in collaborating on open source hardware or software tools to accelerate the creation of more efficient and innovative chip designs.
THe CHIPS Alliance is hosted by The Linux Foundation, a 501(c)6 non-profit.</description></item><item><title>Governance</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/103/about/governance/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/103/about/governance/</guid><description>In addition to the top-level structure of The CHIPS Alliance, each hosted open source project has its own process, structure, and community. While the Technical Steering Community (TSC) sets high-level technical policy, projects have a great deal of flexibility in day-to-day operations.
Rob Mains - General Manager The General Manager works with the Governing Board, our members, and our projects to ensure the CHIPS Alliance is a healthy, sustainable, and neutral home for open source technical collaborations.</description></item><item><title>Join</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/103/join/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/103/join/</guid><description>The CHIPS Alliance is an organization which works collaboratively to develop high quality, open source hardware designs relevant to silicon devices and FPGAs. By sharing openly resources and ideas, we hope to lower the cost of hardware development.
As a collection of open source projects, anyone is welcome to participate in the technical development process. The Technical Steering Committee is governed by a technical charter.
The CHIPS Alliance also welcomes corporate members.</description></item><item><title>Members</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/103/about/members/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/103/about/members/</guid><description>When an organization joins the CHIPS Alliance, they are making a tangible commitment to the success and sustainability of open source projects which help to achieve these goals. The CHIPS Alliance recognizes the critical supporting role of these organizations, and thanks them for their ongoing support of our project communities.
CHIPS Alliance Members Become a Member Platinum Members Gold Members Silver Members Auditor Members Associate Members</description></item><item><title>Projects</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/103/projects/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/103/projects/</guid><description>Graduated Projects Caliptra The Caliptra project focuses on development of HW and SW IP for the Caliptra Root of Trust Repositories: caliptra caliptra-rtl caliptra-sw caliptra-ureg caliptra-dpe Issue Tracker Website Contact: Andres Lagar-Cavilla (GitHub) F4PGA Free and open source toolchain for FPGA devices Repositories: f4pga Issue Tracker Website Contact: Tomasz Michalak (GitHub) FPGA Interchange format FPGA Interchange is a Vendor agnostic FPGA devices and designs description.</description></item><item><title>Rocket Workgroup</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/103/workgroups/rocket/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/103/workgroups/rocket/</guid><description>The Rocket Chip Workgroup covers the “Rocket” pipelined implementation of a RISC-V core as well as a TileLink uncore and cache coherent memory hierarchy. The main rocket-chip repository that the group maintains is a meta-repository containing tools needed to generate and test RTL implementations of SoC designs. This repository contains code that is used to generate RTL using Chisel and Diplomacy: the Rocket Chip generator itself is a Scala program that invokes the Diplomacy library and Chisel compiler in order to emit RTL describing a complete SoC.</description></item><item><title>Tools Workgroup</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/103/workgroups/tools/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/103/workgroups/tools/</guid><description>The Tools workgroup (WG) of CHIPS Alliance covers a wide array of open source tooling for ASIC and FPGA design, mostly focusing around digital design (as there is a separate Analog WG that focuses on AMS design flows). The topics covered include simulation, synthesis, place and route, IP aggregation, linting, formatting, and many more.</description></item><item><title>Who We Are</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/103/about/who-we-are/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/103/about/who-we-are/</guid><description>The CHIPS Alliance leverages common hardware development efforts by developing IP blocks that can be broadly used, such as RISC-V cores and neural network accelerator cores. We recognize that verification contributions benefit all who participate in the project, and prioritize joint resources for design verification.
The scope of the Project includes hardware and software design and development under an open source (Apache v2) license:
Verified IP blocks (compute cores, accelerators etc) Verified SoC designs (based on RISC-V and other open source cores) Open source software development tools for ASIC development High value IP including analog peripherals, mixed signal blocks and compute acceleration Exploration of new design flows such as Python-based design verification.</description></item></channel></rss>