<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Announcements on CHIPS Alliance</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/categories/announcements/</link><description>Recent content in Announcements on CHIPS Alliance</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 13 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://chipsalliance.org/categories/announcements/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>CHIPS Alliance Welcomes the Caliptra Open Source Root of Trust Project</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/news/chips-alliance-welcomes-the-caliptra-open-source-root-of-trust-project/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/news/chips-alliance-welcomes-the-caliptra-open-source-root-of-trust-project/</guid><description>SAN FRANCISCO, December 13, 2022 – CHIPS Alliance, a Linux Foundation project and leading consortium advancing common and open hardware for interfaces, processors and systems, announced that Caliptra, the open source root of trust project founded by technology leaders AMD, Google, Microsoft and NVIDIA, has joined CHIPS Alliance to enable an open, collaborative community-driven approach to hardware security.
Caliptra is a new specification for an open source silicon root of trust (RoT) designed to meet the enhanced security requirements of modern edge and confidential computing workloads.</description></item><item><title>CHIPS Alliance Fall 2022 Technology Update December 15</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/news/chips-alliance-fall-2022-technology-update-december-15/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/news/chips-alliance-fall-2022-technology-update-december-15/</guid><description>Please join us on December 15 at 8:30 am PT either in person at Google or virtually for a CHIPS technology update featuring many exciting speakers. Details and registration are here: https://events.linuxfoundation.org/chips-biannual-technology-update/</description></item><item><title>Catch us at DAC 59 in San Francisco starting July 11</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/news/catch-us-at-dac-59-in-san-francisco-starting-july-11/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/news/catch-us-at-dac-59-in-san-francisco-starting-july-11/</guid><description>Come learn about open source hardware and CHIPS Alliance at next week’s 59th Design Automation Conference in San Francisco. We will be at kiosk 2344 in the RISC-V pavilion. You can also here out talk at 12:30 Monday in the Open Source Central Theatre (booth 2338). We are also in a DAC Pavilion Panel: Is Democratization of Chip Design Already Happening? at 2:30 on Monday. Look forward to an exciting day in SF!</description></item><item><title>Alibaba Cloud Announced Progress in Porting Android Functions onto RISC-V</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/news/alibaba-cloud-announced-progress-in-porting-android-functions-onto-risc-v/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/news/alibaba-cloud-announced-progress-in-porting-android-functions-onto-risc-v/</guid><description>The company also tops MLPerf Tiny v0.7 Benchmark with its IOT processor
Hangzhou, China, April 20, 2022 – Alibaba Cloud, the digital technologies and intelligence backbone of Alibaba Group, announced it has made further progress in porting basic Android functions onto the RISC-V instruction-set architecture (ISA). This proves the feasibility of using RISC-V based Android devices in scenarios ranging from multimedia to signal processing, device interconnection, and artificial intelligence.
Last year, the company reported it had successfully ported basic functions like chrome browsing in Android 10.</description></item><item><title>CHIPS Alliance Forms F4PGA Workgroup to Accelerate Adoption of Open Source FPGA Tooling</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/news/chips-alliance-forms-f4pga-workgroup-to-accelerate-adoption-of-open-source-fpga-tooling/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/news/chips-alliance-forms-f4pga-workgroup-to-accelerate-adoption-of-open-source-fpga-tooling/</guid><description>New workgroup draws support from industry leaders as the open FPGA toolchain matures
SAN FRANCISCO, Feb. 18, 2022 – CHIPS Alliance, the leading consortium advancing common and open source hardware for interfaces, processors and systems, today established the FOSS Flow For FPGA (F4PGA) Workgroup to drive open source tooling, IP and research efforts for FPGAs.
FPGA vendors such as Xilinx (now part of AMD) and QuickLogic, industrial FPGA users and contributors such as Google and Antmicro, as well as universities including Brigham Young University, University of Pennsylvania, Princeton University and University of Toronto, can now officially collaborate under the umbrella of the newly launched F4PGA Workgroup.</description></item><item><title>CHIPS Alliance Announces Xilinx as its Newest Member</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/news/xilinx-new-member/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/news/xilinx-new-member/</guid><description>Xilinx to continue to drive forward open source FPGA innovation
SAN FRANCISCO, Feb. 3, 2022 – CHIPS Alliance, the leading consortium advancing common and open hardware for interfaces, processors and systems, today announced that Xilinx, Inc. (NASDAQ: XLNX) has joined the CHIPS Alliance organization. Xilinx is a leader in adaptive computing, providing highly-flexible programmable silicon, enabled by a suite of advanced software and tools to drive rapid innovation across a wide span of industries and technologies – from consumer to cars to the cloud.</description></item><item><title>SkyWater Technology Joins CHIPS Alliance to Further Efforts to Make Chip Design and Production More Accessible</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/news/skywater-technology-joins-chips-alliance-to-further-efforts-to-make-chip-design-and-production-more-accessible/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/news/skywater-technology-joins-chips-alliance-to-further-efforts-to-make-chip-design-and-production-more-accessible/</guid><description>SkyWater furthers collaboration with CHIPS Alliance members on open source shuttle projects
SAN FRANCISCO, Sept. 16, 2021 – CHIPS Alliance, the leading consortium advancing common and open hardware for interfaces, processors and systems, today announced that SkyWater Technology (NASDAQ: SKYT) has become a member of the organization. SkyWater provides custom development, volume manufacturing and advanced packaging services for a wide range of silicon, including solutions based on the free and open RISC-V instruction set architecture (ISA).</description></item><item><title>CHIPS Alliance and RISC-V International Invite the RISC-V Community to Participate in Updating a New Unified Memory Architecture Standard</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/news/risc-v-international-omnixtend-working-group/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/news/risc-v-international-omnixtend-working-group/</guid><description>New joint working group will enhance the OmniXtend Cache Coherency architecture
SAN FRANCISCO, March 24, 2020 – RISC-V International, a non-profit corporation controlled by its members to drive the adoption and implementation of the free and open RISC-V instruction set architecture (ISA), and CHIPS Alliance, the leading consortium advancing common and open hardware for interfaces, processors and systems, today announced a joint collaboration to update the OmniXtend Cache Coherency specification and protocol, along with building out developer tools for OmniXtend.</description></item><item><title>CHIPS Alliance Welcomes Antmicro and VeriSilicon to the Platinum Membership Level</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/news/chips-alliance-welcomes-antmicro-and-verisilicon-to-the-platinum-membership-level/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/news/chips-alliance-welcomes-antmicro-and-verisilicon-to-the-platinum-membership-level/</guid><description>CHIPS Alliance continues to grow with more than 25 companies collaborating on open source hardware and software technologies
SAN FRANCISCO, Feb. 11, 2021 – CHIPS Alliance, the leading consortium advancing common and open hardware for interfaces, processors and systems, today welcomed Antmicro and VeriSilicon to the company’s Platinum membership level. Antmicro, one of the initial members of the CHIPS Alliance, has upgraded to the Platinum membership level to reflect its deepening involvement in the organization.</description></item></channel></rss>