<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Yosys on CHIPS Alliance</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/208/tags/yosys/</link><description>Recent content in Yosys on CHIPS Alliance</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 30 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://chipsalliance.org/preview/208/tags/yosys/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Enhanced System Verilog Support for Yosys via Antmicro plug-in</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/208/news/enhanced-system-verilog-support-for-yosys-via-antmicro-plug-in/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/208/news/enhanced-system-verilog-support-for-yosys-via-antmicro-plug-in/</guid><description>&lt;p>CHIPS Alliance is pleased to see the announcement by Antmicro for its development and contribution to the open source hardware community to provide a easy to use plug-in for any version of Yosys to allow import of System Verilog based designs. This development is made possible by the underlying utilization of the Unified Hardware Data Model (UHDM), a key open source data representation upon which EDA applications can be built. Details can be seen here from Antmicro: &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/blog/2022/02/simplifying-open-source-sv-synthesis-with-the-yosys-uhdm-plugin/">https://antmicro.com/blog/2022/02/simplifying-open-source-sv-synthesis-with-the-yosys-uhdm-plugin/&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Improving the OpenLane ASIC Build Flow with Open Source SystemVerilog Support</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/208/news/improving-the-openlane-asic-build-flow-with-open-source-systemverilog-support/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/208/news/improving-the-openlane-asic-build-flow-with-open-source-systemverilog-support/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>This post was originally published at &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/blog/2021/10/openlane-asic-build-flow-with-systemverliog-support/">Antmicro&lt;/a>.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Open source toolchains are key to building collaborative ecosystems, welcoming to new approaches, opportunistic/focused innovations and niche use cases. The ASIC design domain, especially in the view of the rising tensions around manufacturing and supply chains, are in dire need of a software-driven innovation based on an open source approach. The fledgling open source hardware ecosystem has been energized by the success of RISC-V and is now being vastly expanded to cover the entire ASIC design flow by &lt;a href="https://chipsalliance.org/">CHIPS Alliance&lt;/a>, and Antmicro has been playing a leadership role in both of these organizations as well as offering commercial engineering and support services to assist with early adoption of open source approaches in hardware.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Progress on Building Open Source Infrastructure for System Verilog</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/208/news/open-source-infrastructure-for-system-verilog/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/208/news/open-source-infrastructure-for-system-verilog/</guid><description>&lt;p>SystemVerilog is a rich hardware design description and verification language that is seeing increased usage in industry. In the second Deep Dive Cafe Talk by CHIPS Alliance on July 20, Henner Zeller, who is an software developer with Google, provided an excellent in depth technical talk on building out an open source tooling ecosystem around SystemVerilog to provide a common framework that can be used by both functional simulation applications as well as logic synthesis. In case you missed the live presentation, you can watch it &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/xLxNHBzmGiI">here&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Efabless Launches chipIgnite with SkyWater to Bring Chip Creation to the Masses</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/208/news/efabless-launches-chipignite/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/208/news/efabless-launches-chipignite/</guid><description>&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Program includes a pre-designed carrier chip and automated open source design flow from Efabless&lt;/li>
&lt;li>SkyWater’s open source SKY130 process is the first node to be used to fabricate chips for the program&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Initiative removes access barriers by significantly reducing cost and the need for deep semiconductor experience to design chips&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.globenewswire.com/Tracker?data=_QfpiutgK9BkRkwqOZ_QgaW-wScChSfzrLoisG3jrx29CaZIKTRoBuySTDuHXJZP0EbK1_N1KyzIRCW2sFc5NA==">Efabless&lt;/a>, a community chip creation platform, today announced the launch of its new chipIgnite program to bring chip design and fabrication to the masses and a collaboration with &lt;a href="https://www.globenewswire.com/Tracker?data=P477GUgP-WxQLcA8zmSX8V24RDJ0fqqGp8teNuFfFkL7nLvoEPgkh9Uyo0a6ZDG-JNw_Hz99p5lNq7zs7gL_EsV6v-ZGI8zuNwlyMu1wbZ4=">SkyWater Technology&lt;/a> for the first node supported in the program. The chipIgnite program expands upon the SKY130-based open source chip manufacturing program sponsored by Google and supports private commercial designs that include non-open source IP. This initiative represents another step forward in the industry to broaden access to chip design by giving people the ability to more easily create and fabricate chips.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Goings-on in the FuseSoC Project and Other Open Source Silicon Related News</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/208/news/goings-on-in-the-fusesoc-project-and-other-open-source-silicon-related-news/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/208/news/goings-on-in-the-fusesoc-project-and-other-open-source-silicon-related-news/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>This post was originally published by &lt;a href="https://olofkindgren.blogspot.com/2021/02/fossi-fever-2020.html">Olof Kindgren&lt;/a>&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="fossi-fever-2020">FOSSi Fever 2020&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="fuckload.png" alt="">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2020 was a year with a lot of bad news and so it feels slightly strange to cheerfully write about a very specific topic in the light of this. But there will always be good and bad things happening in the world. So let’s keep fighting the bad things and for now take look at what happened last year within the amazing world of open source silicon. I will start by mentioning the most significant, but by no means the only, milestones for the FOSSi movement as a whole and then take a more personal look at the work where I have been directly involved.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Enabling Open Source Ibex Synthesis and Simulation in Verilator/Yosys via UHDM/Surelog</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/208/news/ibex-synthesis-and-simulation/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/208/news/ibex-synthesis-and-simulation/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>This post was originally published at &lt;a href="https://antmicro.com/blog/2020/12/ibex-support-in-verilator-yosys-via-uhdm-surelog/">Antmicro&lt;/a>.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Throughout 2020 we were hard at work developing proper, portable SystemVerilog support for multiple open-source FPGA and ASIC design tools used by us and our customers, most notably &lt;a href="https://github.com/YosysHQ/yosys">Yosys&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://github.com/verilator/verilator">Verilator&lt;/a>. We strongly believe that the support is a necessary step in building a collaborative ecosystem and scalable and reproducible CIs, especially publicly accessible ones that are common in multi-organization projects such as &lt;a href="https://opentitan.org/">OpenTitan&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://chipsalliance.org/">CHIPS Alliance&lt;/a>. Leading the efforts towards achieving this goal, we’ve been developing a fully open source SystemVerilog parsing flow for Yosys and Verilator using UHDM and Surelog, achieving an important milestone: being able to fully parse, synthesize and simulate OpenTitan’s Ibex core directly from the SystemVerilog source.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Efabless Joins CHIPS Alliance to Accelerate the Growth of the Open Source Chip Ecosystem</title><link>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/208/news/efabless-joins-chips-alliance-to-accelerate-the-growth-of-the-open-source-chip-ecosystem/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chipsalliance.org/preview/208/news/efabless-joins-chips-alliance-to-accelerate-the-growth-of-the-open-source-chip-ecosystem/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>Efabless to give a talk on the OpenROAD project at the CHIPS Alliance Workshop on Sept. 17&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>SAN FRANCISCO, Sept. 15, 2020&lt;/strong> – CHIPS Alliance, the leading consortium advancing common and open hardware for interfaces, processors and systems, today welcomed Efabless, a crowdsourcing design platform for custom silicon, as its latest member. Efabless is already an active participant in several open source initiatives that the CHIPS Alliance is involved in, including the OpenROAD project and the Open Source Shuttle Program.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>